<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doi_batch version="4.3.0" xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/doi_resources_schema/4.3.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/doi_resources_schema/4.3.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/deposit/doi_resources4.3.0.xsd">
<head>
<doi_batch_id>06aa5b0b-5692-4004-925b-d2a9a877c126</doi_batch_id>
<depositor>
<name>pens</name>
<email_address>bozhin.karaivanov@gmail.com</email_address>
</depositor>
</head>
<body>
<doi_citations>
<doi>part-3-287-4438</doi>
<citation_list>
	<citation key="ref1"><author>Rouse</author><cYear>2001</cYear><volume_title>Polychaetes</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Rouse G, Pleijel F (2001) Polychaetes, Oxford University Press, 354 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref2"><journal_title>Ciencia y Tecnología Marina</journal_title><author>Rozbaczylo</author><volume>29</volume><first_page>71</first_page><cYear>2006</cYear><article_title>Poliquetos bentónicos submareales de fondos blandos de la región de Aysén, Chile: Clado Terebellida (Annelida, Polychaeta).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Rozbaczylo N, Moreno R,  Díaz-Díaz O, Martínez S (2006) Poliquetos bentónicos submareales de fondos blandos de la región de Aysén, Chile: Clado Terebellida (Annelida, Polychaeta). Ciencia y Tecnología Marina 29: 71–90.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref3"><journal_title>Cahiers de l Office de la Recherche Scientifique et Technique d Outre-Mer</journal_title><author>Rullier</author><volume>3</volume><first_page>5</first_page><cYear>1965</cYear><article_title>Contribution a la fauna des annélides polychètes du Dahomey et du Togo.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Rullier F (1965) Contribution a la fauna des annélides polychètes du Dahomey et du Togo. Cahiers de l'Office de la Recherche Scientifique et Technique d'Outre-Mer 3: 5–66.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref4"><journal_title>Smithsonian Contributions to Knowledge</journal_title><author>Stimpson</author><volume>6</volume><first_page>5</first_page><cYear>1853</cYear><article_title>Synopsis of the marine Invertebrata of Grand Manan: or the region abou the mouth of the Bay of Fundy.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Stimpson W (1853) Synopsis of the marine Invertebrata of Grand Manan: or the region abou the mouth of the Bay of Fundy. Smithsonian Contributions to Knowledge 6: 5–67. [printed and distributed in March, 1853]</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref5"><issn>00973157</issn><journal_title>Proc Acad Nat Sci Philadelphia</journal_title><author>Stimpson</author><volume>1864</volume><first_page>153</first_page><cYear>1864</cYear><article_title>Descriptions of new species of marine Invertebrata from Puget Sound, collected by the naturalists of the North-west Boundary Commission, A.H. Campbell, Esq., Commissioner.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Stimpson W (1864) Descriptions of new species of marine Invertebrata from Puget Sound, collected by the naturalists of the North-west Boundary Commission, A.H. Campbell, Esq., Commissioner. Proceedings of the Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia 1864, 153–161.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref6"><author>Strathmann</author><cYear>1987</cYear><volume_title>Reproduction and development of marine invertebrates of the northern Pacific coast Data and methods for the study of eggs embryos and larvae</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Strathmann MF (1987) Reproduction and development of marine invertebrates of the northern Pacific coast. Data and methods for the study of eggs, embryos, and larvae. Seattle &amp; London, University of Washington Press.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref7"><issn>03715612</issn><journal_title>Sci Rep Tokyo Bunrika Daigaku Sect B</journal_title><author>Takahashi</author><volume>3</volume><first_page>192</first_page><cYear>1938</cYear><article_title>Polychaetous annelids of the Izu Peninsula. Polychaeta collected by the Misazo during the zoological survey around the Izu Peninsula.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Takahashi K (1938) Polychaetous annelids of the Izu Peninsula. Polychaeta collected by the Misazo during the zoological survey around the Izu Peninsula. Scientific Reports, Tokyo Bumrika Daigaku, section B 3: 192–330.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref8"><issn>09442006</issn><journal_title>Zoology</journal_title><author>Tebble</author><volume>3</volume><first_page>61</first_page><cYear>1955</cYear><article_title>The polychaete fauna of the Gold Coast. Bulletin of the British Museum (Natural History)</article_title><unstructured_citation>Tebble N (1955) The polychaete fauna of the Gold Coast. Bulletin of the British Museum (Natural History), Zoology 3: 61–148.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref9"><journal_title>Serie Plankton</journal_title><author>Thorson</author><volume>4</volume><issue>1</issue><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1946</cYear><article_title>Reproduction and larval development of Danish marine bottom invertebrates; with special reference to the planktonic larvae in the Sound (Øresund). Meddelelser fra Kommissionen for Danmarks Fiskeri- og Havundersøgelser</article_title><unstructured_citation>Thorson G (1946) Reproduction and larval development of Danish marine bottom invertebrates; with special reference to the planktonic larvae in the Sound (Øresund). Meddelelser fra Kommissionen for Danmarks Fiskeri- og Havundersøgelser, Serie Plankton 4 (1): 1–523.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref9"><doi>10.1111/j.1469-185X.1950.tb00585.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref9"><doi>10.1080/03949370.2010.534321</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref10"><issn>00079723</issn><journal_title>Cah Biol Mar</journal_title><author>Townsend</author><volume>47</volume><first_page>281</first_page><cYear>2006</cYear><article_title>Occurrence of Sternaspis scutata (Polychaeta: Sternaspidae) in the English Channel.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Townsend M, Worsfold TM, Smith PRJ, Martina LJ, McNeill CL, Kendall MA (2006) Occurrence of Sternaspis scutata (Polychaeta: Sternaspidae) in the English Channel. Cahiers de Biologie Marine 47: 281–285.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref11"><issn>00686506</issn><journal_title>Univ Calif Publ Zool</journal_title><author>Treadwell</author><volume>13</volume><issue>8</issue><first_page>175</first_page><cYear>1914</cYear><article_title>Polychaetous annelids of the Pacific coast in the collection of the Zoological Museum of the University of California.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Treadwell A (1914) Polychaetous annelids of the Pacific coast in the collection of the Zoological Museum of the University of California. University of California Publications in Zoology 13(8): 175–234.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref11"><doi>10.1199/tab.0072</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref12"><journal_title>Report of the United States Commisioner for Fisheries Washington</journal_title><author>Verrill</author><volume>1871–1872</volume><first_page>295</first_page><cYear>1873</cYear><article_title>Report upon the invertebrate animals of Vineyard Sound and the adjacent waters, with and account of the physical characters of the region.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Verrill AE (1873) Report upon the invertebrate animals of Vineyard Sound and the adjacent waters, with and account of the physical characters of the region. Report of the United States Commisioner for Fisheries, Washington1871–1872, 295–778. [reprinted in 1874 by the Government Printing Office, Washington, 478 pp.]</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref13"><journal_title>Annalen des Kaiserliche Naturhistorische Hofmusem Wien</journal_title><author>von Marenzeller</author><volume>5</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1890</cYear><article_title>Annulaten des Beringmeeres.</article_title><unstructured_citation>von Marenzeller E (1890) Annulaten des Beringmeeres. Annalen des Kaiserliche Naturhistorische Hofmusem, Wien 5: 1–18.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref14"><journal_title>Paleontological Society Papers</journal_title><author>Walker</author><volume>8</volume><first_page>119</first_page><cYear>2002</cYear><article_title>Post-Paleozoic patterns in marine predation: Was there a Mesozoic and Cenozoic marine predatory revolution?</article_title><unstructured_citation>Walker SE, Brett CE (2002) Post-Paleozoic patterns in marine predation: Was there a Mesozoic and Cenozoic marine predatory revolution? Paleontological Society Papers 8: 119–193.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref15"><journal_title>Acta Zoologica Sinica</journal_title><author>Wang</author><volume>52</volume><first_page>63</first_page><cYear>2006</cYear><unstructured_citation>Wang J-B, Li X-Z, Wang H-F (2006) [Ecological characteristics of dominant polychaete species from the Jiaozhou Bay]. Acta Zoologica Sinica 52: 63–69.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref16"><journal_title>Annual Report of the Commissioner of Fish and Fisheries</journal_title><author>Webster</author><volume>1885</volume><first_page>707</first_page><cYear>1887</cYear><article_title>The Annelida Chaetopoda from Eastport, Maine.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Webster HE, Benedict JE (1887) The Annelida Chaetopoda from Eastport, Maine. Annual Report of the Commissioner of Fish and Fisheries 1885, 707–758.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref17"><journal_title>Proceedings of the Oklahoma Academy of Sciences</journal_title><author>Weese</author><volume>10</volume><first_page>26</first_page><cYear>1930</cYear><article_title>Seral communities of a muddy sea bottom.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Weese AO, Macnab JA (1930) Seral communities of a muddy sea bottom. Proceedings of the Oklahoma Academy of Sciences 10: 26–28.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref18"><journal_title>Danish Ingolf-Expedition</journal_title><author>Wesenberg-Lund</author><volume>4</volume><issue>14</issue><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1950</cYear><article_title>Polychaeta.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Wesenberg-Lund E (1950a) Polychaeta. Danish Ingolf-Expedition 4(14): 1–92.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref19"><journal_title>The Zoology of Iceland</journal_title><author>Wesenberg-Lund</author><volume>2</volume><issue>19</issue><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1951</cYear><article_title>Polychaeta.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Wesenberg-Lund E (1951) Polychaeta. The Zoology of Iceland 2(19): 1–182.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref19"><doi>10.1086/394264</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><issn>02172445</issn><journal_title>Raffles Bull Zool</journal_title><author>Zhu</author><volume>54</volume><first_page>119</first_page><cYear>2006</cYear><article_title>Rare spiders of the genus Cyclocosmia (Arachnida: Araneae: Ctenizidae) from tropical and subtropical China.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Zhu MS, Zhang JX, Zhang F (2006) Rare spiders of the genus Cyclocosmia (Arachnida: Araneae: Ctenizidae) from tropical and subtropical China. Raffles Bulletin of Zoology 54: 119–124.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><doi>10.1186/1471-2148/9/189</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><unstructured_citation>Rietsch M (1882) Étude sur le Sternaspis scutata. Thèse, juin 1882, École Supérieure de Pharmacie de Paris, 84 pp. [publication year based upon the documents; also published in Annals des Sciences Naturelles Paris, Zoologie, série 5 13: 1–84]</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><unstructured_citation>Roule L (1906) Annélides et Géphyriens; pp 1–101 in: Expéditions Scientifiques du &quot;Travailleur&quot; et du &quot;Talisman&quot; pendant les années 1880, 1881, 1882, 1883. A. Milne-Edwards &amp; E. Perrier (eds.), Masson et Cie., Paris.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><unstructured_citation>Selenka E (1885) Report on the Gephyrea collected by the H.M.S. Challenger during the years 1873–76. Challenger Reports, Zoology 13(36): 1–25, Pls. 1–4.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><unstructured_citation>Sendall K (2006) Review and revision of the genus Sternaspis (Polychaeta: Sternaspidae) using cladistics on morphological characters. Master of Science Thesis, University of Victoria, Canada, 146 pp. http://dspace.library.uvic.ca:8080/handle/1828/2189</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><unstructured_citation>Sluiter CP (1882) Ueber einen indischen Sternaspis und seine Verwandschaft zu den Echiuren. Tijdschrift voor Natuurkundig Nederlandsch-lndie, Batavia 41: 235–287, 3 Pls.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><unstructured_citation>Sluiter CP (1890) Die evertebraten aus der Sammlung des koniglichen naturwissenschaftlichen vereins in nieder Hindisch lndien in Batavia. Zugleich eine Skizze der Fauna des Java-Meeres, mit Beschreibung der neuen Arten. Natuurkundig Tijdschrift voor Nederlandsch-lndie 50: 102–123, Pls. 1–2.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><unstructured_citation>Southern R (1928) Polychaeta of the Chilka Lake and also of fresh and brackish waters in other parts oflndia. Memoirs of the Indian Museum 5: 565–659, Pls. 19–31.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><unstructured_citation>Thorson G (1957) Bottom communities (sublittoral or shallow shelf). In: Hedgpeth JW, Ladd HS (Eds) Treatise on Marine Ecology and Palaeoecology. Memoirs Geological Society of America 67: 461–534.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><unstructured_citation>Uschakov PV (1955) Polychaeta of the Far Eastern Seas of the USSR. Israel Program for Scientific Translations, Jerusalem (transl. 1965), 26 + 419.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><unstructured_citation>Vejdovský F (1882) Untersuchungen uber der anatomie, physiologie und entwicklung von Sternaspis. Denkschriften der Mathematisch-Naturwissenschaftlichen Classe der kaiserlichen Akademie der Wissenschaften 43: 33–90, Pls. l–10.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><unstructured_citation>von Marenzeller E (1879) Sudjapanische Anneliden. (Amphinomea, Aphroditea, Lycoridea, Phyllodocea, Hesionea, Syllidea, Eunicea, Glycerea, Sternaspidea, Chaetopterea, Cirratulea, Amphictenea.). Denkschriften der Mathematisch Naturwissenschaftlichen Classe der kaiserlichen Akademie der Wissenschaften 41: 109–154, Pls. 1-6.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><unstructured_citation>Webster HE, Benedict JE (1884) The Annelida Chaetopoda from Provincetown and Wellfleet, Mass. Annual Report of the United States Commisioner of Fish and Fisheries 1881(9): 699–744.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><unstructured_citation>Wesenberg-Lund E (1949) Polychaetes of the Iranian Gulf. Danish Scientific Investigation in Iran, Part IV, 247–400.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><unstructured_citation>Wesenberg-Lund E (1950b) The Polychaeta of West Greenland with special reference to the Fauna of Nordre Strømfjord, Kvane-, and Bredefjord. Meddelelser om Grønland udgivne af Kommissionen for Videnskabelige undersøgelser I Grønland 151(2): 1–171.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><unstructured_citation>Wesenberg-Lund E (1953) The Zoology of East Greenland: Polychaeta. Meddelelser om Grønland udgivne af Kommissionen for Videnskabelige undersøgelser I Grønland 122(3): 1–169.</unstructured_citation></citation>
</citation_list>
</doi_citations>
</body>
</doi_batch>
