<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doi_batch version="4.3.0" xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/doi_resources_schema/4.3.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/doi_resources_schema/4.3.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/deposit/doi_resources4.3.0.xsd">
<head>
<doi_batch_id>ac3fb06c-ecff-496d-9673-bc87c57a6cbc</doi_batch_id>
<depositor>
<name>pens</name>
<email_address>bozhin.karaivanov@gmail.com</email_address>
</depositor>
</head>
<body>
<doi_citations>
<doi>part-2-256-3871</doi>
<citation_list>
	<citation key="ref0"><doi>10.1006/gcen.1999.7388</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref1"><journal_title>Zoologische Wetenschappen</journal_title><author>van der Meer</author><volume>257</volume><first_page>51</first_page><cYear>1989</cYear><article_title>Ecological significance of retinal receptor patterns in 4 sympatric haplochromine cichlids. Annalen van het Koninklijk Museum voor Midden-Afrika</article_title><unstructured_citation>van der Meer HJ (1989) Ecological significance of retinal receptor patterns in 4 sympatric haplochromine cichlids. Annalen van het Koninklijk Museum voor Midden-Afrika, Zoologische Wetenschappen 257: 51–56.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref2"><journal_title>Zoologische Wetenschappen</journal_title><author>van der Meer</author><volume>263</volume><first_page>91</first_page><cYear>1991</cYear><article_title>Determination of photopic thresholds in two sympatric cichlids using optomotor response. Annalen van het Koninklijk Museum voor Midden-Afrika</article_title><unstructured_citation>van der Meer HJ (1991a) Determination of photopic thresholds in two sympatric cichlids using optomotor response. Annalen van het Koninklijk Museum voor Midden-Afrika, Zoologische Wetenschappen 263: 91–96.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref2"><doi>10.1159/000113383</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref2"><doi>10.1159/000113552</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref2"><doi>10.1007/BF00005910</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref2"><doi>10.1111/j.1095-8312.2012.01859.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref3"><journal_title>Zoologische Verhandelingen Leiden</journal_title><author>van Oijen</author><volume>302</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1996</cYear><article_title>Taxonomical and ecological description of a species complex of zooplanktivorous and insectivorous cichlids from Lake Victoria.</article_title><unstructured_citation>van Oijen MJP, Witte F (1996) Taxonomical and ecological description of a species complex of zooplanktivorous and insectivorous cichlids from Lake Victoria. Zoologische Verhandelingen Leiden 302: 1–56.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref3"><doi>10.1007/s10682-012-9596-9</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref4"><issn>09442006</issn><journal_title>Zoology</journal_title><author>van Staaden</author><volume>98</volume><first_page>165</first_page><cYear>1995</cYear><article_title>Brain evolution in cichlids of the African Great Lakes: brain and body size, general patterns, and evolutionary trends.</article_title><unstructured_citation>van Staaden MJ, Huber R, Kaufman LS, Liem KF (1995) Brain evolution in cichlids of the African Great Lakes: brain and body size, general patterns, and evolutionary trends. Zoology 98: 165–178.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref5"><journal_title>Zoologische Wetenschappen</journal_title><author>Verheijen</author><volume>257</volume><first_page>93</first_page><cYear>1989</cYear><article_title>The eye-lens proteins of haplochromine cichlids from Lake Victoria studied by isoelectric focusing. Annalen van het Koninklijk Museum voor Midden-Afrika</article_title><unstructured_citation>Verheijen E, van der Linden A-M, Decleir W (1989) The eye-lens proteins of haplochromine cichlids from Lake Victoria studied by isoelectric focusing. Annalen van het Koninklijk Museum voor Midden-Afrika, Zoologische Wetenschappen 257: 93–96.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref5"><doi>10.1111/j.1365-2427.2001.00644.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref5"><doi>10.1016/S0065-2504(00)31030-3</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref5"><doi>10.1163/002829684X00308</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref6"><author>Witte</author><first_page>155</first_page><cYear>1984</cYear><volume_title>Evolution of Fish Species Flocks</volume_title><article_title>Ecological differentiation in Lake Victoria haplochromines: comparison of cichlid species flocks in African Lakes.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Witte F (1984b) Ecological differentiation in Lake Victoria haplochromines: comparison of cichlid species flocks in African Lakes. In: Echelle AA, Kornfield I (Eds), Evolution of Fish Species Flocks. Orono Press, University of Maine, Maine, 155–167.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref7"><issn>00382353</issn><journal_title>S Afr J Sci</journal_title><author>Witte</author><volume>93</volume><first_page>585</first_page><cYear>1997</cYear><article_title>Intraspecific variation of haplochromine cichlids from Lake Victoria and its taxonomic implications.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Witte F, Barel CDN, van Oijen MJP (1997) Intraspecific variation of haplochromine cichlids from Lake Victoria and its taxonomic implications. South African Journal of Science 93: 585–594.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref8"><issn>00225460</issn><journal_title>J Zool</journal_title><author>Witte</author><volume>42</volume><first_page>214</first_page><cYear>1992</cYear><article_title>Species extinction and concomitant ecological changes in Lake Victoria. Netherlands</article_title><unstructured_citation>Witte F, Goldschmidt T, Goudswaard PC, Ligtvoet W, van Oijen MJP, Wanink JH (1992a) Species extinction and concomitant ecological changes in Lake Victoria. Netherlands Journal of Zoology 42: 214–232.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref8"><doi>10.1007/BF00004782</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref9"><journal_title>Cichlidae</journal_title><author>Witte</author><volume>29</volume><first_page>104</first_page><cYear>2003</cYear><article_title>Door cichlidenogen bezien: het belang van het gezichtsvermogen bij haplochromine cichliden voor het ontstaan en in stand houden van diversiteit.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Witte F, van der Meer H, Barel K (2003) Door cichlidenogen bezien: het belang van het gezichtsvermogen bij haplochromine cichliden voor het ontstaan en in stand houden van diversiteit. Cichlidae 29: 104–114.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref9"><doi>10.1023/A:1016677515930</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref9"><doi>10.1007/s00027-012-0265-4</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref9"><doi>10.1007/s10750-011-0893-z</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref10"><journal_title>Cichlidae</journal_title><author>Witte</author><volume>26</volume><first_page>77</first_page><cYear>2000</cYear><article_title>De zoöplanktivore cichliden van het Victoriameer: ontdekking, verdwijning en terugkeer.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Witte F, Wanink JH (2000) De zoöplanktivore cichliden van het Victoriameer: ontdekking, verdwijning en terugkeer. Cichlidae 26: 77–84.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref10"><doi>10.1577/T05-179.1</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref10"><doi>10.1080/14634980701709410</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref11"><author>Witte</author><first_page>301</first_page><cYear>2005</cYear><volume_title>Restoration and Management of Tropical Eutrophic Lakes</volume_title><article_title>Eutrophication and its influences on the fish fauna of Lake Victoria.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Witte F, Wanink JH, Rutjes HA, van der Meer HJ, van den Thillart GEEJM (2005) Eutrophication and its influences on the fish fauna of Lake Victoria. In: Reddy VM (Ed) Restoration and Management of Tropical Eutrophic Lakes. Science publishers, Inc., Enfield (NH), 301–338.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref11"><doi>10.1111/J.1095-8312.2008.00971.X</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref11"><doi>10.1163/002829680X00249</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref11"><doi>10.1163/002829682X00210</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref11"><unstructured_citation>van der Meer HJ (1991b) Ecomorphology of photoreception in haplochromine cichlid fishes. PhD Thesis, Leiden, the Netherlands: Leiden University.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref11"><unstructured_citation>van Oijen MJP (1996) The generic classification of the haplochromine cichlids of Lake Victoria, East Africa.  Zoologische Verhandelingen Leiden 302: 57–110. http://www.repository.naturalis.nl/document/148949</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref11"><unstructured_citation>Wanink JH (1998) The pelagic cyprinid Rastrineobola argentea as a crucial link in the disrupted ecosystem of Lake Victoria. PhD Thesis, Leiden, the Netherlands: Leiden University.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref11"><unstructured_citation>Wanink JH, Goldschmidt T, Witte F (1989) Recent changes in the zooplanktivorous-/insectivorous fish community from the Mwanza Gulf of Lake Victoria. In: Anonymous (Eds) WOTRO Report for the year 1988. Netherlands Foundation for the Advancement of Tropical Research, The Hague, the Netherlands: 22–28.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref11"><unstructured_citation>Wanink JH, Witte F (1998) Niche shift in a zooplanktivorous cyprinid from Lake Victoria after reduction of its cichlid guild members by Nile perch. In: Wanink JH (1998) The pelagic cyprinid Rastrineobola argentea as a crucial link in the disrupted ecosystem of Lake Victoria. PhD Thesis, Leiden, the Netherlands: Leiden University, 157–167.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref11"><unstructured_citation>Witte F (1987) From form to fishery. An ecological and taxonomical contribution to morphology and fishery of Lake Victoria cichlids. PhD Thesis, Leiden, the Netherlands: Leiden University.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref11"><unstructured_citation>Witte F, Witte-Maas ELM (1987) Implications for taxonomy and functional morphology of intraspecific variation in haplochromine cichlids of Lake Victoria. In: Witte F, From form to fishery, PhD Thesis, Leiden, the Netherlands: Leiden University. 1–83.</unstructured_citation></citation>
</citation_list>
</doi_citations>
</body>
</doi_batch>
