<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doi_batch version="4.3.0" xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/doi_resources_schema/4.3.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/doi_resources_schema/4.3.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/deposit/doi_resources4.3.0.xsd">
<head>
<doi_batch_id>ba8d1416-8739-4952-8aca-82c3c464f24b</doi_batch_id>
<depositor>
<name>pens</name>
<email_address>bozhin.karaivanov@gmail.com</email_address>
</depositor>
</head>
<body>
<doi_citations>
<doi>part-3-253-3414</doi>
<citation_list>
	<citation key="ref1"><author>Jolivet</author><cYear>1995</cYear><volume_title>Host-plants of Chrysomelidae of the World An essay about the relationships between the leaf-beetles and their food-plants</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Jolivet P, Hawkeswood TJ (1995) Host-plants of Chrysomelidae of the World. An essay about the relationships between the leaf-beetles and their food-plants. Backhuys Publishers, Leiden, 281 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref2"><journal_title>Entomologische Hefte</journal_title><author>Koch</author><volume>2</volume><issue>1</issue><first_page>3</first_page><cYear>1803</cYear><article_title>Monographie der Floehkaefer.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Koch JDW (1803) Monographie der Floehkaefer. Entomologische Hefte 2(1): 3−90.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref3"><journal_title>Stettiner Entomologische Zeitung</journal_title><author>Kolbe</author><volume>55</volume><first_page>79</first_page><cYear>1894</cYear><article_title>Die Pfeilgiftkafer der Kalahari-Wuste, Diamphidia simplex Péring. (locusta Fairm.).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Kolbe HJ (1894) Die Pfeilgiftkafer der Kalahari-Wuste, Diamphidia simplex Péring. (locusta Fairm.). Stettiner Entomologische Zeitung 55: 79−86.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref4"><journal_title>Memoirs on Entomology</journal_title><author>Konstantinov</author><volume>11</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1998</cYear><article_title>Revision of the Palearctic species of Aphthona Chevrolat and cladistic classification of the Aphthonini (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae: Alticinae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Konstantinov AS (1998) Revision of the Palearctic species of Aphthona Chevrolat and cladistic classification of the Aphthonini (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae: Alticinae). Memoirs on Entomology 11: 1−429.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref5"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Konstantinov</author><volume>124</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2002</cYear><article_title>A new genus of flea beetles from Greater Antilles (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Konstantinov AS (2002) A new genus of flea beetles from Greater Antilles (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae). Zootaxa 124: 1−24.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref6"><author>Konstantinov</author><cYear>2011</cYear><volume_title>Revision of the Palearctic Chaetocnema species (Coleoptera Chrysomelidae Galerucinae Alticini)</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Konstantinov AS, Baselga A, Grebennikov VV, Prena J, Lingafelter SW (2011) Revision of the Palearctic Chaetocnema species (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae: Galerucinae: Alticini). Pensoft, Sofia-Moscow, 363 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref6"><doi>10.1649/0010-065X(2006)60[275:ANGOMF]2.0.CO;2</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref7"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Konstantinov</author><volume>1037</volume><first_page>49</first_page><cYear>2005</cYear><article_title>New species of Clavicornaltica Scherer (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae) from continental Asia.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Konstantinov AS, Duckett CN (2005) New species of Clavicornaltica Scherer (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae) from continental Asia. Zootaxa 1037: 49−64.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref7"><doi>10.1649/1089.1</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref8"><author>Laboissière</author><first_page>575</first_page><cYear>1932</cYear><volume_title>Synopsis des genres de Galerucini de Madagascar</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Laboissière V (1932) Synopsis des genres de Galerucini de Madagascar. Société Entomologique de France, Livre du Centenaire. Paris, 575−592.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref9"><issn>01510517</issn><journal_title>Bull Soc Entomol Fr</journal_title><author>Laboissière</author><volume>42</volume><first_page>27</first_page><cYear>1937</cYear><article_title>Nouveaux Galerucinae palearctiques.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Laboissière V (1937) Nouveaux Galerucinae palearctiques. Bull. Soc. Entomol. Fr. 42 :27−31.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref10"><issn>00351814</issn><journal_title>Rev Zool Bot Afr</journal_title><author>Laboissière</author><volume>34</volume><first_page>316</first_page><cYear>1941</cYear><article_title>Nouveaux Halticinae et Galerucinae de la Collection du Musée du Congo.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Laboissière V (1941) Nouveaux Halticinae et Galerucinae de la Collection du Musée du Congo. Revue de Zoologie et de Botanique africaines 34: 316−321.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref11"><journal_title>Institut des Parcs Nationaux du Congo Belge</journal_title><author>Laboissière</author><volume>39</volume><first_page>3</first_page><cYear>1942</cYear><article_title>Exploration du Parc National Albert. Mission G.F. De Witte (1933−1935). Halticinae (Coleoptera Phytophaga). Fam. Chrysomelidae.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Laboissière V (1942) Exploration du Parc National Albert. Mission G.F. De Witte (1933−1935). Halticinae (Coleoptera Phytophaga). Fam. Chrysomelidae. Institut des Parcs Nationaux du Congo Belge 39: 3−130.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref12"><author>Latreille</author><cYear>1810</cYear><volume_title>Considérations générales sur l ordre naturel des animaux composant les classes des Crustacés des Arachnides et des Insectes Avec un tableau méthodique de leurs genres disposés en familles</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Latreille PA (1810) Considérations générales sur l'ordre naturel des animaux composant les classes des Crustacés, des Arachnides, et des Insectes. Avec un tableau méthodique de leurs genres, disposés en familles. F. Schoell, Paris, 444 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref13"><doi>10.5962/bhl.title.11575</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref14"><author>Linnaeus</author><cYear>1758</cYear><volume_title>Systema Naturae per regna tria naturae secundum classes ordines genera species cum caracteribus differentiis synonymis locis Tomus I Editio Decima reformata Laurentii Salvii</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Linnaeus C (1758) Systema Naturae per regna tria naturae,: secundum classes, ordines, genera, species cum caracteribus, differentiis, synonymis, locis. Tomus I. Editio Decima, reformata. Laurentii Salvii, Stockholmiae, 824 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref15"><author>Linnaeus</author><cYear>1761</cYear><volume_title>Fauna Svecica sistens Animalia Sveciae regni Mammalia Aves Amphibia Pisces Insecta Vermes Distributa per classes &amp; ordines genera &amp; species cum differentiis specierum synonymis auctorum nominibus incolarum locis natalium descriptionibus insectorum Laurentii Salvii</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Linnaeus C (1761) Fauna Svecica sistens Animalia Sveciae regni: Mammalia, Aves, Amphibia, Pisces, Insecta, Vermes. Distributa per classes &amp; ordines, genera &amp; species, cum differentiis specierum, synonymis auctorum, nominibus incolarum, locis natalium, descriptionibus insectorum. Laurentii Salvii, Stockholmiae, 578 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref16"><author>Lucas</author><cYear>1849</cYear><volume_title>Exploration scientifique de l Algérie pendant les années 1840 1841 1842 publiée par ordre du gouvernement et avec le concours d une commission academique Sciences physiques Zoologie III</volume_title><article_title>Histoire naturelle des Animaux Articulés. Deuxieme Partie. Insectes.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Lucas PH (1849) Histoire naturelle des Animaux Articulés. Deuxieme Partie. Insectes. In: Exploration scientifique de l'Algérie pendant les années 1840, 1841, 1842, publiée par ordre du gouvernement et avec le concours d'une commission academique. Sciences physiques. Zoologie III. Imprimerie Nationale, Paris, 590 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref17"><journal_title>Proceedings of the Royal Entomological Society of London</journal_title><author>Maulik</author><volume>1929</volume><first_page>305</first_page><cYear>1929</cYear><article_title>On the structure of the hind femur in halticine beetles.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Maulik S (1929) On the structure of the hind femur in halticine beetles. Proceedings of the Royal Entomological Society of London 1929: 305−308.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref18"><issn>09442006</issn><journal_title>Zoology</journal_title><author>Maulik</author><volume>19</volume><first_page>241</first_page><cYear>1931</cYear><article_title>Coleoptera, Chrysomelidae, Eumolpinae, Galerucinae and Halticinae. Percy Sladen Trust Expedition,1905. Transactions of the Linnean Society of London (series 2)</article_title><unstructured_citation>Maulik S (1931) Coleoptera, Chrysomelidae, Eumolpinae, Galerucinae and Halticinae. Percy Sladen Trust Expedition,1905. Transactions of the Linnean Society of London (series 2), Zoology 19: 241−260.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref19"><journal_title>Entomologica Basiliensia</journal_title><author>Medvedev</author><volume>18</volume><first_page>479</first_page><cYear>1995</cYear><article_title>New species of Alticinae (Coleoptera, Chrysomelidae) from South Asia.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Medvedev LN (1995) New species of Alticinae (Coleoptera, Chrysomelidae) from South Asia. Entomologica Basiliensia 18: 479−488.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><journal_title>Fauna of Saudi Arabia</journal_title><author>Medvedev</author><volume>15</volume><first_page>215</first_page><cYear>1996</cYear><article_title>The Chrysomelidae of Arabia.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Medvedev LN (1996) The Chrysomelidae of Arabia. Fauna of Saudi Arabia 15: 215−263.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref21"><issn>03418391</issn><journal_title>Spixiana</journal_title><author>Medvedev</author><volume>25</volume><first_page>59</first_page><cYear>2002</cYear><article_title>New and poorly known Chrysomelidae from the Philippines (Insecta, Coleoptera).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Medvedev LN (2002) New and poorly known Chrysomelidae from the Philippines (Insecta, Coleoptera). Spixiana 25: 59–67.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref22"><journal_title>Entomologica Basiliensia et Collectionis Frey</journal_title><author>Medvedev</author><volume>30</volume><first_page>243</first_page><cYear>2008</cYear><article_title>New species of Chrysomelidae (Coleoptera) from Sulawesi.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Medvedev LN (2008) New species of Chrysomelidae (Coleoptera) from Sulawesi. Entomologica Basiliensia et Collectionis Frey 30: 243–261.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref23"><author>Medvedev</author><cYear>2009</cYear><volume_title>Alticinae of Indochina</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Medvedev L (2009) Alticinae of Indochina. KMK Scientific Press, Moscow, 224 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref24"><journal_title>Entomologische Arbeiten aus dem Museum Georg Frey</journal_title><author>Monrós</author><volume>7</volume><first_page>1118</first_page><cYear>1956</cYear><article_title>Über einige verkannte Chrysomeliden-Namen.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Monrós F., Bechyné J (1956) Über einige verkannte Chrysomeliden-Namen. Entomologische Arbeiten aus dem Museum Georg Frey 7: 1118−1137.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref25"><author>Motschulsky</author><volume>2</volume><first_page>77</first_page><cYear>1860</cYear><volume_title>Reisen und Forschungen im Amurlande</volume_title><article_title>Coleopteres de la Siberie orientale et en particulier des rives de l'Amour.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Motschulsky V (1860) Coleopteres de la Siberie orientale et en particulier des rives de l'Amour. In: Schrenck L von (Ed) Reisen und Forschungen im Amurlande. Vol. 2. St. Petersburg, pp. 77−257.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref25"><doi>10.1017/S0014479797003116</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref26"><journal_title>Entomologica Basiliensia et Collectionis Frey</journal_title><author>Nadein</author><volume>29</volume><first_page>307</first_page><cYear>2007</cYear><article_title>On the taxonomy and classification of the genus Psylliodes Latreille, 1825 (Coleoptera, Chrysomelidae, Galerucinae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Nadein KS (2007) On the taxonomy and classification of the genus Psylliodes Latreille, 1825 (Coleoptera, Chrysomelidae, Galerucinae). Entomologica Basiliensia et Collectionis Frey 29: 307−332.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref27"><author>Olivier</author><volume>IV</volume><cYear>1789</cYear><volume_title>Encyclopédie Méthodique ou par ordre de Matières par une Societé de Gens de Lettres de savans et d Artistes précedée d un vocabulire universel servant de table pour tout l ouvrage ornée des portraits de MM Diderot &amp; D Alembert premiers editeurs de l Encyclopédie Histoire Naturelle Insectes</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Olivier GA (1789) Encyclopédie Méthodique, ou par ordre de Matières; par une Societé de Gens de Lettres, de savans et d'Artistes; précedée d'un vocabulire universel, servant de table pour tout l'ouvrage, ornée des portraits de MM. Diderot &amp; D'Alembert, premiers editeurs de l'Encyclopédie. Histoire Naturelle. Insectes. Tome IV. Chez Panckoucke, Paris, 519 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref28"><author>Olivier</author><volume>VI</volume><first_page>613</first_page><cYear>1808</cYear><volume_title>Entomologie ou histoire naturelle des Insectes avec leurs caractères génériques et spécifiques leur description leur synonymie et leur figure enluminée Coléoptères</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Olivier GA (1808) Entomologie, ou histoire naturelle des Insectes, avec leurs caractères génériques et spécifiques, leur description, leur synonymie et leur figure enluminée. Coléoptères, Tome VI. Desray Libraire, pp. 613–1104.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref28"><doi>10.1017/S0007485300046538</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref28"><doi>10.3897/zookeys.157.1472</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><issn>00138797</issn><journal_title>Proc Entomol Soc Wash</journal_title><author>Savini</author><volume>103</volume><first_page>903</first_page><cYear>2001</cYear><article_title>The status of Heikertingerella, Monotalla, Pseudodibolia, and Sphaeroderma (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae: Alticinae) in the New World.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Savini V, Furth DG (2001) The status of Heikertingerella, Monotalla, Pseudodibolia, and Sphaeroderma (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae: Alticinae) in the New World. Proc. Entomol. Soc. Wash. 103: 903−912.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><journal_title>Boletin Sociedad Entomológica Aragonesa</journal_title><author>Savini</author><volume>44</volume><first_page>53</first_page><cYear>2009</cYear><article_title>Bubiscus, un género nuevo neotropical (Coleoptera, Chrysomelidae, Alticinae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Savini V, Furth DG, Joly LJ (2009) Bubiscus, un género nuevo neotropical (Coleoptera, Chrysomelidae, Alticinae). Boletin Sociedad Entomológica Aragonesa 44: 53−61.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><journal_title>Transactions Royal Dublin Society</journal_title><author>Sharp</author><volume>3</volume><first_page>351</first_page><cYear>1886</cYear><article_title>On New Zealand Coleoptera, with description of new genera and species.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Sharp D (1886) On New Zealand Coleoptera, with description of new genera and species. Transactions Royal Dublin Society 3: 351−456.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref32"><journal_title>Entomologische Arbeiten aus dem Museum Georg Frey</journal_title><author>Scherer</author><volume>10</volume><first_page>177</first_page><cYear>1959</cYear><article_title>Die Alticiden-Ausbeute der Expedition des Museums G. Frey nach Nigeria-Kamerun 1955/56 (Col. Phytoph.).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Scherer G (1959) Die Alticiden-Ausbeute der Expedition des Museums G. Frey nach Nigeria-Kamerun 1955/56 (Col. Phytoph.). Entomologische Arbeiten aus dem Museum Georg Frey 10: 177−265.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><journal_title>Entomologische Arbeiten aus dem Museum Georg Frey</journal_title><author>Scherer</author><volume>12</volume><first_page>251</first_page><cYear>1961</cYear><article_title>Bestimmungsschlussel der Alticinen-Genera Afrikas.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Scherer G (1961) Bestimmungsschlussel der Alticinen-Genera Afrikas. Entomologische Arbeiten aus dem Museum Georg Frey 12: 251−288.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref34"><journal_title>Sciences Zoologiques</journal_title><author>Scherer</author><volume>113</volume><first_page>7</first_page><cYear>1962</cYear><article_title>Beitrag zur Kenntnis der Alticiden-fauna Zentral-Afrikas (Coleoptera Chrysomelidae Alticinae). Annales de Musée Royal de l'Afrique Centrale de Tervuren, Belgique, Series in 8°</article_title><unstructured_citation>Scherer G (1962a) Beitrag zur Kenntnis der Alticiden-fauna Zentral-Afrikas (Coleoptera Chrysomelidae Alticinae). Annales de Musée Royal de l'Afrique Centrale de Tervuren, Belgique, Series in 8°, Sciences Zoologiques 113: 7−82.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref35"><journal_title>Institut Parcs Nationaux du Congo et du Rwanda (Bruxelles)</journal_title><author>Scherer</author><volume>31</volume><first_page>3</first_page><cYear>1962</cYear><article_title>Alticinae (Coleoptera, Phytophaga) Fam. Chrysomelidae. Exploration du Parc National de la Garamba. Mission H. De Saeger (1949−1952).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Scherer G (1962b) Alticinae (Coleoptera, Phytophaga) Fam. Chrysomelidae. Exploration du Parc National de la Garamba. Mission H. De Saeger (1949−1952). Institut Parcs Nationaux du Congo et du Rwanda (Bruxelles) 31: 3−86.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref36"><journal_title>Entomologische Arbeiten aus dem Museum Georg Frey</journal_title><author>Scherer</author><volume>14</volume><first_page>648</first_page><cYear>1963</cYear><article_title>Beitrag zur Kenntnis der Alticidenfauna Afrikas (Coleoptera, Chrysomelidae, Alticinae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Scherer G (1963) Beitrag zur Kenntnis der Alticidenfauna Afrikas (Coleoptera, Chrysomelidae, Alticinae). Entomologische Arbeiten aus dem Museum Georg Frey 14: 648−684.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref37"><journal_title>Sciences Zoologiques</journal_title><author>Scherer</author><volume>175</volume><first_page>365</first_page><cYear>1969</cYear><article_title>Contribution à la connaissance de la faune entomologique de la Côte-d'Ivoire (J. Decelle, 1961−1964). XLIII. Coleoptera Chrysomelidae Alticinae. Annales de Musée Royal de l'Afrique Centrale de Tervuren, Belgique, Series in 8°</article_title><unstructured_citation>Scherer G (1969) Contribution à la connaissance de la faune entomologique de la Côte-d'Ivoire (J. Decelle, 1961−1964). XLIII. Coleoptera Chrysomelidae Alticinae. Annales de Musée Royal de l'Afrique Centrale de Tervuren, Belgique, Series in 8°, Sciences Zoologiques 175: 365−371.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref38"><journal_title>Entomologische Arbeiten aus dem Museum Georg Frey</journal_title><author>Scherer</author><volume>21</volume><first_page>298</first_page><cYear>1970</cYear><article_title>Beitrag zur Kenntnis der Alticinae Afrikas (Coleoptera - Chrysomelidae - Alticinae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Scherer G (1970) Beitrag zur Kenntnis der Alticinae Afrikas (Coleoptera - Chrysomelidae - Alticinae). Entomologische Arbeiten aus dem Museum Georg Frey 21: 298−304.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref39"><journal_title>Notulae Entomologicae</journal_title><author>Scherer</author><volume>52</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1972</cYear><article_title>Coleoptera aus Nordostafrica. Chrysomelidae: Alticinae.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Scherer G (1972) Coleoptera aus Nordostafrica. Chrysomelidae: Alticinae. Notulae Entomologicae 52 :1−17.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref40"><issn>0035418X</issn><journal_title>Rev Suisse Zool</journal_title><author>Scherer</author><volume>81</volume><first_page>57</first_page><cYear>1974</cYear><article_title>Clavicornaltica a new genus from Ceylon (Coleoptera-Chrysomelidae-Alticinae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Scherer G (1974) Clavicornaltica a new genus from Ceylon (Coleoptera-Chrysomelidae-Alticinae). Revue Suisse de Zoologie 81: 57–68.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref41"><issn>03418391</issn><journal_title>Spixiana</journal_title><author>Scherer</author><volume>20</volume><first_page>7</first_page><cYear>1997</cYear><article_title>Attraction of Gabonia and Nzerekorena to pyrrolizidine alkaloids - with description of 13 new species and notes on male structural peculiarities (Insecta, Coleoptera, Chrysomelidae, Alticinae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Scherer G, Boppré M (1997) Attraction of Gabonia and Nzerekorena to pyrrolizidine alkaloids - with description of 13 new species and notes on male structural peculiarities (Insecta, Coleoptera, Chrysomelidae, Alticinae). Spixiana 20: 7−38.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref42"><journal_title>Zoology London</journal_title><author>Sclater</author><volume>2</volume><first_page>130</first_page><cYear>1858</cYear><article_title>On the general distribution of the members of the Class Aves. Journal of the Linnean Society</article_title><unstructured_citation>Sclater P (1858) On the general distribution of the members of the Class Aves. Journal of the Linnean Society, Zoology, London 2: 130–145.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref43"><journal_title>Entomography</journal_title><author>Seeno</author><volume>1</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1982</cYear><article_title>Leaf beetle genera (Coleoptera, Chrysomelidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Seeno TN, Wilcox JA (1982) Leaf beetle genera (Coleoptera, Chrysomelidae). Entomography 1: 1−221.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref44"><journal_title>Bulletin de l Institut Francais d Afrique Noire</journal_title><author>Selman</author><volume>25</volume><first_page>1148</first_page><cYear>1963</cYear><article_title>Coléopterès Chrysomelides récoltés par M.J. Mateu dans l'Ennedi et au Tchad.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Selman BJ (1963) Coléopterès Chrysomelides récoltés par M.J. Mateu dans l'Ennedi et au Tchad. Bulletin de l'Institut Francais d'Afrique Noire (série A) 25: 1148−1162.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref44"><doi>10.1080/00222936800770901</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref44"><doi>10.5962/bhl.title.51800</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref45"><author>Stephens</author><volume>IV</volume><cYear>1831</cYear><volume_title>Illustrations of British Entomology or a Synopsis of Indigenous Insects containing their generic and specific distinctions with an account of their metamorphoses times of appearance localities food and economy as far as practicable Mandibulata</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Stephens JF (1831) Illustrations of British Entomology; or, a Synopsis of Indigenous Insects: containing their generic and specific distinctions; with an account of their metamorphoses, times of appearance, localities, food, and economy, as far as practicable. Mandibulata. Vol. IV. Baldwin &amp; Craddock, London, 366 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref46"><journal_title>Mittheilungen der Schweizer Entomologischen Gesellschaft</journal_title><author>Stierlin</author><volume>1866–1868</volume><first_page>30</first_page><cYear>1866</cYear><article_title>Coleopterologisches.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Stierlin G (1866) Coleopterologisches. Mittheilungen der Schweizer Entomologischen Gesellschaft 1866–1868: 30–32.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><journal_title>Archives Entomologiques</journal_title><author>Thomson</author><volume>2</volume><first_page>9</first_page><cYear>1858</cYear><article_title>Voyage au Gabon.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Thomson J (1858) Voyage au Gabon. Archives Entomologiques 2: 9−471.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Jolivet P, Verma KK (2002) Biology of leaf beetles. Intercept Publishers, Andover, Hampshire, xiv + 332 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Kiesenwetter von H (1877) In: Erichson WF (Ed) Naturgeschichte der Insecten Deutschlands. Erste Abtheilung. Coleoptera. Fünfter Band, Erste Lieferung, Bogen 1−12. Nicolaische Verlags-Buchhandlung, Berlin, 887 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Konstantinov AS, Vanderberg NJ (1996) Handbook of Palearctic Flea Beetle (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae: Alticinae). Contribution on Entomology 1: 237–439.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Laboissière V (1922) Étude des Galerucini de la Collection du Musée du Congo belge. Première Partie. Revue Zoologique africaine 10: 131–183.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Lebert H (1879) Hydrachnides du Léman. In Forel F.A.(ed.): Fauna profonde du Lac Léman. Bulletin de la Société Vaudoise des Sciences Naturelles 16: 327−377.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Marsham T (1802) Entomologia Britannica, sistens insecta Britanniae indigena, secundum methodum Linneanum disposita. I. Coleoptera. J. White, London, xxxi + 548 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Maulik S (1926) The Fauna of British India, including Ceylon and Burma. Coleoptera. Chrysomelidae (Chrysomelinae and Halticinae). Taylor and Francis, London, xiv + 443 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Palisot de Beauvois AMFJ (1812) Essai d'une nouvelle agrostographie, ou, Nouveaux genres des graminées: avec figures représentant les caractères de tous les genres. Imprimé de l'auteur, Paris, lxxiv + 182 pp., xxv pls.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Pic M (1921) Notes diverses, descriptions et diagnoses. Echange 37: 1−6, 9−10, 13−15.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Santiago-Blay JA (2004) Leaf-mining chrysomelids. In Jolivet P., Santiago-Blay J.A., Schmitt M. (eds): New developments on the biology of Chrysomelidae. SPB Academic Publishing bv, The Hague, The Netherlands. pp. 305−306 and pp. 1−83 of CD-ROM.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Scherer G (1978) Missione 1965 del professor Giuseppe Scortecci nello Yemen (Arabia meridionale). Coleoptera Chrysomelidae: Alticinae. Atti della Società Italiana di Scienze naturali e del Museo Civico di Storia naturale di Milano 119: 264−266.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Scherer G (1983) Review of the genus Chirodica Germar. Entomologische Arbeiten aus dem Museum Georg Frey 31−32: 173−175.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Scherer G (1985) Yemenaltica, eine neue Gattung aus dem Yemen (Coleoptera Chrysomelidae Alticinae). Atti della Società Italiana di Scienze naturali e del Museo Civico di Storia naturale di Milano 126: 85−88.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Scherer G (1987) The Genus Torodera Weise (Coleoptera - Chrysomelidae - Alticinae). Entomologische Arbeiten aus dem Museum Georg Frey 35−36: 67−71.</unstructured_citation></citation>
</citation_list>
</doi_citations>
</body>
</doi_batch>
