<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doi_batch version="4.3.0" xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/doi_resources_schema/4.3.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/doi_resources_schema/4.3.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/deposit/doi_resources4.3.0.xsd">
<head>
<doi_batch_id>1fe9c074-24ea-4574-8b2f-83ae7febaa2e</doi_batch_id>
<depositor>
<name>pens</name>
<email_address>bozhin.karaivanov@gmail.com</email_address>
</depositor>
</head>
<body>
<doi_citations>
<doi>part-1-281-4171</doi>
<citation_list>
	<citation key="ref1"><issn>13300520</issn><journal_title>Natura Croat</journal_title><author>Arko-Pjevac</author><volume>10</volume><issue>3</issue><first_page>163</first_page><cYear>2001</cYear><article_title>A submarine cave at the Island of KRK (North Adriatic Sea).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Arko-Pjevac M, Benac C, Kovacic M, Kirincic M (2001) A submarine cave at the Island of KRK (North Adriatic Sea). Natura Croatica 10(3): 163–184.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref2"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Bakran-Petricioli</author><volume>3172</volume><first_page>20</first_page><cYear>2012</cYear><article_title>How diverse is sponge fauna in the Adriatic Sea?</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bakran-Petricioli T, Radolovic M, Petricioli D (2012) How diverse is sponge fauna in the Adriatic Sea? Zootaxa 3172: 20–38.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref3"><journal_title>Bulletin de l Institut National Scientifique et Technique d Océanographie et de Pêche de Salammbô</journal_title><author>Ben Mustapha</author><volume>29</volume><first_page>23</first_page><cYear>2002</cYear><article_title>Tunisian megabenthos from infra (Posidonia meadows) and circalittoral (coralligenous) sites.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Ben Mustapha K, Komatsu K, Hattour A, Sammari C, Zarrouk S, Souissi A, El Abed A (2002) Tunisian megabenthos from infra (Posidonia meadows) and circalittoral (coralligenous) sites. Bulletin de l'Institut National Scientifique et Technique d'Océanographie et de Pêche de Salammbô 29: 23–36.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref4"><journal_title>Bulletin de l Institut National Scientifique et Technique d Océanographie et de Pêche de Salammbô</journal_title><author>Ben Mustapha</author><volume>30</volume><first_page>55</first_page><cYear>2003</cYear><article_title>Diversité des demosponges tunisiennes.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Ben Mustapha K, Zarrouk A, Souissi A, El Abed A (2003) Diversité des demosponges tunisiennes. Bulletin de l'Institut National Scientifique et Technique d'Océanographie et de Pêche de Salammbô 30: 55–78.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref4"><doi>10.1017/S0025315400039953</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref4"><doi>10.1080/03014223.1980.10423761</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref5"><issn>03014223</issn><journal_title>N Z J Zool</journal_title><author>Bergquist</author><volume>7</volume><issue>4</issue><first_page>443</first_page><cYear>1980</cYear><article_title>A revision of the supraspecific classification of the orders Dictyoceratida, Dendroceratida and Verongida (class Demospongiae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bergquist PR (1980b) A revision of the supraspecific classification of the orders Dictyoceratida, Dendroceratida and Verongida (class Demospongiae). New Zealand Journal of Zoology 7(4): 443–503.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref6"><journal_title>New Zealand Oceanographic Institute Memoir</journal_title><author>Bergquist</author><volume>107</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1996</cYear><article_title>The Marine Fauna of New Zealand: Porifera: Demospongiae. Part 5. Dendroceratida and Halisarca.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bergquist PR (1996) The Marine Fauna of New Zealand: Porifera: Demospongiae. Part 5. Dendroceratida and Halisarca. New Zealand Oceanographic Institute Memoir 107: 1–53.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref7"><author>Bibiloni</author><first_page>383</first_page><cYear>1984</cYear><volume_title>Els sistemes naturals de les Illes Medes</volume_title><article_title>Les esponges de les Illes Medes.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bibiloni A, Olivella I, Ros J (1984a) Les esponges de les Illes Medes. In: Ros J, Olivella I, Gili JM (Eds) Els sistemes naturals de les Illes Medes. Barcelona: Arxius de la Secciò de Ciéncies, 383–405.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref7"><doi>10.1111/j.1439-0485.1989.tb00076.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref7"><doi>10.1016/j.ympev.2004.02.021</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref8"><author>Borg</author><cYear>2004</cYear><volume_title>Report on a survey of the marine infralittoral benthic habitats in the Dwejra/Qawra area (Gozo Maltese Islands) Mosta</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Borg JA, Dimech M, Schembri PJ (2004) Report on a survey of the marine infralittoral benthic habitats in the Dwejra/Qawra area (Gozo, Maltese Islands). Mosta (Malta), Ecoserv 30 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref9"><issn>00079723</issn><journal_title>Cah Biol Mar</journal_title><author>Borojevic</author><volume>9</volume><issue>1</issue><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1968</cYear><article_title>Inventaire de la faune marine de Roscoff. Spongiaires.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Borojevic R, Cabioch, Lévi C (1968) Inventaire de la faune marine de Roscoff. Spongiaires. Cahiers de Biologie Marine 9(1): 1–44.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref10"><issn>02408759</issn><journal_title>Vie Milieu</journal_title><author>Boury-Esnault</author><volume>22</volume><issue>2</issue><first_page>287</first_page><cYear>1971</cYear><article_title>Spongiaires de la zone rocheuse littorale de Banyuls-sur-Mer. II. Systématique.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Boury-Esnault N (1971) Spongiaires de la zone rocheuse littorale de Banyuls-sur-Mer. II. Systématique. Vie Milieu 22(2): 287–349.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref11"><journal_title>Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society</journal_title><author>Bowerbank</author><volume>152</volume><issue>2</issue><first_page>1087</first_page><cYear>1862</cYear><article_title>On the Anatomy and Physiology of the Spongiadae. Part III. On the Generic Characters, the Specific Characters, and on the Method of Examination.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bowerbank JS (1862) On the Anatomy and Physiology of the Spongiadae. Part III. On the Generic Characters, the Specific Characters, and on the Method of Examination. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society 152(2): 1087–1135.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref12"><issn>01739565</issn><journal_title>Mar Ecol (Berl )</journal_title><author>Bussotti</author><volume>325</volume><first_page>109</first_page><cYear>2006</cYear><article_title>Spatial and temporal variability of sessile benthos in shallow Mediterranean marine cave.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bussotti S, Terlizzi A, Fraschetti S, Belmonte G, Boero F (2006) Spatial and temporal variability of sessile benthos in shallow Mediterranean marine cave. Marine Ecology 325: 109–119.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref13"><issn>00079723</issn><journal_title>Cah Biol Mar</journal_title><author>Cabioch</author><volume>9</volume><first_page>493</first_page><cYear>1968</cYear><article_title>Contribution à la connaissance des peuplement benthiques de la Manche Occidentale.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Cabioch L (1968) Contribution à la connaissance des peuplement benthiques de la Manche Occidentale. Cahiers de Biologie Marine 9: 493–720.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref14"><author>Cinelli</author><first_page>173</first_page><cYear>1977</cYear><volume_title>Biology of benthic organisms</volume_title><article_title>Distribution of benthic phyto- and zoo-coenoses along a light gradient in a superficial marine cave.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Cinelli F, Fresi E, Mazzella L, Pansini M, Pronzato R, Svoboda A (1977) Distribution of benthic phyto- and zoo-coenoses along a light gradient in a superficial marine cave. In: Keegan BF, O'Cèidigh P, Boaden PJS (Eds) Biology of benthic organisms, Pergamon Press, London, 173–183.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref14"><doi>10.1080/11250000409356578</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref14"><doi>10.1046/j.1439-0485.2000.00655.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref15"><issn>05633745</issn><journal_title>Thalassia Salent</journal_title><author>Denitto</author><volume>32</volume><first_page>129</first_page><cYear>2010</cYear><article_title>Prima indagine faunistica della Grotta del Sifone (Canale d'Otranto, Salento Meridionale, Italia).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Denitto F, Bussotti S, Costantini A, Poto M, Onorato R, Belmonte G (2010) Prima indagine faunistica della Grotta del Sifone (Canale d'Otranto, Salento Meridionale, Italia). Thalassia Salentina 32: 129–138.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref16"><author>Desqueyroux-Faundez</author><cYear>1992</cYear><volume_title>O Schmidt sponge catalogue An illustrated guide to the Graz Museum Collection with notes on additional material</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Desqueyroux-Faundez R, Stone SM (1992) O. Schmidt sponge catalogue. An illustrated guide to the Graz Museum Collection, with notes on additional material. Museum d'Histoire Naturelle Genève 190 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref17"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Ereskovsky</author><volume>2768</volume><first_page>5</first_page><cYear>2011</cYear><article_title>Molecular and morphological description of a new species of Halisarca (Demospongiae: Halisarcida) from Mediterranean Sea and a redescription of the type species Halisarca dujardini.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Ereskovsky AV, Lavrov DV, Boury-Esnault N, Vacelet J (2011) Molecular and morphological description of a new species of Halisarca (Demospongiae: Halisarcida) from Mediterranean Sea and a redescription of the type species Halisarca dujardini. Zootaxa 2768: 5–31.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref18"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Erpenbeck</author><volume>1668</volume><first_page>107</first_page><cYear>2007</cYear><article_title>On the molecular phylogeny of sponges (Porifera).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Erpenbeck D, Wörheide G (2007) On the molecular phylogeny of sponges (Porifera). Zootaxa 1668: 107–126.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref18"><doi>10.1016/j.ympev.2012.02.024</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref19"><journal_title>Annales Series Historia Naturalis</journal_title><author>Faresi</author><volume>16</volume><first_page>9</first_page><cYear>2006</cYear><article_title>Benthic macrofauna of a submarine cave on the Istrian Peninsula (Croatia).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Faresi L, Bettoso N, Aleffi IF (2006) Benthic macrofauna of a submarine cave on the Istrian Peninsula (Croatia). Annales Series Historia Naturalis 16: 9–16.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><journal_title>Animal Biology</journal_title><author>Gaino</author><volume>4</volume><first_page>31</first_page><cYear>1995</cYear><article_title>Organizational plasticity as a successful conservative tactics in sponges.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gaino E, Manconi R, Pronzato R (1995) Organizational plasticity as a successful conservative tactics in sponges. Animal Biology 4: 31–43.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><doi>10.1371/journal.pone.0039873</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref21"><author>Grant</author><cYear>1861</cYear><volume_title>Tabular view of the primary divisions of the Animal Kingdom</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Grant RE (1861) Tabular view of the primary divisions of the Animal Kingdom. London, 91 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref22"><journal_title>Scientific Reports of the Port-Cros Natural Park</journal_title><author>Harmelin</author><volume>19</volume><first_page>117</first_page><cYear>2003</cYear><article_title>Peuplement de la grotte sous-marine de l'Ile de Bagaud (Parc National de Port-Cros, France, Méditerranée).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Harmelin JG, Boury-Esnault N, Fichez R, Vacelet J, Zibrowius H (2003) Peuplement de la grotte sous-marine de l'Ile de Bagaud (Parc National de Port-Cros, France, Méditerranée). Scientific Reports of the Port-Cros Natural Park 19:117–134.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref23"><doi>10.1007/978-1-4615-0747-5</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref24"><journal_title>Chiara</journal_title><author>Labate</author><volume>14</volume><first_page>319</first_page><cYear>1964</cYear><article_title>Poriferi di grotta superficiale del litorale adriatico pugliese. Annali dell'Istituto Superiore di Scienze e Lettere S.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Labate M (1964) Poriferi di grotta superficiale del litorale adriatico pugliese. Annali dell'Istituto Superiore di Scienze e Lettere S. Chiara 14: 319–342.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref25"><issn>11250003</issn><journal_title>Ital J Zool (Modena)</journal_title><author>Labate</author><volume>32</volume><issue>1</issue><first_page>541</first_page><cYear>1965</cYear><article_title>Ecologia dei Poriferi della Grotta della Regina.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Labate M (1965) Ecologia dei Poriferi della Grotta della Regina. Italian Journal of Zoology 32(1): 541–553.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref26"><journal_title>Bulletin de l Institut Océanographique de Monaco</journal_title><author>Laborel</author><volume>55</volume><issue>1120</issue><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1958</cYear><article_title>Etude des peuplements d'une grotte sous-marine du Golfe de Marseille.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Laborel J, Vacelet J (1958) Etude des peuplements d'une grotte sous-marine du Golfe de Marseille. Bulletin de l'Institut Océanographique de Monaco 55(1120): 1–20.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref26"><doi>10.1016/j.ympev.2008.05.014</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref27"><cYear>1759</cYear><volume_title>Systema naturae per regna tria naturæ secundum classes ordines genera species cum characteribus differentiis synonymis locis Tomus II Editio decima reformata</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Linnaeus (Linnaei) C (1759) Systema naturae per regna tria naturæ, secundum classes, ordines, genera, species, cum characteribus, differentiis, synonymis, locis. Tomus II. Editio decima, reformata, 1348 pp. Holmiae, Laurentii Salvii.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref28"><journal_title>Biologia Marina Mediterranea</journal_title><author>Manconi</author><volume>18</volume><issue>1</issue><first_page>258</first_page><cYear>2011</cYear><article_title>Biodiversity of Sardinian marine caves: sponge fauna.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Manconi R, Cadeddu B, Pansini M, Pronzato R, Ledda FD (2011) Biodiversity of Sardinian marine caves: sponge fauna. Biologia Marina Mediterranea 18(1): 258–259.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><author>Von Martens</author><cYear>1824</cYear><volume_title>Reise nach Venedig</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Martens GM Von (1824) Reise nach Venedig. 2 Volumes.(Stettinschen Buchhandlung: Ulm).</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><doi>10.1017/S0025315404009567h</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><journal_title>Giacomo Doria</journal_title><author>Melone</author><volume>75</volume><first_page>344</first_page><cYear>1965</cYear><article_title>I Poriferi associati a Corallium rubrum (L.) della Sardegna. Annali del Museo Civico di Storia Naturale</article_title><unstructured_citation>Melone N (1965) I Poriferi associati a Corallium rubrum (L.) della Sardegna. Annali del Museo Civico di Storia Naturale &quot;Giacomo Doria&quot; 75: 344–358.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><unstructured_citation>Balduzzi A, Bianchi CN, Boero F, Cattaneo-Vietti R, Pansini M, Sarà M (1989) The suspension – feeder communities of a Mediterranean sea cave. In: Ros JD (Ed.) Topics in marine biology. Scientia Marina 53(2–3): 387–395.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><unstructured_citation>Barrois C (1876) Mémoire sur l'embryologie de quelques Eponges de la Manche. Annales des Sciences Naturelles (6) 3(11): 1–84.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><unstructured_citation>Bergquist PR, Cook S De C (2002a) Order Dendroceratida Minchin, 1900. In: Hooper JNA and Van Soest RWM (Eds) Systema Porifera: a guide to the classification of Sponges, Vol. I, New York, NY (USA), Kluwer Academic/Plenum Publishers, 1067–1076.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><unstructured_citation>Bergquist PR, Cook S De C (2002b) Order Halisarcida Bergquist, 1996. In: Hooper JNA, Van Soest RWM (Eds) Systema Porifera: a guide to the classification of Sponges. Vol. I, New York, NY (USA), Kluwer Academic/Plenum Publishers, 1077–1080.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><unstructured_citation>Bergquist PR, Cook S De C (2002c) Order Verongida Bergquist, 1978. In: Hooper JNA, Van Soest RWM (Eds) Systema Porifera: a guide to the classification of Sponges. Vol. I, New York, NY (USA), Kluwer Academic/Plenum Publishers, 1081–196.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><unstructured_citation>Bianchi CN, Morri C (1994) Studio bionomico comparativo di alcune grotte sommerse: definizione di una scala di confinamento. Memorie dell'Istituto Italiano di Biospeolologia 6: 107–123.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><unstructured_citation>Bianchi CN, Cevasco MG, Diviacco G, Morri C (1986) Primi risultati di una ricerca ecologica sulla grotta marina di Bergeggi (Savona). Bollettino dei Musei e degli Istituti di Biologia dell'Università di Genova 52: 267–293.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><unstructured_citation>Bibiloni MA, Gili JM, Ros J (1984b) Les coves submarines de les Illes Mèdes. In: Ros J, Aragonès J, Olivella I, Prats I, Gili JM, Sardà JM (Eds) Els Sistemes Naturals de les Illes Mèdes. Instituciò Catalana d'Història Natural i Societat Catalana de Biologia, 708–735.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><unstructured_citation>Cadeddu B (2012) Biodiversity assessment in Mediterranean caves: the case of Porifera as model taxon. PhD Thesis, Sassari: University of Sassari (Italy).</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><unstructured_citation>Carter HJ (1876) Descriptions and figures of deep-sea sponges and their spicules, from the Atlantic Ocean, dredged up on board H.M.S.'Porcupine', chiefly in 1869 (concluded). Annals and Magazine of Natural History (4) 18(105): 226–240; (106): 307–324; (107): 388–410; (108): 458–479.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><unstructured_citation>Cook S De C, Bergquist PR (2002) Order Dictyoceratida Minchin, 1900. In: Hooper JNA, Van Soest RWM (Eds), Systema Porifera: a guide to the classification of Sponges, Vol. I, New York, NY (USA), Kluwer Academic/Plenum Publishers, 1021–1066.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><unstructured_citation>Erpenbeck D, Hendriks P, Strickland C, Ekins M, Schlacher-Hoenlinger MA, Degnan BM, Hooper JNA, Wörheide G (2007) Molecular and Biochemical Systematics of Keratose Sponges. ManaproXII International Symposium on Marine Natural Products. Conference Programme &amp; Proceedings, ISBN 978–0–473–11940–9, p 152.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><unstructured_citation>Johnston G (1842) A History of British Sponges and Lithophytes.(W.H. Lizars: Edinburgh): i-xii, 1–264, pls I-XXV.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><unstructured_citation>Lamarck JBP De Monet Comte De (1813–1814) Sur les polypiers empâtés. Suite du mémoire intitulé: Sur les Polypiers empâtés. Suite des éponges. Annales du Muséum national d'histoire naturelle, Paris 20 (6): 294–312 (published 1813), 370–386, 432–458 (published 1814).</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><unstructured_citation>Laubenfels MW de (1948) The order Keratosa of the phylum Porifera. A monographic study. Allan Hancock Foundation Occasional Paper 3: 1–217.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><unstructured_citation>Linnaeus (Linné) C (1789) Systema Naturae, per regna tria naturæ, secundum classes, ordines, genera, species cum characteribus, differentiis, synonymis, locis. Tomus I, Pars VI. Editio decima tertia aucta, reformata, 3817–3826 pp. Cura JF Gmelin, apud Deamolliere JB, Lugdini.</unstructured_citation></citation>
</citation_list>
</doi_citations>
</body>
</doi_batch>
