<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doi_batch version="4.3.0" xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/doi_resources_schema/4.3.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/doi_resources_schema/4.3.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/deposit/doi_resources4.3.0.xsd">
<head>
<doi_batch_id>66423310-5af7-421e-bbf6-5f61a52977ac</doi_batch_id>
<depositor>
<name>pens</name>
<email_address>bozhin.karaivanov@gmail.com</email_address>
</depositor>
</head>
<body>
<doi_citations>
<doi>part-2-281-4171</doi>
<citation_list>
	<citation key="ref1"><journal_title>Memoirs of the Wernerian Natural History Society</journal_title><author>Montagu</author><volume>2</volume><issue>1</issue><first_page>67</first_page><cYear>1818</cYear><article_title>An Essay on Sponges, with Descriptions of all the species that have been discovered on the Coast of Great Britain.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Montagu G (1818) An Essay on Sponges, with Descriptions of all the species that have been discovered on the Coast of Great Britain. Memoirs of the Wernerian Natural History Society 2(1): 67–122, pls III–XVI.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref2"><issn>13300520</issn><journal_title>Natura Croat</journal_title><author>Novosel</author><volume>11</volume><first_page>387</first_page><cYear>2002</cYear><article_title>The benthos of the northern part of the Velebit Channel (Adriatic Sea, Croatia).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Novosel M, Bakran-Petricioli T, Požar-Domac A, Kružić P, Radić I (2002) The benthos of the northern part of the Velebit Channel (Adriatic Sea, Croatia). Natura Croatica 11: 387–409.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref2"><doi>10.5962/bhl.title.6595</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref3"><journal_title>Bulletin de l Institut Océanographique de Monaco</journal_title><author>Pansini</author><volume>9</volume><first_page>43</first_page><cYear>1992</cYear><article_title>Considérations biogéographiques et systématiques pour une mise à jour des données sur le peuplement de spongiaires méditerranéens.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Pansini M (1992) Considérations biogéographiques et systématiques pour une mise à jour des données sur le peuplement de spongiaires méditerranéens. Bulletin de l'Institut Océanographique de Monaco 9: 43–51.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref4"><journal_title>Biogeographia</journal_title><author>Pansini</author><volume>24</volume><issue>1</issue><first_page>59</first_page><cYear>2003</cYear><article_title>A review of Mediterranean Sea sponge biogeography with, in appendix, a list of the demosponges hitherto recorded from this sea. Marine Biogeography of the Mediterranean Sea: patterns and dynamics of biodiversity.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Pansini M, Longo C (2003) A review of Mediterranean Sea sponge biogeography with, in appendix, a list of the demosponges hitherto recorded from this sea. Marine Biogeography of the Mediterranean Sea: patterns and dynamics of biodiversity. Biogeographia 24(1): 59–90.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref5"><issn>03734110</issn><journal_title>Boll Musei Istituti Biologici Dell Universita Genova</journal_title><author>Pansini</author><volume>41</volume><first_page>5</first_page><cYear>1973</cYear><article_title>Il coralligeno di Bogliasco e il suo popolamento di Poriferi.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Pansini M, Pronzato R (1973) Il coralligeno di Bogliasco e il suo popolamento di Poriferi. Bollettino dei Musei e degli Istituti Biologici dell'Università di Genova 41: 5–34.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref6"><journal_title>Bollettino dei Musei e degli Istituti di Biologia Università di Genova</journal_title><author>Pansini</author><volume>50</volume><first_page>287</first_page><cYear>1982</cYear><article_title>Distribuzione ed ecologia dei poriferi nella grotta di Mitigliano (penisola Sorrentina).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Pansini M., Pronzato R. (1982) Distribuzione ed ecologia dei poriferi nella grotta di Mitigliano (penisola Sorrentina). Bollettino dei Musei e degli Istituti di Biologia Università di Genova 50: 287–293.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref7"><issn>16971523</issn><journal_title>Tethys</journal_title><author>Pouliquen</author><volume>3</volume><issue>4</issue><first_page>715</first_page><cYear>1972</cYear><article_title>Les Spongiaires des grottes sous-marines de la région de Marseille. Ecologie et systématique.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Pouliquen L (1972) Les Spongiaires des grottes sous-marines de la région de Marseille. Ecologie et systématique. Tethys 3(4): 715–758.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref8"><journal_title>Bollettino dei Musei e degli Istituti di Biologia Università di Genova</journal_title><author>Pronzato</author><volume>43</volume><first_page>5</first_page><cYear>1975</cYear><article_title>Note tassonomiche sul genere Darwinella (Porifera).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Pronzato R (1975) Note tassonomiche sul genere Darwinella (Porifera). Bollettino dei Musei e degli Istituti di Biologia Università di Genova 43: 5–20.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref9"><journal_title>Biogeographia</journal_title><author>Pronzato</author><volume>24</volume><issue>1</issue><first_page>91</first_page><cYear>2003</cYear><article_title>Mediterranean sponge fauna: a biological, historical and cultural heritage, Marine Biogeography of the Mediterranean Sea: patterns and dynamics of biodiversity</article_title><unstructured_citation>Pronzato R (2003) Mediterranean sponge fauna: a biological, historical and cultural heritage, Marine Biogeography of the Mediterranean Sea: patterns and dynamics of biodiversity, Biogeographia 24(1): 91–99.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref9"><doi>10.1111/j.1439-0485.2008.00235.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref10"><issn>00074977</issn><journal_title>Bull Mar Sci</journal_title><author>Pronzato</author><volume>63</volume><issue>2</issue><first_page>317</first_page><cYear>1998</cYear><article_title>Morpho-functional adaptations of three species of Spongia (Porifera, Demospongiae) from a Mediterranean cliff.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Pronzato R, Bavestrello G, Cerrano C (1998) Morpho-functional adaptations of three species of Spongia (Porifera, Demospongiae) from a Mediterranean cliff. Bulletin of Marine Science 63(2): 317–328.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref11"><author>Pronzato</author><first_page>32</first_page><cYear>2012</cYear><volume_title>Endangered Species Habitat Protection and Ecological Significance</volume_title><article_title>Mediterranean horny sponges: how to drive a neverending story of exploitation toward a sustainable management and conservation.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Pronzato R, Ledda FD, Manconi R (2012) Mediterranean horny sponges: how to drive a neverending story of exploitation toward a sustainable management and conservation. In: Lucas-Borja ME (Ed.) Endangered Species: Habitat, Protection and Ecological Significance, pp. 32, Nova Science Publishers, Hauppauge, NY.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref11"><doi>10.1080/11250000309356538</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref12"><issn>0039081X</issn><journal_title>Pubbl Stn Zool Napoli</journal_title><author>Pulitzer-Finali</author><volume>40</volume><first_page>83</first_page><cYear>1976</cYear><article_title>Report on a collection of sponges from the Bay of Naples. II Keratosa.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Pulitzer-Finali G, Pronzato R (1976) Report on a collection of sponges from the Bay of Naples. II Keratosa. Pubblicazioni della Stazione Zoologica di Napoli 40: 83–104.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref12"><doi>10.1071/IS11044</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref12"><doi>10.1016/j.ympev.2010.03.034</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref13"><author>Riedl</author><cYear>1966</cYear><volume_title>Biologie der Meereshöhlen</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Riedl R (1966) Biologie der Meereshöhlen. Paul Parey, Hamburg.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref14"><journal_title>Serie Universitaria</journal_title><author>Rubió-Lois</author><volume>164</volume><first_page>54</first_page><cYear>1981</cYear><article_title>Contribución a la fauna de esponjas del litoral catalán. Esponjas corneas. Fundación Juan March</article_title><unstructured_citation>Rubió-Lois M, Uriz-Lespe M, Bibiloni-Rotger A (1981) Contribución a la fauna de esponjas del litoral catalán. Esponjas corneas. Fundación Juan March, Serie Universitaria 164: 54.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref15"><issn>00445231</issn><journal_title>Zool Anz</journal_title><author>Rützler</author><volume>176</volume><issue>5</issue><first_page>303</first_page><cYear>1966</cYear><article_title>Die Poriferen einer sorrentiner Höhle. Ergebnisse der Österreichischen Tyrrhenia-Expedition 1952.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Rützler K (1966) Die Poriferen einer sorrentiner Höhle. Ergebnisse der Österreichischen Tyrrhenia-Expedition 1952. Zoologischer Anzeiger 176(5): 303–319.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref16"><issn>16971523</issn><journal_title>Tethys</journal_title><author>Rützler</author><volume>7</volume><issue>2–3</issue><first_page>249</first_page><cYear>1976</cYear><article_title>Ecology of Tunisian commercial sponges.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Rützler K (1976) Ecology of Tunisian commercial sponges. Tethys 7(2–3): 249–264.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref17"><journal_title>Archivio Zoologico Italiano</journal_title><author>Sarà</author><volume>43</volume><first_page>203</first_page><cYear>1958</cYear><article_title>Studio sui Poriferi di una grotta di marea del Golfo di Napoli.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Sarà M (1958) Studio sui Poriferi di una grotta di marea del Golfo di Napoli. Archivio Zoologico Italiano 43: 203–280.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref18"><issn>0039081X</issn><journal_title>Pubbl Stn Zool Napoli</journal_title><author>Sarà</author><volume>31</volume><first_page>421</first_page><cYear>1960</cYear><article_title>Poriferi del litorale dell'Isola d'Ischia e loro ripartizione per ambienti.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Sarà M (1960a) Poriferi del litorale dell'Isola d'Ischia e loro ripartizione per ambienti. Pubblicazioni della Stazione Zoologica di Napoli 31: 421–472.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref19"><journal_title>Unione Zoologica Italiana</journal_title><author>Sarà</author><volume>27</volume><issue>1</issue><first_page>51</first_page><cYear>1960</cYear><article_title>Aspetti e problemi di una ricerca sinecologica sui Poriferi del golfo di Napoli.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Sarà M (1960b) Aspetti e problemi di una ricerca sinecologica sui Poriferi del golfo di Napoli. Unione Zoologica Italiana 27(1): 51–65.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><journal_title>Archivio Zoologico Italiano</journal_title><author>Sarà</author><volume>46</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1961</cYear><article_title>La fauna dei Poriferi delle grotte delle isole Tremiti. Studio ecologico e sistematico.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Sarà M (1961b) La fauna dei Poriferi delle grotte delle isole Tremiti. Studio ecologico e sistematico. Archivio Zoologico Italiano 46: 1–59.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref21"><journal_title>Chiara</journal_title><author>Sarà</author><volume>12</volume><first_page>191</first_page><cYear>1962</cYear><article_title>Distribuzione ed ecologia dei Poriferi in acque superficiali del Golfo di Policastro (Mar Tirreno). Annali del Pontificio Istituto Superiore di Scienze e Lettere S.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Sarà M (1962) Distribuzione ed ecologia dei Poriferi in acque superficiali del Golfo di Policastro (Mar Tirreno). Annali del Pontificio Istituto Superiore di Scienze e Lettere S. Chiara 12: 191–215.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref22"><journal_title>Archivio Zoologico Italiano</journal_title><author>Sarà</author><volume>49</volume><first_page>181</first_page><cYear>1964</cYear><article_title>Distribuzione ed ecologia dei Poriferi in acque superficiali della Riviera ligure di Levante.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Sarà M (1964a) Distribuzione ed ecologia dei Poriferi in acque superficiali della Riviera ligure di Levante. Archivio Zoologico Italiano 49: 181–248.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref23"><journal_title>Chiara Napoli</journal_title><author>Sarà</author><volume>14</volume><issue>2</issue><first_page>299</first_page><cYear>1964</cYear><article_title>Poriferi di acque superficiali (0–3 m) del litorale italiano. Annali del Pontificio Istituto Superiore di Scienze e Lettere di S.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Sarà M (1964b) Poriferi di acque superficiali (0–3 m) del litorale italiano. Annali del Pontificio Istituto Superiore di Scienze e Lettere di S. Chiara Napoli 14(2): 299–317.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref24"><author>Schmidt</author><cYear>1862</cYear><volume_title>Die Spongien des Adriatischen Meeres</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Schmidt O (1862) Die Spongien des Adriatischen Meeres. Wilhelm Engelman, Leipzig, 88pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref25"><author>Schmidt</author><cYear>1864</cYear><volume_title>Supplement der Spongien des Adriatischen Meeres Enthaltend die Histologie und systematische Ergänzungen</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Schmidt O (1864) Supplement der Spongien des Adriatischen Meeres. Enthaltend die Histologie und systematische Ergänzungen. Wilhelm Engelmann, Leipzig, 48 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref26"><author>Schmidt</author><cYear>1868</cYear><volume_title>Die Spongien der Küste von Algier Mit Nachträgen zu den Spongien des Adriatischen Meeres (Drittes Supplement)</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Schmidt O (1868) Die Spongien der Küste von Algier. Mit Nachträgen zu den Spongien des Adriatischen Meeres (Drittes Supplement). Wilhelm Engelmann, Leipzig, 44 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref27"><journal_title>Z Wiss Zool</journal_title><author>Schulze</author><volume>32</volume><first_page>117</first_page><cYear>1878</cYear><article_title>Untersuchungen über den Bau und die Entwicklung der Spongien. Sechste Mittheilung. Die Gattung Spongelia.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Schulze FE (1878) Untersuchungen über den Bau und die Entwicklung der Spongien. Sechste Mittheilung. Die Gattung Spongelia. Zeitschrift für wissenschaftliche Zoologie 32: 117–157, pls V-VIII.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref28"><journal_title>Z Wiss Zool</journal_title><author>Schulze</author><volume>32</volume><first_page>593</first_page><cYear>1879</cYear><article_title>Untersuchungen über den Bau und die Entwicklung der Spongien. Siebente Mittheilung. Die Familie der Spongidae.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Schulze FE (1879a) Untersuchungen über den Bau und die Entwicklung der Spongien. Siebente Mittheilung. Die Familie der Spongidae. Zeitschrift für wissenschaftliche Zoologie 32: 593–660.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><journal_title>Z Wiss Zool</journal_title><author>Schulze</author><volume>33</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1879</cYear><article_title>Untersuchungen über den Bau und die Entwicklung der Spongien. Achte Mitteilung. Die Gattung Hircinia Nardo und Oligoceras n. g.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Schulze FE (1879b) Untersuchungen über den Bau und die Entwicklung der Spongien. Achte Mitteilung. Die Gattung Hircinia Nardo und Oligoceras n. g. Zeitschrift für wissenschaftliche Zoologie 33: 1–38.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><unstructured_citation>Minchin EA (1900) Chapter III. Sponges. In: Lankester ER (Ed.) A Treatise on Zoology. Part II. The Porifera and Coelenterata. Adam &amp; Charles Black: London, 1–178 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><unstructured_citation>Nardo GD (1833) Auszug aus einem neuen System der Spongiarien, wonach bereits die Aufstellung in der Universitäts-Sammlung zu Paduagemacht ist. Isis, oder Encyclopädische Zeitung Coll. Oken: Jena, 519–523 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><unstructured_citation>Nardo GD (1834) De Spongiis. Isis, Coll. Oken: 714–716.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><unstructured_citation>Pansini M, Longo C (2008) Porifera. In: Relini G (Ed.) Checklist della Flora e della Fauna dei Mari Italiani (Parte I). Biologia Marina Mediterranea 15 suppl(1): 42–66.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><unstructured_citation>Pansini M., Manconi R, Pronzato R (Eds) (2011) Porifera I. Calcarea, Demospongiae (partim), Hexactinellida, Homoscleromorpha. Fauna d'Italia vol. 46, Calderini-Il Sole 24 Ore, Bologna, 554 pp. ISBN: 978–88–506–5395–9</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><unstructured_citation>Pansini M, Pronzato R, Fresi E, Cinelli F, Mazzella L, Ponticelli MP (1977) Evoluzione delle biocenosi bentoniche di substrato duro lungo un gradiente di luce in una grotta marina superficiale: Poriferi. In: Fresi E, Cinelli F (Eds) Atti IX Congresso Nazionale S.I.B.M., Lacco Ameno d'Ischia. La Seppia, Firenze, 315–330.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><unstructured_citation>Pronzato R, Manconi R (2011) Class Demospongiae. Orders Dendroceratida, Dictyoceratida, Verongida, Halisarcida. In: Pansini M, Manconi R, Pronzato R (Eds) Fauna d'Italia. Porifera I. Calcarea, Demospongiae (partim), Hexactinellida, Homoscleromorpha. vol. 46, p. 245–340, Calderini-Il Sole 24 Ore, Bologna.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><unstructured_citation>Pronzato R, Malva R, Manconi R (2004) The taxonomic status of Ircinia fasciculata, Ircinia felix, and Ircinia variabilis (Dictyoceratida, Irciniidae). In: Pansini M, Pronzato R, Bavestrello G, Manconi R (Eds) Sponge Science in the New Millennium. Bollettino dei Musei e degli Istituti di Biologia dell'Università di Genova 68: 553–563.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><unstructured_citation>Pulitzer-Finali G (1977) Report on a collection of sponges from the Bay of Naples. III. Hadromerida, Axinellida, Poecilosclerida, Halichondrida, Haplosclerida. Bollettino dei Musei e degli Istituti di Biologia dell'Università di Genova 44: 7–89.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><unstructured_citation>Pulitzer-Finali G, Pronzato R (1980) The Keratosa in a collection of Mediterranean sponges, mainly from the Italian coasts. Annali del Museo Civico di Storia naturale 'Giacomo Doria' di Genova 83: 123–158.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><unstructured_citation>Relini G, Giaccone G (Eds) (2009) Gli Habitat prioritari del Protocollo SPA/BIO (Convenzione di Barcellona) presenti in Italia. Schede descrittive per l'identificazione. Biologia Marina Mediterranea 16(1): 1–365.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><unstructured_citation>Relini G, Tunesi L (Eds) (2009) Le specie protette dal protocollo SPA/BIO (Convenzione di Barcellona) presenti in Italia. Schede descrittive per l'identificazione. Biologia Marina Mediterranea 16(2): 1–433.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><unstructured_citation>Sarà M (1959) Considerazioni sulla distribuzione ed ecologia dei Poriferi nelle grotte. Annuario dell'Istituto e Museo di Zoologia dell'Università di Napoli 11: 1–7.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><unstructured_citation>Sarà M (1961a) Zonazione dei Poriferi nella Grotta &quot;della Gaiola&quot;. Annuario dell'Istituto e Museo di Zoologia dell'Università di Napoli 13(1): 1–32.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><unstructured_citation>Sarà M (1968) Stratification des peuplements d'ésponges à recouvrement total dans certainens grottes du niveau superficiel. Rapports et procès-verbaux de la Commission internationale pour l'étude scientifique de la Mer Méditerranée 19(2): 83–85.</unstructured_citation></citation>
</citation_list>
</doi_citations>
</body>
</doi_batch>
