<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doi_batch version="4.3.0" xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/doi_resources_schema/4.3.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/doi_resources_schema/4.3.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/deposit/doi_resources4.3.0.xsd">
<head>
<doi_batch_id>1fe9c074-24ea-4574-8b2f-83ae7febaa2e</doi_batch_id>
<depositor>
<name>pens</name>
<email_address>bozhin.karaivanov@gmail.com</email_address>
</depositor>
</head>
<body>
<doi_citations>
<doi>10.3897/zookeys.281.4171</doi>
<citation_list>
	<citation key="ref1"><issn>13300520</issn><journal_title>Natura Croat</journal_title><author>Arko-Pjevac</author><volume>10</volume><issue>3</issue><first_page>163</first_page><cYear>2001</cYear><article_title>A submarine cave at the Island of KRK (North Adriatic Sea).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Arko-Pjevac M, Benac C, Kovacic M, Kirincic M (2001) A submarine cave at the Island of KRK (North Adriatic Sea). Natura Croatica 10(3): 163–184.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref2"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Bakran-Petricioli</author><volume>3172</volume><first_page>20</first_page><cYear>2012</cYear><article_title>How diverse is sponge fauna in the Adriatic Sea?</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bakran-Petricioli T, Radolovic M, Petricioli D (2012) How diverse is sponge fauna in the Adriatic Sea? Zootaxa 3172: 20–38.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref3"><journal_title>Bulletin de l Institut National Scientifique et Technique d Océanographie et de Pêche de Salammbô</journal_title><author>Ben Mustapha</author><volume>29</volume><first_page>23</first_page><cYear>2002</cYear><article_title>Tunisian megabenthos from infra (Posidonia meadows) and circalittoral (coralligenous) sites.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Ben Mustapha K, Komatsu K, Hattour A, Sammari C, Zarrouk S, Souissi A, El Abed A (2002) Tunisian megabenthos from infra (Posidonia meadows) and circalittoral (coralligenous) sites. Bulletin de l'Institut National Scientifique et Technique d'Océanographie et de Pêche de Salammbô 29: 23–36.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref4"><journal_title>Bulletin de l Institut National Scientifique et Technique d Océanographie et de Pêche de Salammbô</journal_title><author>Ben Mustapha</author><volume>30</volume><first_page>55</first_page><cYear>2003</cYear><article_title>Diversité des demosponges tunisiennes.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Ben Mustapha K, Zarrouk A, Souissi A, El Abed A (2003) Diversité des demosponges tunisiennes. Bulletin de l'Institut National Scientifique et Technique d'Océanographie et de Pêche de Salammbô 30: 55–78.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref5"><doi>10.1017/S0025315400039953</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref6"><doi>10.1080/03014223.1980.10423761</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref7"><issn>03014223</issn><journal_title>N Z J Zool</journal_title><author>Bergquist</author><volume>7</volume><issue>4</issue><first_page>443</first_page><cYear>1980</cYear><article_title>A revision of the supraspecific classification of the orders Dictyoceratida, Dendroceratida and Verongida (class Demospongiae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bergquist PR (1980b) A revision of the supraspecific classification of the orders Dictyoceratida, Dendroceratida and Verongida (class Demospongiae). New Zealand Journal of Zoology 7(4): 443–503.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref8"><journal_title>New Zealand Oceanographic Institute Memoir</journal_title><author>Bergquist</author><volume>107</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1996</cYear><article_title>The Marine Fauna of New Zealand: Porifera: Demospongiae. Part 5. Dendroceratida and Halisarca.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bergquist PR (1996) The Marine Fauna of New Zealand: Porifera: Demospongiae. Part 5. Dendroceratida and Halisarca. New Zealand Oceanographic Institute Memoir 107: 1–53.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref9"><author>Bibiloni</author><first_page>383</first_page><cYear>1984</cYear><volume_title>Els sistemes naturals de les Illes Medes</volume_title><article_title>Les esponges de les Illes Medes.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bibiloni A, Olivella I, Ros J (1984a) Les esponges de les Illes Medes. In: Ros J, Olivella I, Gili JM (Eds) Els sistemes naturals de les Illes Medes. Barcelona: Arxius de la Secciò de Ciéncies, 383–405.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref10"><doi>10.1111/j.1439-0485.1989.tb00076.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref11"><doi>10.1016/j.ympev.2004.02.021</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref12"><author>Borg</author><cYear>2004</cYear><volume_title>Report on a survey of the marine infralittoral benthic habitats in the Dwejra/Qawra area (Gozo Maltese Islands) Mosta</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Borg JA, Dimech M, Schembri PJ (2004) Report on a survey of the marine infralittoral benthic habitats in the Dwejra/Qawra area (Gozo, Maltese Islands). Mosta (Malta), Ecoserv 30 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref13"><issn>00079723</issn><journal_title>Cah Biol Mar</journal_title><author>Borojevic</author><volume>9</volume><issue>1</issue><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1968</cYear><article_title>Inventaire de la faune marine de Roscoff. Spongiaires.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Borojevic R, Cabioch, Lévi C (1968) Inventaire de la faune marine de Roscoff. Spongiaires. Cahiers de Biologie Marine 9(1): 1–44.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref14"><issn>02408759</issn><journal_title>Vie Milieu</journal_title><author>Boury-Esnault</author><volume>22</volume><issue>2</issue><first_page>287</first_page><cYear>1971</cYear><article_title>Spongiaires de la zone rocheuse littorale de Banyuls-sur-Mer. II. Systématique.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Boury-Esnault N (1971) Spongiaires de la zone rocheuse littorale de Banyuls-sur-Mer. II. Systématique. Vie Milieu 22(2): 287–349.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref15"><journal_title>Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society</journal_title><author>Bowerbank</author><volume>152</volume><issue>2</issue><first_page>1087</first_page><cYear>1862</cYear><article_title>On the Anatomy and Physiology of the Spongiadae. Part III. On the Generic Characters, the Specific Characters, and on the Method of Examination.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bowerbank JS (1862) On the Anatomy and Physiology of the Spongiadae. Part III. On the Generic Characters, the Specific Characters, and on the Method of Examination. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society 152(2): 1087–1135.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref16"><issn>01739565</issn><journal_title>Mar Ecol (Berl )</journal_title><author>Bussotti</author><volume>325</volume><first_page>109</first_page><cYear>2006</cYear><article_title>Spatial and temporal variability of sessile benthos in shallow Mediterranean marine cave.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bussotti S, Terlizzi A, Fraschetti S, Belmonte G, Boero F (2006) Spatial and temporal variability of sessile benthos in shallow Mediterranean marine cave. Marine Ecology 325: 109–119.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref17"><issn>00079723</issn><journal_title>Cah Biol Mar</journal_title><author>Cabioch</author><volume>9</volume><first_page>493</first_page><cYear>1968</cYear><article_title>Contribution à la connaissance des peuplement benthiques de la Manche Occidentale.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Cabioch L (1968) Contribution à la connaissance des peuplement benthiques de la Manche Occidentale. Cahiers de Biologie Marine 9: 493–720.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref18"><author>Cinelli</author><first_page>173</first_page><cYear>1977</cYear><volume_title>Biology of benthic organisms</volume_title><article_title>Distribution of benthic phyto- and zoo-coenoses along a light gradient in a superficial marine cave.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Cinelli F, Fresi E, Mazzella L, Pansini M, Pronzato R, Svoboda A (1977) Distribution of benthic phyto- and zoo-coenoses along a light gradient in a superficial marine cave. In: Keegan BF, O'Cèidigh P, Boaden PJS (Eds) Biology of benthic organisms, Pergamon Press, London, 173–183.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref19"><doi>10.1080/11250000409356578</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><doi>10.1046/j.1439-0485.2000.00655.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref21"><issn>05633745</issn><journal_title>Thalassia Salent</journal_title><author>Denitto</author><volume>32</volume><first_page>129</first_page><cYear>2010</cYear><article_title>Prima indagine faunistica della Grotta del Sifone (Canale d'Otranto, Salento Meridionale, Italia).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Denitto F, Bussotti S, Costantini A, Poto M, Onorato R, Belmonte G (2010) Prima indagine faunistica della Grotta del Sifone (Canale d'Otranto, Salento Meridionale, Italia). Thalassia Salentina 32: 129–138.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref22"><author>Desqueyroux-Faundez</author><cYear>1992</cYear><volume_title>O Schmidt sponge catalogue An illustrated guide to the Graz Museum Collection with notes on additional material</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Desqueyroux-Faundez R, Stone SM (1992) O. Schmidt sponge catalogue. An illustrated guide to the Graz Museum Collection, with notes on additional material. Museum d'Histoire Naturelle Genève 190 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref23"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Ereskovsky</author><volume>2768</volume><first_page>5</first_page><cYear>2011</cYear><article_title>Molecular and morphological description of a new species of Halisarca (Demospongiae: Halisarcida) from Mediterranean Sea and a redescription of the type species Halisarca dujardini.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Ereskovsky AV, Lavrov DV, Boury-Esnault N, Vacelet J (2011) Molecular and morphological description of a new species of Halisarca (Demospongiae: Halisarcida) from Mediterranean Sea and a redescription of the type species Halisarca dujardini. Zootaxa 2768: 5–31.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref24"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Erpenbeck</author><volume>1668</volume><first_page>107</first_page><cYear>2007</cYear><article_title>On the molecular phylogeny of sponges (Porifera).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Erpenbeck D, Wörheide G (2007) On the molecular phylogeny of sponges (Porifera). Zootaxa 1668: 107–126.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref25"><doi>10.1016/j.ympev.2012.02.024</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref26"><journal_title>Annales Series Historia Naturalis</journal_title><author>Faresi</author><volume>16</volume><first_page>9</first_page><cYear>2006</cYear><article_title>Benthic macrofauna of a submarine cave on the Istrian Peninsula (Croatia).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Faresi L, Bettoso N, Aleffi IF (2006) Benthic macrofauna of a submarine cave on the Istrian Peninsula (Croatia). Annales Series Historia Naturalis 16: 9–16.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref27"><journal_title>Animal Biology</journal_title><author>Gaino</author><volume>4</volume><first_page>31</first_page><cYear>1995</cYear><article_title>Organizational plasticity as a successful conservative tactics in sponges.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gaino E, Manconi R, Pronzato R (1995) Organizational plasticity as a successful conservative tactics in sponges. Animal Biology 4: 31–43.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref28"><doi>10.1371/journal.pone.0039873</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><author>Grant</author><cYear>1861</cYear><volume_title>Tabular view of the primary divisions of the Animal Kingdom</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Grant RE (1861) Tabular view of the primary divisions of the Animal Kingdom. London, 91 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><journal_title>Scientific Reports of the Port-Cros Natural Park</journal_title><author>Harmelin</author><volume>19</volume><first_page>117</first_page><cYear>2003</cYear><article_title>Peuplement de la grotte sous-marine de l'Ile de Bagaud (Parc National de Port-Cros, France, Méditerranée).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Harmelin JG, Boury-Esnault N, Fichez R, Vacelet J, Zibrowius H (2003) Peuplement de la grotte sous-marine de l'Ile de Bagaud (Parc National de Port-Cros, France, Méditerranée). Scientific Reports of the Port-Cros Natural Park 19:117–134.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><doi>10.1007/978-1-4615-0747-5</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref32"><journal_title>Chiara</journal_title><author>Labate</author><volume>14</volume><first_page>319</first_page><cYear>1964</cYear><article_title>Poriferi di grotta superficiale del litorale adriatico pugliese. Annali dell'Istituto Superiore di Scienze e Lettere S.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Labate M (1964) Poriferi di grotta superficiale del litorale adriatico pugliese. Annali dell'Istituto Superiore di Scienze e Lettere S. Chiara 14: 319–342.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><issn>11250003</issn><journal_title>Ital J Zool (Modena)</journal_title><author>Labate</author><volume>32</volume><issue>1</issue><first_page>541</first_page><cYear>1965</cYear><article_title>Ecologia dei Poriferi della Grotta della Regina.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Labate M (1965) Ecologia dei Poriferi della Grotta della Regina. Italian Journal of Zoology 32(1): 541–553.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref34"><journal_title>Bulletin de l Institut Océanographique de Monaco</journal_title><author>Laborel</author><volume>55</volume><issue>1120</issue><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1958</cYear><article_title>Etude des peuplements d'une grotte sous-marine du Golfe de Marseille.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Laborel J, Vacelet J (1958) Etude des peuplements d'une grotte sous-marine du Golfe de Marseille. Bulletin de l'Institut Océanographique de Monaco 55(1120): 1–20.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref35"><doi>10.1016/j.ympev.2008.05.014</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref36"><cYear>1759</cYear><volume_title>Systema naturae per regna tria naturæ secundum classes ordines genera species cum characteribus differentiis synonymis locis Tomus II Editio decima reformata</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Linnaeus (Linnaei) C (1759) Systema naturae per regna tria naturæ, secundum classes, ordines, genera, species, cum characteribus, differentiis, synonymis, locis. Tomus II. Editio decima, reformata, 1348 pp. Holmiae, Laurentii Salvii.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref37"><journal_title>Biologia Marina Mediterranea</journal_title><author>Manconi</author><volume>18</volume><issue>1</issue><first_page>258</first_page><cYear>2011</cYear><article_title>Biodiversity of Sardinian marine caves: sponge fauna.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Manconi R, Cadeddu B, Pansini M, Pronzato R, Ledda FD (2011) Biodiversity of Sardinian marine caves: sponge fauna. Biologia Marina Mediterranea 18(1): 258–259.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref38"><author>Von Martens</author><cYear>1824</cYear><volume_title>Reise nach Venedig</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Martens GM Von (1824) Reise nach Venedig. 2 Volumes.(Stettinschen Buchhandlung: Ulm).</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref39"><doi>10.1017/S0025315404009567h</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref40"><journal_title>Giacomo Doria</journal_title><author>Melone</author><volume>75</volume><first_page>344</first_page><cYear>1965</cYear><article_title>I Poriferi associati a Corallium rubrum (L.) della Sardegna. Annali del Museo Civico di Storia Naturale</article_title><unstructured_citation>Melone N (1965) I Poriferi associati a Corallium rubrum (L.) della Sardegna. Annali del Museo Civico di Storia Naturale &quot;Giacomo Doria&quot; 75: 344–358.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref41"><unstructured_citation>Balduzzi A, Bianchi CN, Boero F, Cattaneo-Vietti R, Pansini M, Sarà M (1989) The suspension – feeder communities of a Mediterranean sea cave. In: Ros JD (Ed.) Topics in marine biology. Scientia Marina 53(2–3): 387–395.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref42"><unstructured_citation>Barrois C (1876) Mémoire sur l'embryologie de quelques Eponges de la Manche. Annales des Sciences Naturelles (6) 3(11): 1–84.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref43"><unstructured_citation>Bergquist PR, Cook S De C (2002a) Order Dendroceratida Minchin, 1900. In: Hooper JNA and Van Soest RWM (Eds) Systema Porifera: a guide to the classification of Sponges, Vol. I, New York, NY (USA), Kluwer Academic/Plenum Publishers, 1067–1076.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref44"><unstructured_citation>Bergquist PR, Cook S De C (2002b) Order Halisarcida Bergquist, 1996. In: Hooper JNA, Van Soest RWM (Eds) Systema Porifera: a guide to the classification of Sponges. Vol. I, New York, NY (USA), Kluwer Academic/Plenum Publishers, 1077–1080.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref45"><unstructured_citation>Bergquist PR, Cook S De C (2002c) Order Verongida Bergquist, 1978. In: Hooper JNA, Van Soest RWM (Eds) Systema Porifera: a guide to the classification of Sponges. Vol. I, New York, NY (USA), Kluwer Academic/Plenum Publishers, 1081–196.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref46"><unstructured_citation>Bianchi CN, Morri C (1994) Studio bionomico comparativo di alcune grotte sommerse: definizione di una scala di confinamento. Memorie dell'Istituto Italiano di Biospeolologia 6: 107–123.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Bianchi CN, Cevasco MG, Diviacco G, Morri C (1986) Primi risultati di una ricerca ecologica sulla grotta marina di Bergeggi (Savona). Bollettino dei Musei e degli Istituti di Biologia dell'Università di Genova 52: 267–293.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref48"><unstructured_citation>Bibiloni MA, Gili JM, Ros J (1984b) Les coves submarines de les Illes Mèdes. In: Ros J, Aragonès J, Olivella I, Prats I, Gili JM, Sardà JM (Eds) Els Sistemes Naturals de les Illes Mèdes. Instituciò Catalana d'Història Natural i Societat Catalana de Biologia, 708–735.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref49"><unstructured_citation>Cadeddu B (2012) Biodiversity assessment in Mediterranean caves: the case of Porifera as model taxon. PhD Thesis, Sassari: University of Sassari (Italy).</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref50"><unstructured_citation>Carter HJ (1876) Descriptions and figures of deep-sea sponges and their spicules, from the Atlantic Ocean, dredged up on board H.M.S.'Porcupine', chiefly in 1869 (concluded). Annals and Magazine of Natural History (4) 18(105): 226–240; (106): 307–324; (107): 388–410; (108): 458–479.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref51"><unstructured_citation>Cook S De C, Bergquist PR (2002) Order Dictyoceratida Minchin, 1900. In: Hooper JNA, Van Soest RWM (Eds), Systema Porifera: a guide to the classification of Sponges, Vol. I, New York, NY (USA), Kluwer Academic/Plenum Publishers, 1021–1066.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref52"><unstructured_citation>Erpenbeck D, Hendriks P, Strickland C, Ekins M, Schlacher-Hoenlinger MA, Degnan BM, Hooper JNA, Wörheide G (2007) Molecular and Biochemical Systematics of Keratose Sponges. ManaproXII International Symposium on Marine Natural Products. Conference Programme &amp; Proceedings, ISBN 978–0–473–11940–9, p 152.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref53"><unstructured_citation>Johnston G (1842) A History of British Sponges and Lithophytes.(W.H. Lizars: Edinburgh): i-xii, 1–264, pls I-XXV.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref54"><unstructured_citation>Lamarck JBP De Monet Comte De (1813–1814) Sur les polypiers empâtés. Suite du mémoire intitulé: Sur les Polypiers empâtés. Suite des éponges. Annales du Muséum national d'histoire naturelle, Paris 20 (6): 294–312 (published 1813), 370–386, 432–458 (published 1814).</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref55"><unstructured_citation>Laubenfels MW de (1948) The order Keratosa of the phylum Porifera. A monographic study. Allan Hancock Foundation Occasional Paper 3: 1–217.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref56"><unstructured_citation>Linnaeus (Linné) C (1789) Systema Naturae, per regna tria naturæ, secundum classes, ordines, genera, species cum characteribus, differentiis, synonymis, locis. Tomus I, Pars VI. Editio decima tertia aucta, reformata, 3817–3826 pp. Cura JF Gmelin, apud Deamolliere JB, Lugdini.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref57"><journal_title>Memoirs of the Wernerian Natural History Society</journal_title><author>Montagu</author><volume>2</volume><issue>1</issue><first_page>67</first_page><cYear>1818</cYear><article_title>An Essay on Sponges, with Descriptions of all the species that have been discovered on the Coast of Great Britain.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Montagu G (1818) An Essay on Sponges, with Descriptions of all the species that have been discovered on the Coast of Great Britain. Memoirs of the Wernerian Natural History Society 2(1): 67–122, pls III–XVI.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref58"><issn>13300520</issn><journal_title>Natura Croat</journal_title><author>Novosel</author><volume>11</volume><first_page>387</first_page><cYear>2002</cYear><article_title>The benthos of the northern part of the Velebit Channel (Adriatic Sea, Croatia).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Novosel M, Bakran-Petricioli T, Požar-Domac A, Kružić P, Radić I (2002) The benthos of the northern part of the Velebit Channel (Adriatic Sea, Croatia). Natura Croatica 11: 387–409.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref59"><doi>10.5962/bhl.title.6595</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref60"><journal_title>Bulletin de l Institut Océanographique de Monaco</journal_title><author>Pansini</author><volume>9</volume><first_page>43</first_page><cYear>1992</cYear><article_title>Considérations biogéographiques et systématiques pour une mise à jour des données sur le peuplement de spongiaires méditerranéens.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Pansini M (1992) Considérations biogéographiques et systématiques pour une mise à jour des données sur le peuplement de spongiaires méditerranéens. Bulletin de l'Institut Océanographique de Monaco 9: 43–51.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref61"><journal_title>Biogeographia</journal_title><author>Pansini</author><volume>24</volume><issue>1</issue><first_page>59</first_page><cYear>2003</cYear><article_title>A review of Mediterranean Sea sponge biogeography with, in appendix, a list of the demosponges hitherto recorded from this sea. Marine Biogeography of the Mediterranean Sea: patterns and dynamics of biodiversity.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Pansini M, Longo C (2003) A review of Mediterranean Sea sponge biogeography with, in appendix, a list of the demosponges hitherto recorded from this sea. Marine Biogeography of the Mediterranean Sea: patterns and dynamics of biodiversity. Biogeographia 24(1): 59–90.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref62"><issn>03734110</issn><journal_title>Boll Musei Istituti Biologici Dell Universita Genova</journal_title><author>Pansini</author><volume>41</volume><first_page>5</first_page><cYear>1973</cYear><article_title>Il coralligeno di Bogliasco e il suo popolamento di Poriferi.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Pansini M, Pronzato R (1973) Il coralligeno di Bogliasco e il suo popolamento di Poriferi. Bollettino dei Musei e degli Istituti Biologici dell'Università di Genova 41: 5–34.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref63"><journal_title>Bollettino dei Musei e degli Istituti di Biologia Università di Genova</journal_title><author>Pansini</author><volume>50</volume><first_page>287</first_page><cYear>1982</cYear><article_title>Distribuzione ed ecologia dei poriferi nella grotta di Mitigliano (penisola Sorrentina).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Pansini M., Pronzato R. (1982) Distribuzione ed ecologia dei poriferi nella grotta di Mitigliano (penisola Sorrentina). Bollettino dei Musei e degli Istituti di Biologia Università di Genova 50: 287–293.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref64"><issn>16971523</issn><journal_title>Tethys</journal_title><author>Pouliquen</author><volume>3</volume><issue>4</issue><first_page>715</first_page><cYear>1972</cYear><article_title>Les Spongiaires des grottes sous-marines de la région de Marseille. Ecologie et systématique.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Pouliquen L (1972) Les Spongiaires des grottes sous-marines de la région de Marseille. Ecologie et systématique. Tethys 3(4): 715–758.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref65"><journal_title>Bollettino dei Musei e degli Istituti di Biologia Università di Genova</journal_title><author>Pronzato</author><volume>43</volume><first_page>5</first_page><cYear>1975</cYear><article_title>Note tassonomiche sul genere Darwinella (Porifera).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Pronzato R (1975) Note tassonomiche sul genere Darwinella (Porifera). Bollettino dei Musei e degli Istituti di Biologia Università di Genova 43: 5–20.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref66"><journal_title>Biogeographia</journal_title><author>Pronzato</author><volume>24</volume><issue>1</issue><first_page>91</first_page><cYear>2003</cYear><article_title>Mediterranean sponge fauna: a biological, historical and cultural heritage, Marine Biogeography of the Mediterranean Sea: patterns and dynamics of biodiversity</article_title><unstructured_citation>Pronzato R (2003) Mediterranean sponge fauna: a biological, historical and cultural heritage, Marine Biogeography of the Mediterranean Sea: patterns and dynamics of biodiversity, Biogeographia 24(1): 91–99.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref67"><doi>10.1111/j.1439-0485.2008.00235.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref68"><issn>00074977</issn><journal_title>Bull Mar Sci</journal_title><author>Pronzato</author><volume>63</volume><issue>2</issue><first_page>317</first_page><cYear>1998</cYear><article_title>Morpho-functional adaptations of three species of Spongia (Porifera, Demospongiae) from a Mediterranean cliff.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Pronzato R, Bavestrello G, Cerrano C (1998) Morpho-functional adaptations of three species of Spongia (Porifera, Demospongiae) from a Mediterranean cliff. Bulletin of Marine Science 63(2): 317–328.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref69"><author>Pronzato</author><first_page>32</first_page><cYear>2012</cYear><volume_title>Endangered Species Habitat Protection and Ecological Significance</volume_title><article_title>Mediterranean horny sponges: how to drive a neverending story of exploitation toward a sustainable management and conservation.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Pronzato R, Ledda FD, Manconi R (2012) Mediterranean horny sponges: how to drive a neverending story of exploitation toward a sustainable management and conservation. In: Lucas-Borja ME (Ed.) Endangered Species: Habitat, Protection and Ecological Significance, pp. 32, Nova Science Publishers, Hauppauge, NY.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref70"><doi>10.1080/11250000309356538</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref71"><issn>0039081X</issn><journal_title>Pubbl Stn Zool Napoli</journal_title><author>Pulitzer-Finali</author><volume>40</volume><first_page>83</first_page><cYear>1976</cYear><article_title>Report on a collection of sponges from the Bay of Naples. II Keratosa.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Pulitzer-Finali G, Pronzato R (1976) Report on a collection of sponges from the Bay of Naples. II Keratosa. Pubblicazioni della Stazione Zoologica di Napoli 40: 83–104.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref72"><doi>10.1071/IS11044</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref73"><doi>10.1016/j.ympev.2010.03.034</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref74"><author>Riedl</author><cYear>1966</cYear><volume_title>Biologie der Meereshöhlen</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Riedl R (1966) Biologie der Meereshöhlen. Paul Parey, Hamburg.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref75"><journal_title>Serie Universitaria</journal_title><author>Rubió-Lois</author><volume>164</volume><first_page>54</first_page><cYear>1981</cYear><article_title>Contribución a la fauna de esponjas del litoral catalán. Esponjas corneas. Fundación Juan March</article_title><unstructured_citation>Rubió-Lois M, Uriz-Lespe M, Bibiloni-Rotger A (1981) Contribución a la fauna de esponjas del litoral catalán. Esponjas corneas. Fundación Juan March, Serie Universitaria 164: 54.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref76"><issn>00445231</issn><journal_title>Zool Anz</journal_title><author>Rützler</author><volume>176</volume><issue>5</issue><first_page>303</first_page><cYear>1966</cYear><article_title>Die Poriferen einer sorrentiner Höhle. Ergebnisse der Österreichischen Tyrrhenia-Expedition 1952.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Rützler K (1966) Die Poriferen einer sorrentiner Höhle. Ergebnisse der Österreichischen Tyrrhenia-Expedition 1952. Zoologischer Anzeiger 176(5): 303–319.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref77"><issn>16971523</issn><journal_title>Tethys</journal_title><author>Rützler</author><volume>7</volume><issue>2–3</issue><first_page>249</first_page><cYear>1976</cYear><article_title>Ecology of Tunisian commercial sponges.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Rützler K (1976) Ecology of Tunisian commercial sponges. Tethys 7(2–3): 249–264.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref78"><journal_title>Archivio Zoologico Italiano</journal_title><author>Sarà</author><volume>43</volume><first_page>203</first_page><cYear>1958</cYear><article_title>Studio sui Poriferi di una grotta di marea del Golfo di Napoli.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Sarà M (1958) Studio sui Poriferi di una grotta di marea del Golfo di Napoli. Archivio Zoologico Italiano 43: 203–280.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref79"><issn>0039081X</issn><journal_title>Pubbl Stn Zool Napoli</journal_title><author>Sarà</author><volume>31</volume><first_page>421</first_page><cYear>1960</cYear><article_title>Poriferi del litorale dell'Isola d'Ischia e loro ripartizione per ambienti.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Sarà M (1960a) Poriferi del litorale dell'Isola d'Ischia e loro ripartizione per ambienti. Pubblicazioni della Stazione Zoologica di Napoli 31: 421–472.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref80"><journal_title>Unione Zoologica Italiana</journal_title><author>Sarà</author><volume>27</volume><issue>1</issue><first_page>51</first_page><cYear>1960</cYear><article_title>Aspetti e problemi di una ricerca sinecologica sui Poriferi del golfo di Napoli.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Sarà M (1960b) Aspetti e problemi di una ricerca sinecologica sui Poriferi del golfo di Napoli. Unione Zoologica Italiana 27(1): 51–65.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref81"><journal_title>Archivio Zoologico Italiano</journal_title><author>Sarà</author><volume>46</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1961</cYear><article_title>La fauna dei Poriferi delle grotte delle isole Tremiti. Studio ecologico e sistematico.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Sarà M (1961b) La fauna dei Poriferi delle grotte delle isole Tremiti. Studio ecologico e sistematico. Archivio Zoologico Italiano 46: 1–59.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref82"><journal_title>Chiara</journal_title><author>Sarà</author><volume>12</volume><first_page>191</first_page><cYear>1962</cYear><article_title>Distribuzione ed ecologia dei Poriferi in acque superficiali del Golfo di Policastro (Mar Tirreno). Annali del Pontificio Istituto Superiore di Scienze e Lettere S.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Sarà M (1962) Distribuzione ed ecologia dei Poriferi in acque superficiali del Golfo di Policastro (Mar Tirreno). Annali del Pontificio Istituto Superiore di Scienze e Lettere S. Chiara 12: 191–215.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref83"><journal_title>Archivio Zoologico Italiano</journal_title><author>Sarà</author><volume>49</volume><first_page>181</first_page><cYear>1964</cYear><article_title>Distribuzione ed ecologia dei Poriferi in acque superficiali della Riviera ligure di Levante.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Sarà M (1964a) Distribuzione ed ecologia dei Poriferi in acque superficiali della Riviera ligure di Levante. Archivio Zoologico Italiano 49: 181–248.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref84"><journal_title>Chiara Napoli</journal_title><author>Sarà</author><volume>14</volume><issue>2</issue><first_page>299</first_page><cYear>1964</cYear><article_title>Poriferi di acque superficiali (0–3 m) del litorale italiano. Annali del Pontificio Istituto Superiore di Scienze e Lettere di S.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Sarà M (1964b) Poriferi di acque superficiali (0–3 m) del litorale italiano. Annali del Pontificio Istituto Superiore di Scienze e Lettere di S. Chiara Napoli 14(2): 299–317.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref85"><author>Schmidt</author><cYear>1862</cYear><volume_title>Die Spongien des Adriatischen Meeres</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Schmidt O (1862) Die Spongien des Adriatischen Meeres. Wilhelm Engelman, Leipzig, 88pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref86"><author>Schmidt</author><cYear>1864</cYear><volume_title>Supplement der Spongien des Adriatischen Meeres Enthaltend die Histologie und systematische Ergänzungen</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Schmidt O (1864) Supplement der Spongien des Adriatischen Meeres. Enthaltend die Histologie und systematische Ergänzungen. Wilhelm Engelmann, Leipzig, 48 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref87"><author>Schmidt</author><cYear>1868</cYear><volume_title>Die Spongien der Küste von Algier Mit Nachträgen zu den Spongien des Adriatischen Meeres (Drittes Supplement)</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Schmidt O (1868) Die Spongien der Küste von Algier. Mit Nachträgen zu den Spongien des Adriatischen Meeres (Drittes Supplement). Wilhelm Engelmann, Leipzig, 44 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref88"><journal_title>Z Wiss Zool</journal_title><author>Schulze</author><volume>32</volume><first_page>117</first_page><cYear>1878</cYear><article_title>Untersuchungen über den Bau und die Entwicklung der Spongien. Sechste Mittheilung. Die Gattung Spongelia.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Schulze FE (1878) Untersuchungen über den Bau und die Entwicklung der Spongien. Sechste Mittheilung. Die Gattung Spongelia. Zeitschrift für wissenschaftliche Zoologie 32: 117–157, pls V-VIII.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref89"><journal_title>Z Wiss Zool</journal_title><author>Schulze</author><volume>32</volume><first_page>593</first_page><cYear>1879</cYear><article_title>Untersuchungen über den Bau und die Entwicklung der Spongien. Siebente Mittheilung. Die Familie der Spongidae.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Schulze FE (1879a) Untersuchungen über den Bau und die Entwicklung der Spongien. Siebente Mittheilung. Die Familie der Spongidae. Zeitschrift für wissenschaftliche Zoologie 32: 593–660.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref90"><journal_title>Z Wiss Zool</journal_title><author>Schulze</author><volume>33</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1879</cYear><article_title>Untersuchungen über den Bau und die Entwicklung der Spongien. Achte Mitteilung. Die Gattung Hircinia Nardo und Oligoceras n. g.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Schulze FE (1879b) Untersuchungen über den Bau und die Entwicklung der Spongien. Achte Mitteilung. Die Gattung Hircinia Nardo und Oligoceras n. g. Zeitschrift für wissenschaftliche Zoologie 33: 1–38.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref91"><unstructured_citation>Minchin EA (1900) Chapter III. Sponges. In: Lankester ER (Ed.) A Treatise on Zoology. Part II. The Porifera and Coelenterata. Adam &amp; Charles Black: London, 1–178 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref92"><unstructured_citation>Nardo GD (1833) Auszug aus einem neuen System der Spongiarien, wonach bereits die Aufstellung in der Universitäts-Sammlung zu Paduagemacht ist. Isis, oder Encyclopädische Zeitung Coll. Oken: Jena, 519–523 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref93"><unstructured_citation>Nardo GD (1834) De Spongiis. Isis, Coll. Oken: 714–716.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref94"><unstructured_citation>Pansini M, Longo C (2008) Porifera. In: Relini G (Ed.) Checklist della Flora e della Fauna dei Mari Italiani (Parte I). Biologia Marina Mediterranea 15 suppl(1): 42–66.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref95"><unstructured_citation>Pansini M., Manconi R, Pronzato R (Eds) (2011) Porifera I. Calcarea, Demospongiae (partim), Hexactinellida, Homoscleromorpha. Fauna d'Italia vol. 46, Calderini-Il Sole 24 Ore, Bologna, 554 pp. ISBN: 978–88–506–5395–9</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref96"><unstructured_citation>Pansini M, Pronzato R, Fresi E, Cinelli F, Mazzella L, Ponticelli MP (1977) Evoluzione delle biocenosi bentoniche di substrato duro lungo un gradiente di luce in una grotta marina superficiale: Poriferi. In: Fresi E, Cinelli F (Eds) Atti IX Congresso Nazionale S.I.B.M., Lacco Ameno d'Ischia. La Seppia, Firenze, 315–330.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref97"><unstructured_citation>Pronzato R, Manconi R (2011) Class Demospongiae. Orders Dendroceratida, Dictyoceratida, Verongida, Halisarcida. In: Pansini M, Manconi R, Pronzato R (Eds) Fauna d'Italia. Porifera I. Calcarea, Demospongiae (partim), Hexactinellida, Homoscleromorpha. vol. 46, p. 245–340, Calderini-Il Sole 24 Ore, Bologna.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref98"><unstructured_citation>Pronzato R, Malva R, Manconi R (2004) The taxonomic status of Ircinia fasciculata, Ircinia felix, and Ircinia variabilis (Dictyoceratida, Irciniidae). In: Pansini M, Pronzato R, Bavestrello G, Manconi R (Eds) Sponge Science in the New Millennium. Bollettino dei Musei e degli Istituti di Biologia dell'Università di Genova 68: 553–563.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref99"><unstructured_citation>Pulitzer-Finali G (1977) Report on a collection of sponges from the Bay of Naples. III. Hadromerida, Axinellida, Poecilosclerida, Halichondrida, Haplosclerida. Bollettino dei Musei e degli Istituti di Biologia dell'Università di Genova 44: 7–89.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref100"><unstructured_citation>Pulitzer-Finali G, Pronzato R (1980) The Keratosa in a collection of Mediterranean sponges, mainly from the Italian coasts. Annali del Museo Civico di Storia naturale 'Giacomo Doria' di Genova 83: 123–158.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref101"><unstructured_citation>Relini G, Giaccone G (Eds) (2009) Gli Habitat prioritari del Protocollo SPA/BIO (Convenzione di Barcellona) presenti in Italia. Schede descrittive per l'identificazione. Biologia Marina Mediterranea 16(1): 1–365.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref102"><unstructured_citation>Relini G, Tunesi L (Eds) (2009) Le specie protette dal protocollo SPA/BIO (Convenzione di Barcellona) presenti in Italia. Schede descrittive per l'identificazione. Biologia Marina Mediterranea 16(2): 1–433.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref103"><unstructured_citation>Sarà M (1959) Considerazioni sulla distribuzione ed ecologia dei Poriferi nelle grotte. Annuario dell'Istituto e Museo di Zoologia dell'Università di Napoli 11: 1–7.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref104"><unstructured_citation>Sarà M (1961a) Zonazione dei Poriferi nella Grotta &quot;della Gaiola&quot;. Annuario dell'Istituto e Museo di Zoologia dell'Università di Napoli 13(1): 1–32.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref105"><unstructured_citation>Sarà M (1968) Stratification des peuplements d'ésponges à recouvrement total dans certainens grottes du niveau superficiel. Rapports et procès-verbaux de la Commission internationale pour l'étude scientifique de la Mer Méditerranée 19(2): 83–85.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref106"><author>Sowerby</author><cYear>1806</cYear><volume_title>British Miscellany or coloured figures of new rare or little known animal subjects not before ascertained to be inhabitants of the British Isles</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Sowerby J (1806) British Miscellany, or coloured figures of new rare or little known animal subjects, not before ascertained to be inhabitants of the British Isles. Taylor &amp; Co., London, 2 Vols: 660 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref107"><journal_title>Mémoires de la Société Zoologique de France</journal_title><author>Topsent</author><volume>9</volume><first_page>113</first_page><cYear>1896</cYear><article_title>Matériaux pour servir à l'étude de la faune des spongiaires de France.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Topsent E (1896) Matériaux pour servir à l'étude de la faune des spongiaires de France. Mémoires de la Société Zoologique de France 9: 113–133.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref108"><journal_title>Archives de Zoologie Expérimentale et Generale</journal_title><author>Topsent</author><volume>63</volume><issue>5</issue><first_page>623</first_page><cYear>1925</cYear><article_title>Etude des Spongiaires du Golfe de Naples.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Topsent E (1925) Etude des Spongiaires du Golfe de Naples. Archives de Zoologie Expérimentale et Generale 63(5): 623–725.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref109"><journal_title>Bulletin de l Institut Océanographique de Monaco</journal_title><author>Topsent</author><volume>537</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1929</cYear><article_title>Spongionella Bow. et Cacospongia Schm.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Topsent E (1929) Spongionella Bow. et Cacospongia Schm. Bulletin de l'Institut Océanographique de Monaco 537: 1–14.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref110"><journal_title>Atti Associazione Italiana di Oceanologia e Limnologia</journal_title><author>Tunesi</author><volume>19</volume><first_page>489</first_page><cYear>2008</cYear><article_title>Marine protected species and habitats of conservation interest in the Gallinaria Island (Ligurian Sea): a study for the establishment of the marine protected area.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Tunesi L, Agnesi S, Di Nora T, Molinari A, Mo G (2008) Marine protected species and habitats of conservation interest in the Gallinaria Island (Ligurian Sea): a study for the establishment of the marine protected area. Atti Associazione Italiana di Oceanologia e Limnologia 19: 489–497.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref111"><doi>10.3989/scimar.2009.73n2387</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref112"><issn>12809551</issn><journal_title>Zoosystema</journal_title><author>Uriz</author><volume>22</volume><issue>2</issue><first_page>401</first_page><cYear>2000</cYear><article_title>The genus Acanthodendrilla in the Mediterranean Sea with description of a new species.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Uriz JM, Maldonado M (2000) The genus Acanthodendrilla in the Mediterranean Sea with description of a new species. Zoosystema 22(2): 401–410.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref113"><doi>10.1111/j.1439-0485.1992.tb00343.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref114"><journal_title>Recueil des Travaux de la Station Marine d Endoume Marseille</journal_title><author>Vacelet</author><volume>26</volume><issue>16</issue><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1959</cYear><article_title>Répartition générale des éponges et systématique des éponges cornées de la région de Marseille et de quelque station Méditerranée.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Vacelet J (1959) Répartition générale des éponges et systématique des éponges cornées de la région de Marseille et de quelque station Méditerranée. Recueil des Travaux de la Station Marine d'Endoume, Marseille 26(16): 1–101.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref115"><journal_title>Recueil des Travaux de la Station Marine d Endoume Marseille</journal_title><author>Vacelet</author><volume>22</volume><first_page>21</first_page><cYear>1961</cYear><article_title>Spongiaires (Démosponges) de la région de Bonifacio (Corse).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Vacelet J (1961b) Spongiaires (Démosponges) de la région de Bonifacio (Corse). Recueil des Travaux de la Station Marine d'Endoume Marseille 22: 21–45.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref116"><journal_title>Memoires du Museum National d Histoire Naturelle</journal_title><author>Vacelet</author><volume>59</volume><first_page>146</first_page><cYear>1969</cYear><article_title>Eponges de la roche du large et de l'etage bathyal de Mediterranee.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Vacelet J (1969) Eponges de la roche du large et de l'etage bathyal de Mediterranee. Memoires du Museum National d'Histoire Naturelle, 59: 146–219.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref117"><journal_title>Travaux Scientifique Parc National de Port-Cros</journal_title><author>Vacelet</author><volume>2</volume><first_page>167</first_page><cYear>1976</cYear><article_title>Inventaire des Spongiaires du Parc National de Port-Cros (Var).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Vacelet J (1976) Inventaire des Spongiaires du Parc National de Port-Cros (Var). Travaux Scientifique Parc National de Port-Cros 2: 167–186.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref118"><doi>10.1017/S0025315407060687</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref119"><author>Van Soest</author><volume>213</volume><cYear>1994</cYear><volume_title>Sponges in Time and Space</volume_title><article_title>Demosponge distribution patterns.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Van Soest RW (1994) Demosponge distribution patterns. In: Van Soest RMW, Van Kempen TMB, Braekman JC (Eds) Sponges in Time and Space. Balkema, Rotterdam 213–223pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref120"><doi>10.1371/journal.pone.0035105</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref121"><author>von Lendenfeld</author><cYear>1889</cYear><volume_title>A Monograph of Horny Sponges</volume_title><unstructured_citation>von Lendenfeld R (1889) A Monograph of Horny Sponges. Trübner, Ludgate Hill, London, 936 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref122"><doi>10.1080/11250000509356653</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref123"><doi>10.1002/mmnz.19930690105</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref124"><doi>10.1111/j.1463-6409.1991.tb00284.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref125"><doi>10.1007/s10750-011-0880-4</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref126"><unstructured_citation>Topsent E (1892) Diagnoses d'éponges nouvelles de la Méditerranée et plus particulièrement de Banyuls. Archives de Zoologie expérimentale et générale (2) 10 (Notes et Revue 6) 17–28.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref127"><unstructured_citation>Topsent E (1905) Étude sur les Dendroceratida. Archives de Zoologie expérimentale et générale (4) 3(8): 171-192.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref128"><unstructured_citation>Vacelet J (1961a) Quelques Eponges remarquables de Méditerranée. Revue des Travaux de l'Institut des Pêches maritimes 25(3): 351–354.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref129"><unstructured_citation>Van Soest RWM, Boury-Esnault N, Hooper JNA, Rützler K, De Voogd NJ, Alvarez B, Hajdu E, Pisera AB, Vacelet J, Manconi R, Schoenberg C, Janussen D, Tabachnick KR, Klautau M, Picton B, Kelly M (2012b) World Porifera Database [available online at http://www.marinespecies.org/porifera].</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref130"><unstructured_citation>Vosmaer GCJ (1883) Studies on Sponges. I. On Velinea gracilis, n. g.; n. sp. Mitteilungen aus der Zoologischen Station zu Neapel 4: 437–447, pls 31–32.</unstructured_citation></citation>
</citation_list>
</doi_citations>
</body>
</doi_batch>
