<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doi_batch version="4.3.0" xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/doi_resources_schema/4.3.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/doi_resources_schema/4.3.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/deposit/doi_resources4.3.0.xsd">
<head>
<doi_batch_id>3ebe300c-6186-4694-9d0a-94d3fead2139</doi_batch_id>
<depositor>
<name>pens</name>
<email_address>bozhin.karaivanov@gmail.com</email_address>
</depositor>
</head>
<body>
<doi_citations>
<doi>10.3897/zookeys.257.4156</doi>
<citation_list>
	<citation key="ref1"><journal_title>Revue d Entomologie (Caen)</journal_title><author>André</author><volume>6</volume><first_page>280</first_page><cYear>1887</cYear><article_title>Description de quelques fourmis nouvelles ou imparfaitement connues.</article_title><unstructured_citation>André E (1887) Description de quelques fourmis nouvelles ou imparfaitement connues. Revue d'Entomologie (Caen) 6: 280–298.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref2"><journal_title>Monografie del Museo Regionale di Scienze Naturali Torino</journal_title><author>Baroni Urbani</author><volume>36</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2003</cYear><article_title>The ant genus Proceratium in the extant and fossil record (Hymenoptera: Formicidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Baroni Urbani C, De Andrade ML (2003) The ant genus Proceratium in the extant and fossil record (Hymenoptera: Formicidae). Monografie del Museo Regionale di Scienze Naturali Torino 36: 1–492.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref3"><journal_title>Mémoires de l Institut Français d Afrique Noire</journal_title><author>Bernard</author><volume>19</volume><first_page>165</first_page><cYear>1953</cYear><article_title>La réserve naturelle intégrale du Mt Nimba. XI. Hyménoptères Formicidae.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bernard F (1953) La réserve naturelle intégrale du Mt Nimba. XI. Hyménoptères Formicidae. Mémoires de l'Institut Français d'Afrique Noire 19: 165–270.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref3"><doi>10.1111/j.1365-3113.1975.tb00001.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref4"><journal_title>Entomology</journal_title><author>Bolton</author><volume>34</volume><first_page>281</first_page><cYear>1976</cYear><article_title>The ant tribe Tetramoriini (Hymenoptera: Formicidae). Constituent genera, review of smaller genera and revision of Triglyphothrix Forel. Bulletin of the British Museum (Natural History)</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bolton B (1976) The ant tribe Tetramoriini (Hymenoptera: Formicidae). Constituent genera, review of smaller genera and revision of Triglyphothrix Forel. Bulletin of the British Museum (Natural History) Entomology 34: 281–379.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref5"><journal_title>Entomology</journal_title><author>Bolton</author><volume>36</volume><first_page>67</first_page><cYear>1977</cYear><article_title>The ant tribe Tetramoriini (Hymenoptera: Formicidae). The genus Tetramorium Mayr in the Oriental and Indo-Australian regions, and in Australia. Bulletin of the British Museum (Natural History)</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bolton B (1977) The ant tribe Tetramoriini (Hymenoptera: Formicidae). The genus Tetramorium Mayr in the Oriental and Indo-Australian regions, and in Australia. Bulletin of the British Museum (Natural History) Entomology 36: 67–151.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref5"><doi>10.1080/00222938500770191</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref6"><journal_title>Entomology</journal_title><author>Bolton</author><volume>54</volume><first_page>263</first_page><cYear>1987</cYear><article_title>A review of the Solenopsis genus-group and revision of Afrotropical Monomorium Mayr (Hymenoptera: Formicidae). Bulletin of the British Museum (Natural History)</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bolton B (1987) A review of the Solenopsis genus-group and revision of Afrotropical Monomorium Mayr (Hymenoptera: Formicidae). Bulletin of the British Museum (Natural History) Entomology 54: 263–452.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref7"><issn>05694450</issn><journal_title>Contrib Am Entomol Inst</journal_title><author>Bolton</author><volume>35</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2007</cYear><article_title>Taxonomy of the dolichoderine ant genus Technomyrmex Mayr (Hymenoptera: Formicidae) based on the worker caste.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bolton B (2007) Taxonomy of the dolichoderine ant genus Technomyrmex Mayr (Hymenoptera: Formicidae) based on the worker caste. Contributions of the American Entomological Institute 35: 1–150.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref7"><doi>10.1017/S0007485300054456</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref8"><doi>10.1155/1948/36948</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref9"><journal_title>Bulletin of the Museum of Comparative Zoology</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>118</volume><first_page>173</first_page><cYear>1958</cYear><article_title>Contributions toward a reclassification of the Formicidae. II. Tribe Ectatommini (Hymenoptera).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown WL, Jr. (1958a) Contributions toward a reclassification of the Formicidae. II. Tribe Ectatommini (Hymenoptera). Bulletin of the Museum of Comparative Zoology 118: 173–362.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref10"><doi>10.1155/1957/87473</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref11"><journal_title>Bulletin of the Museum of Comparative Zoology</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>122</volume><first_page>143</first_page><cYear>1960</cYear><article_title>Contributions toward a reclassification of the Formicidae. III. Tribe Amblyoponini (Hymenoptera).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown WL, Jr. (1960) Contributions toward a reclassification of the Formicidae. III. Tribe Amblyoponini (Hymenoptera). Bulletin of the Museum of Comparative Zoology 122: 143–230.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref12"><journal_title>Search Agriculture (Ithaca N Y)</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>5</volume><issue>1</issue><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1975</cYear><article_title>Contributions toward a reclassification of the Formicidae. V. Ponerinae, tribes Platythyreini, Cerapachyini, Cylindromyrmecini, Acanthostichini, and Aenictogitini.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown WL, Jr. (1975) Contributions toward a reclassification of the Formicidae. V. Ponerinae, tribes Platythyreini, Cerapachyini, Cylindromyrmecini, Acanthostichini, and Aenictogitini. Search Agriculture (Ithaca, N Y) 5(1): 1–115.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref13"><issn>05855098</issn><journal_title>Stud Entomol</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>19</volume><first_page>67</first_page><cYear>1976</cYear><article_title>Contributions toward a reclassification of the Formicidae. Part VI. Ponerinae, tribe Ponerini, subtribe Odontomachiti. Section A. Introduction, subtribal characters. Genus Odontomachus.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown WL, Jr. (1976) Contributions toward a reclassification of the Formicidae. Part VI. Ponerinae, tribe Ponerini, subtribe Odontomachiti. Section A. Introduction, subtribal characters. Genus Odontomachus. Studia Entomologica 19: 67–171.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref14"><issn>05855098</issn><journal_title>Stud Entomol</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>20</volume><first_page>549</first_page><cYear>1978</cYear><article_title>Contributions toward a reclassification of the Formicidae. Part VI. Ponerinae, tribe Ponerini, subtribe Odontomachiti. Section B. Genus Anochetus and bibliography.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown WL, Jr. (1978) Contributions toward a reclassification of the Formicidae. Part VI. Ponerinae, tribe Ponerini, subtribe Odontomachiti. Section B. Genus Anochetus and bibliography. Studia Entomologica 20: 549–638.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref15"><doi>10.1155/1994/65706</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref16"><journal_title>Monographs of the Institute of Science and Technology Manila</journal_title><author>Chapman</author><volume>1</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1951</cYear><article_title>Check list of the ants (Hymenoptera: Formicidae) of Asia.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Chapman JW, Capco SR (1951) Check list of the ants (Hymenoptera: Formicidae) of Asia. Monographs of the Institute of Science and Technology, Manila 1: 1–327.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref17"><author>Diamond</author><first_page>342</first_page><cYear>1975</cYear><volume_title>Ecology and Evolution of Communities</volume_title><article_title>Assembly of species communities.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Diamond JM (1975) Assembly of species communities. In: Cody ML, Diamond JM (Eds) Ecology and Evolution of Communities. Belknap Press, Cambridge, MA, 342–444.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref17"><doi>10.1073/pnas.73.1.262</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref18"><journal_title>Entomologist (London)</journal_title><author>Donisthorpe</author><volume>74</volume><first_page>36</first_page><cYear>1941</cYear><article_title>New ants from Waigeu Island, New Guinea, and the Solomons.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Donisthorpe H (1941) New ants from Waigeu Island, New Guinea, and the Solomons. Entomologist (London) 74: 36–42.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref18"><doi>10.1086/665996</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref18"><doi>10.1071/ZO9660073</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref18"><doi>10.1111/j.1440-6055.1978.tb02220.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref19"><doi>10.5962/bhl.title.36510</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref19"><doi>10.1371/journal.pone.0001787</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><journal_title>Transactions of the Entomological Society of London</journal_title><author>Forel</author><volume>1893</volume><first_page>333</first_page><cYear>1893</cYear><article_title>Formicides de l'Antille St. Vincent, récoltées par Mons. H. H. Smith.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Forel A (1893) Formicides de l'Antille St. Vincent, récoltées par Mons. H. H. Smith. Transactions of the Entomological Society of London 1893: 333–418.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref21"><issn>0035418X</issn><journal_title>Rev Suisse Zool</journal_title><author>Forel</author><volume>18</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1910</cYear><article_title>Formicides australiens reçus de MM. Froggatt et Rowland Turner.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Forel A (1910) Formicides australiens reçus de MM. Froggatt et Rowland Turner. Revue Suisse de Zoologie 18: 1–94.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref22"><journal_title>Entomologische Mitteilungen</journal_title><author>Forel</author><volume>1</volume><first_page>67</first_page><cYear>1912</cYear><article_title>H. Sauter's Formosa-Ausbeute. Formicidae (Hym.) (Schluss).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Forel A (1912) H. Sauter's Formosa-Ausbeute. Formicidae (Hym.) (Schluss). Entomologische Mitteilungen 1: 67–81.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref22"><doi>10.1111/j.1752-4571.2010.00119.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref22"><doi>10.1146/annurev.ento.47.091201.145244</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref22"><doi>10.2307/2406901</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref22"><doi>10.2307/2402874</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref22"><doi>10.1111/j.1440-6055.1971.tb00036.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref22"><doi>10.1007/BF02226626</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref23"><author>Greenslade</author><first_page>209</first_page><cYear>1970</cYear><volume_title>Methods of study in soil ecology</volume_title><article_title>Studies on the fauna of soil, litter and allied habitats in the Solomon Islands.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Greenslade PJM, Greenslade P (1970) Studies on the fauna of soil, litter and allied habitats in the Solomon Islands. In: Phillipson J (Ed) Methods of study in soil ecology. UNIPUB, New York, NY. 303 p., 209–212.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref23"><doi>10.1111/j.1440-6055.1971.tb00037.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref23"><doi>10.1007/BF02227169</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref24"><journal_title>Proceedings of the Hawaiian Entomological Society</journal_title><author>Gressitt</author><volume>16</volume><first_page>361</first_page><cYear>1958</cYear><article_title>Ants attracted to naphthalene on Malaita.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gressitt JL (1958) Ants attracted to naphthalene on Malaita. Proceedings of the Hawaiian Entomological Society 16: 361–362.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref25"><author>Guérin-Méneville</author><cYear>1844</cYear><volume_title>Iconographie du règne animal de G Cuvier ou représentation d après nature de l une des espèces les plus remarquables et souvent non encore figurées de chaque genre d animaux</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Guérin-Méneville FE (1844) Iconographie du règne animal de G. Cuvier, ou représentation d'après nature de l'une des espèces les plus remarquables, et souvent non encore figurées, de chaque genre d'animaux. Insectes. J. B. Baillière, Paris, 576 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref25"><doi>10.1016/S1367-9120(01)00069-4</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref26"><journal_title>Asian Myrmecology</journal_title><author>Hosoishi</author><volume>2</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2008</cYear><article_title>The ant genus Crematogaster Lund, subgenus Physocrema Forel, in the Indochinese Peninsula (Hymenoptera: Formicidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Hosoishi S, Ogata K (2008) The ant genus Crematogaster Lund, subgenus Physocrema Forel, in the Indochinese Peninsula (Hymenoptera: Formicidae). Asian Myrmecology 2: 1–10.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref27"><journal_title>FAO Asia and Pacific Plant Protection Commission</journal_title><author>Ikin</author><volume>27</volume><first_page>8</first_page><cYear>1984</cYear><article_title>Solomon Islands cocoa tree-ant. Quarterly Newsletter</article_title><unstructured_citation>Ikin R (1984) Solomon Islands cocoa tree-ant. Quarterly Newsletter, FAO Asia and Pacific Plant Protection Commission 27: 8.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref28"><issn>00798835</issn><journal_title>Mem Queensl Mus</journal_title><author>Kohout</author><volume>28</volume><first_page>499</first_page><cYear>1990</cYear><article_title>A review of the Polyrhachis viehmeyeri species-group (Hymenoptera: Formicidae: Formicinae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Kohout RJ (1990) A review of the Polyrhachis viehmeyeri species-group (Hymenoptera: Formicidae: Formicinae). Memoirs of the Queensland Museum 28: 499–508.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><issn>00798835</issn><journal_title>Mem Queensl Mus</journal_title><author>Kohout</author><volume>42</volume><first_page>505</first_page><cYear>1998</cYear><article_title>New synonyms and nomenclatural changes in the ant genus Polyrhachis Fr. Smith (Hymenoptera: Formicidae: Formicinae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Kohout RJ (1998) New synonyms and nomenclatural changes in the ant genus Polyrhachis Fr. Smith (Hymenoptera: Formicidae: Formicinae). Memoirs of the Queensland Museum 42: 505–531.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><issn>00798835</issn><journal_title>Mem Queensl Mus</journal_title><author>Kohout</author><volume>52</volume><first_page>87</first_page><cYear>2006</cYear><article_title>Review of Polyrhachis (Cyrtomyrma) Forel (Hymenoptera: Formicidae: Formicinae) of Australia, Borneo, New Guinea and the Solomon Islands with descriptions of new species.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Kohout RJ (2006) Review of Polyrhachis (Cyrtomyrma) Forel (Hymenoptera: Formicidae: Formicinae) of Australia, Borneo, New Guinea and the Solomon Islands with descriptions of new species. Memoirs of the Queensland Museum 52: 87–146.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><issn>10709428</issn><journal_title>J Hymenopt Res</journal_title><author>Kugler</author><volume>3</volume><first_page>17</first_page><cYear>1994</cYear><article_title>A revision of the ant genus Rogeria with description of the sting apparatus (Hymenoptera: Formicidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Kugler C (1994) A revision of the ant genus Rogeria with description of the sting apparatus (Hymenoptera: Formicidae). Journal of Hymenoptera Research 3: 17–89.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref32"><issn>05694450</issn><journal_title>Contrib Am Entomol Inst</journal_title><author>LaPolla</author><volume>33</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2004</cYear><article_title>Acropyga (Hymenoptera: Formicidae) of the world.</article_title><unstructured_citation>LaPolla JS (2004) Acropyga (Hymenoptera: Formicidae) of the world. Contributions of the American Entomological Institute 33: 1–130.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>LaPolla</author><volume>2046</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2009</cYear><article_title>Taxonomic revision of the Southeast Asian ant genus Euprenolepis.</article_title><unstructured_citation>LaPolla JS (2009) Taxonomic revision of the Southeast Asian ant genus Euprenolepis. Zootaxa 2046: 1–25. http://www.mapress.com/zootaxa/</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><doi>10.1080/00222930210135631</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref34"><journal_title>University of California Publications in Entomology</journal_title><author>Lattke</author><volume>122</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2004</cYear><article_title>A taxonomic revision and phylogenetic analysis of the ant genus Gnamptogenys Roger in Southeast Asia and Australasia (Hymenoptera: Formicidae: Ponerinae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Lattke JE (2004) A taxonomic revision and phylogenetic analysis of the ant genus Gnamptogenys Roger in Southeast Asia and Australasia (Hymenoptera: Formicidae: Ponerinae). University of California Publications in Entomology 122: 1–266.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref35"><journal_title>PANS</journal_title><author>Leston</author><volume>19</volume><first_page>311</first_page><cYear>1973</cYear><article_title>The ant mosaic - tropical tree crops and the limiting of pests and diseases.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Leston D (1973) The ant mosaic - tropical tree crops and the limiting of pests and diseases. PANS (Pest Articles and News Summaries) 19: 311–341.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref36"><journal_title>British Solomon Island Protect Agr Gaz</journal_title><author>Lever</author><volume>1</volume><first_page>13</first_page><cYear>1933</cYear><article_title>Relative abundance of Axiagastus and Oecophylla on coconut palms in the Western Solomons.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Lever RJAW (1933) Relative abundance of Axiagastus and Oecophylla on coconut palms in the Western Solomons. British Solomon Island Protect Agr Gaz 1: 13.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref37"><journal_title>World Crops</journal_title><author>Lever</author><volume>13</volume><issue>2</issue><first_page>60</first_page><cYear>1961</cYear><article_title>Immature nutfall of coconuts. The war of the ants.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Lever RJAW (1961) Immature nutfall of coconuts. The war of the ants. World Crops 13(2): 60–62.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref38"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Lucky</author><volume>1681</volume><first_page>37</first_page><cYear>2008</cYear><article_title>New species of Lordomyrma (Hymenoptera: Formicidae) from Southeast Asia and Fiji.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Lucky A, Sarnat EM (2008) New species of Lordomyrma (Hymenoptera: Formicidae) from Southeast Asia and Fiji. Zootaxa 1681: 37–46.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref39"><journal_title>Bull Mus Comp Zool</journal_title><author>Mann</author><volume>63</volume><first_page>273</first_page><cYear>1919</cYear><article_title>The ants of the British Solomon Islands.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Mann WM (1919) The ants of the British Solomon Islands. Bull Mus Comp Zool 63: 273–391.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref40"><issn>00138746</issn><journal_title>Ann Entomol Soc Am</journal_title><author>Mann</author><volume>13</volume><first_page>60</first_page><cYear>1920</cYear><article_title>Ant guests from Fiji and the British Solomon Islands.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Mann WM (1920) Ant guests from Fiji and the British Solomon Islands. Annals of the Entomological Society of America 13: 60–69.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref41"><author>Mann</author><cYear>1948</cYear><volume_title>Ant hill odyssey</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Mann WM (1948) Ant hill odyssey. Little, Brown, Boston, 338 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref42"><author>Mayr</author><cYear>2001</cYear><volume_title>The birds of northern Melanesia speciation ecology and biogeography</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Mayr E, Diamond JM (2001) The birds of northern Melanesia: speciation, ecology, and biogeography. Oxford University Press, Oxford, United Kingdom, 492 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref43"><journal_title>Sitzungsberichte der Kaiserlichen Akademie der Wissenschaften in Wien Mathematisch-Naturwissenschaftliche Klasse Abteilung I</journal_title><author>Mayr</author><volume>53</volume><first_page>484</first_page><cYear>1866</cYear><article_title>Myrmecologische Beiträge.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Mayr G (1866) Myrmecologische Beiträge. Sitzungsberichte der Kaiserlichen Akademie der Wissenschaften in Wien Mathematisch-Naturwissenschaftliche Klasse Abteilung I 53: 484–517, Tafel.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref44"><journal_title>Agricultural Journal Fiji</journal_title><author>O'Conner</author><volume>20</volume><first_page>27</first_page><cYear>1949</cYear><article_title>Premature nutfall of coconuts in the British Solomon Islands Protectorate.</article_title><unstructured_citation>O'Conner BA (1949) Premature nutfall of coconuts in the British Solomon Islands Protectorate. Agricultural Journal, Fiji 20: 27–29.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref45"><journal_title>Agricultural Journal Fiji</journal_title><author>O'Conner</author><volume>21</volume><first_page>21</first_page><cYear>1950</cYear><article_title>Premature nutfall of coconuts in the British Solomon Islands Protectorate.</article_title><unstructured_citation>O'Conner BA (1950) Premature nutfall of coconuts in the British Solomon Islands Protectorate. Agricultural Journal, Fiji 21: 21–42.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref45"><doi>10.1017/S0007485300046848</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref46"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Sarnat</author><volume>1767</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2008</cYear><article_title>A taxonomic revision of the Pheidole roosevelti-group (Hymenoptera: Formicidae) in Fiji.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Sarnat EM (2008) A taxonomic revision of the Pheidole roosevelti-group (Hymenoptera: Formicidae) in Fiji. Zootaxa 1767: 1–36.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><journal_title>University of California Publications in Entomology</journal_title><author>Sarnat</author><volume>132</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2012</cYear><article_title>Ants of Fiji.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Sarnat EM, Economo EP (2012) Ants of Fiji. University of California Publications in Entomology 132: 1–398.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Bolton B (2000) The ant tribe Dacetini. With a revision of the Strumigenys species of the Malagasy Region by Brian L. Fisher, and a revision of the Austral epopostrumiform genera by Steven O. Shattuck. Memoirs of the American Entomological Institute 65 (2 vol.): 1–1028.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Bolton B (2012) AntCat: An online catalog of ants of the world. 1 Jan. 2012. http://antcat.org [accessed Accessed 22 Aug. 2012].</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Bolton B, Alpert G, Ward PS, Nasrecki P (2006) Bolton's Catalogue of ants of the world. Harvard University Press, Cambridge, Massachusetts, CD-ROM., pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Bradley JD (1955) The Natural History of Rennell Island, British Solomon Islands. 3. Account and List of Stations of the British Museum. 43–57.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Brown WL, Jr. (1988) Strumigenys yaleopleura species nov. Pilot Register of Zoology (Cornell University) Card No. 41, pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Brown WL, Jr., Kempf WW (1960) A world revision of the ant tribe Basicerotini (Hym. Formicidae). Studia Entomologica (n.s.)3: 161–250.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Fasi J (2009) Quantifying the dominance of little fire ant (Wasmannia auropunctata) and its effect on crops in the Solomon Islands. Masters of Science in Biology thesis, The University of the South Pacific, ix + 101 p.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Greenslade PJM (1964) Entomological research on premature nutfall of coconuts in the British Solomon Islands. Studies in the ecology of ants. Entomol. Prog. Rep. No. 7, p. 1–43, pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Kohout RJ (2012) A review of the Australian Polyrhachis ants of the subgenera Myrma Billberg, Myrmatopa Forel, Myrmothrinax Forel and Polyrhachis Fr. Smith (Hymenoptera: Formicidae: Formicinae). Memoirs of the Queensland Museum – Nature 56: 25–59.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Kroenke LW, Rodda P (1984) Cenozoic tectonic development of the Southwest Pacific. Technical bulletin (Committee for Co-ordination of Joint Prospecting for Mineral Resources in South Pacific Offshore Areas); no 6. CCOP/SOPAC. United Nations. Economic and Social Commission for Asia and the, Pacific, [Suva, Fiji], 122 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Lin CC, Wu WJ (1996) Revision of the ant genus Strumigenys Fr. Smith (Hymenoptera: Formicidae) of Taiwan. Chinese Journal of Entomology = Zhonghua Kunchong 16: 137–152.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>MacArthur RH, Wilson EO (1967) The theory of island biogeography. Princeton University Press, Princeton, xi + 203 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Mackay WP, Mackay EE (2010) The Systematics and Biology of the New World Ants of the Genus Pachycondyla (Hymenoptera: Formicidae). Edwin Mellon Press, Lewiston, New York, xii+642 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Phillips JS (1940) Immature nutfall of coconuts in the Solomon Islands. Bulletin of Entomological Research 31: 295–316, plate 213.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Porter SD, Wojcik DP (2012) FORMIS: a master bibliography of ant literature. USDA-ARS, CMAVE, Gainesville, FL, pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Sarnat EM (2006) Lordomyrma (Hymenoptera: Formicidae) of the Fiji Islands. Occasional Papers of the Bernice Pauhahi Bishop Museum 90: 9–42.</unstructured_citation></citation>
</citation_list>
</doi_citations>
</body>
</doi_batch>
