<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doi_batch version="4.3.0" xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/doi_resources_schema/4.3.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/doi_resources_schema/4.3.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/deposit/doi_resources4.3.0.xsd">
<head>
<doi_batch_id>2ca6ab11-490a-4006-b43c-11896461e38b</doi_batch_id>
<depositor>
<name>pens</name>
<email_address>bozhin.karaivanov@gmail.com</email_address>
</depositor>
</head>
<body>
<doi_citations>
<doi>part-2-282-4401</doi>
<citation_list>
	<citation key="ref1"><author>Chevrolat</author><first_page>735</first_page><cYear>1847</cYear><volume_title>Dictionnaire universel d histoire naturelle… Tome neuvième MM</volume_title><article_title>Philochlaenia.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Chevrolat LAA (1847a) Philochlaenia. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.) Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle… Tome neuvième. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, 735–736.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref2"><author>Chevrolat</author><volume>267</volume><first_page>602</first_page><cYear>1847</cYear><volume_title>Dictionnaire universel d histoire naturelle… Tome dixième MM</volume_title><article_title>Plectroscelis. Psomeles.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Chevrolat LAA (1847b) Plectroscelis. Psomeles. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.) Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle… Tome dixième. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, 267, 602.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref3"><author>Chevrolat</author><volume>52</volume><cYear>1848</cYear><volume_title>Dictionnaire universel d histoire naturelle… Tome douzième MM</volume_title><article_title>Strabala.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Chevrolat LAA (1848) Strabala. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.) Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle… Tome douzième. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, 52.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref4"><journal_title>EOS Revista Espa-ola de Entomologia</journal_title><author>Cobos</author><volume>55–56</volume><issue>1979–1980</issue><first_page>23</first_page><cYear>1981</cYear><article_title>Ensayo sobre los géneros de la subfamilia Polycestinae (Coleoptera, Buprestidae) (Parte II).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Cobos A (1981) Ensayo sobre los géneros de la subfamilia Polycestinae (Coleoptera, Buprestidae) (Parte II). EOS, Revista Espa-ola de Entomologia 55–56 [1979–1980]: 23–94.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref5"><issn>00973157</issn><journal_title>Proc Acad Nat Sci Philadelphia</journal_title><author>Crotch</author><volume>25</volume><first_page>19</first_page><cYear>1873</cYear><article_title>Materials for the study of the Phytophaga of the United States.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Crotch GR (1873a). Materials for the study of the Phytophaga of the United States. Proceedings of the Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia 25: 19–83.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref6"><issn>00028320</issn><journal_title>Trans Am Entomol Soc</journal_title><author>Crotch</author><volume>4</volume><first_page>363</first_page><cYear>1873</cYear><article_title>Revision of the Coccinellidae of the United States.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Crotch GR (1873b) Revision of the Coccinellidae of the United States. Transactions of the American Entomological Society 4: 363–382.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref7"><journal_title>Cistula Entomologica</journal_title><author>Crotch</author><volume>1</volume><first_page>377</first_page><cYear>1876</cYear><article_title>A revision of the coleopterous family Erotylidae.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Crotch GR (1876) A revision of the coleopterous family Erotylidae. Cistula Entomologica 1: 377–572.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref8"><author>von Dalla Torre</author><first_page>291</first_page><cYear>1913</cYear><volume_title>Coleopterorum Catalogus auspiciis et auxilio W Junk editus a S Schenkling Pars 50 Scarabaeidae Melolonthinae IV</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Dalla Torre KW von (1913) Coleopterorum Catalogus auspiciis et auxilio W. Junk editus a S. Schenkling. Pars 50: Scarabaeidae: Melolonthinae IV. W. Junk, Berlin, 291–450.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref9"><author>Dejean</author><cYear>1802</cYear><volume_title>Catalogue des coléoptères de la collection d Auguste Dejean classés suivant le Systema Eleutheratorum Fabricii</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Dejean PFMA (1802) Catalogue des coléoptères de la collection d'Auguste Dejean: classés suivant le Systema Eleutheratorum Fabricii. Impr. de la République, Paris, [2] + 11 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref10"><author>Dejean</author><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1833</cYear><volume_title>Catalogue des Coléoptères de la collection de M le Comte Dejean</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Dejean PFMA (1833) Catalogue des Coléoptères de la collection de M. le Comte Dejean. [Livraisons 1-2]. Méquignon-Marvis, Paris, 1–176.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref11"><author>Dejean</author><first_page>177</first_page><cYear>1834</cYear><volume_title>Catalogue des Coléoptères de la collection de M le Comte Dejean</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Dejean PFMA (1834) Catalogue des Coléoptères de la collection de M. le Comte Dejean. [Livraison 3]. Méquignon-Marvis, Paris, 177–256.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref12"><author>Dejean</author><first_page>257</first_page><cYear>1835</cYear><volume_title>Catalogue des Coléoptères de la collection de M le Comte Dejean</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Dejean PFMA (1835) Catalogue des Coléoptères de la collection de M. le Comte Dejean. [Livraison 4]. Méquignon-Marvis, Paris, 257–360.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref13"><author>Dejean</author><first_page>361</first_page><cYear>1836</cYear><volume_title>Catalogue des Coléoptères de la collection de M le Comte Dejean</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Dejean PFMA (1836a) Catalogue des Coléoptères de la collection de M. le Comte Dejean. [Livraison 5]. Méquignon-Marvis, Paris, 361–443.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref14"><author>Dejean</author><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1836</cYear><volume_title>Catalogue des coléoptères de la collection de M le comte Dejean Troisième édition revue corrigée et augmentée</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Dejean PFMA (1836b) Catalogue des coléoptères de la collection de M. le comte Dejean. Troisième édition, revue, corrigée et augmentée. [Livraisons 1-4]. Méquignon-Marvis Père et Fils, Paris, 1–384.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref15"><author>Dejean</author><first_page>385</first_page><cYear>1837</cYear><volume_title>Catalogue des coléoptères de la collection de M le comte Dejean Troisième édition revue corrigée et augmentée</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Dejean PFMA (1837) Catalogue des coléoptères de la collection de M. le comte Dejean. Troisième édition, revue, corrigée et augmentée. [Livraison 5]. Méquignon-Marvis Père et Fils, Paris, 385–503.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref16"><author>Delkeskamp</author><cYear>1977</cYear><volume_title>Cantharidae Coleopterorum Catalogus Supplementa Pars 165 Fasc 1</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Delkeskamp K (1977) Cantharidae. Coleopterorum Catalogus Supplementa. Pars 165, Fasc. 1. Dr W. Junk, The Hague, 485 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref17"><author>Delkeskamp</author><cYear>1981</cYear><volume_title>Erotylidae von Afrika und Madagascar Coleopterorum Catalogus Supplementa Pars 34</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Delkeskamp K (1981) Erotylidae von Afrika und Madagascar. Coleopterorum Catalogus Supplementa. Pars 34. Dr W. Junk, The Hague, 65 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref18"><journal_title>Coleoptera</journal_title><author>Dombrow</author><volume>5</volume><first_page>107</first_page><cYear>2001</cYear><article_title>Revision of the genus Gymnoloma Burmeister 1844 with observations on three new genera (Coleoptera: Scarabaeidae: Melolonthinae: Hopliini). 14th contribution to the knowledge of African Hopliini.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Dombrow H (2001) Revision of the genus Gymnoloma Burmeister 1844 with observations on three new genera (Coleoptera: Scarabaeidae: Melolonthinae: Hopliini). 14th contribution to the knowledge of African Hopliini. Coleoptera 5: 107–148.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref19"><author>Drapiez</author><cYear>1837</cYear><volume_title>Dictionnaire classique des sciences naturelles présentant la définition l analyse et l histoire de tous les êtres qui composent les trois règnes leur application générale aux arts à l agriculture à la médecine à l économie domestique etc résumant tous les faits présentés par les dictionnaires d histoire naturelle augmentée des nombreuses découvertes acquises depuis la publication de ces ouvrages Tome second</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Drapiez PAJ (1837) Dictionnaire classique des sciences naturelles, présentant la définition, l'analyse et l'histoire de tous les êtres qui composent les trois règnes, leur application générale aux arts, à l'agriculture, à la médecine, à l'économie domestique, etc.; résumant tous les faits présentés par les dictionnaires d'histoire naturelle; augmentée des nombreuses découvertes acquises depuis la publication de ces ouvrages. Tome second. Meline, Cans et compagnie, Bruxelles, 570 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><journal_title>Series Entomologica (Dordrecht)</journal_title><author>Endrödi</author><volume>28</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1985</cYear><article_title>The Dynastinae of the world.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Endrödi S (1985) The Dynastinae of the world. Series Entomologica (Dordrecht) 28: 1–800.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref21"><journal_title>Archiv für Naturgeschichte</journal_title><author>Erichson</author><volume>3</volume><issue>2</issue><first_page>281</first_page><cYear>1837</cYear><article_title>Bericht über die Leistungen in der Entomologie während des Jahres 1836.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Erichson WF (1837b) Bericht über die Leistungen in der Entomologie während des Jahres 1836. Archiv für Naturgeschichte 3(2): 281–339.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref22"><journal_title>Archiv für Naturgeschichte</journal_title><author>Erichson</author><volume>8</volume><issue>1</issue><first_page>83</first_page><cYear>1842</cYear><article_title>Beitrag zur Insecten-Fauna von Vandiemensland, mit besonderer Berücksichtigung der geographischen Verbreitung der Insecten.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Erichson WF (1842) Beitrag zur Insecten-Fauna von Vandiemensland, mit besonderer Berücksichtigung der geographischen Verbreitung der Insecten. Archiv für Naturgeschichte 8(1): 83–287.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref23"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Evans</author><volume>211</volume><first_page>3</first_page><cYear>2003</cYear><article_title>A checklist of the New World chafers (Coleoptera: Scarabaeidae: Melolonthinae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Evans AV (2003) A checklist of the New World chafers (Coleoptera: Scarabaeidae: Melolonthinae). Zootaxa 211: 3–458.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref23"><doi>10.5962/bhl.title.36510</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref24"><author>Fabricius</author><cYear>1781</cYear><volume_title>Species insectorum exhibentes eorum differentias specificas synonyma auctorum loca natalia metamorphosin adiectis observationibus descriptionibus Tom I C E Bohnii</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Fabricius JC (1781) Species insectorum exhibentes eorum differentias specificas, synonyma auctorum, loca natalia, metamorphosin adiectis observationibus, descriptionibus. Tom. I. C.E. Bohnii, Hamburgi et Kilonii, [8] + 552 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref24"><doi>10.5962/bhl.title.36532</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref25"><journal_title>Zeitschrift für Entomologie</journal_title><author>Ferrer</author><volume>27</volume><first_page>229</first_page><cYear>2006</cYear><article_title>Description d'un genre nouveau et note synonymique et systématique sur les genres Alobates Motschoulsky, 1872 et Acanthobas Gebien, 1928 (Coleoptera, Tenebrionidae, Tenebrionini). Entomofauna</article_title><unstructured_citation>Ferrer J (2006) Description d'un genre nouveau et note synonymique et systématique sur les genres Alobates Motschoulsky, 1872 et Acanthobas Gebien, 1928 (Coleoptera, Tenebrionidae, Tenebrionini). Entomofauna, Zeitschrift für Entomologie 27: 229–240.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref26"><author>Fischer von Waldheim</author><cYear>1829</cYear><volume_title>Museum historiae naturalis Universitatis Caesareae Mosquensis Pars II Insecta Typis Universitatis Caesareae</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Fischer von Waldheim G (1829) Museum historiae naturalis Universitatis Caesareae Mosquensis. Pars II. Insecta. Typis Universitatis Caesareae, Mosquae, 147 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref27"><journal_title>Entomologische Arbeiten aus dem Museum Georg Frey</journal_title><author>Freude</author><volume>18</volume><first_page>137</first_page><cYear>1967</cYear><article_title>Revision der Epitragini (Coleoptera, Tenebrionidae). I. Teil.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Freude H (1967) Revision der Epitragini (Coleoptera, Tenebrionidae). I. Teil. Entomologische Arbeiten aus dem Museum Georg Frey 18: 137–307.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref28"><journal_title>Pietro Rossi</journal_title><author>Gebien</author><volume>2</volume><first_page>505</first_page><cYear>1937</cYear><article_title>Katalog der Tenebrioniden (Col. Heteromera). Teil I. Publicazioni del Museo Entomologico</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gebien H (1937) Katalog der Tenebrioniden (Col. Heteromera). Teil I. Publicazioni del Museo Entomologico «Pietro Rossi» 2: 505–883.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><journal_title>Mitteilungen der Münchener Entomologischen Gesellschaft</journal_title><author>Gebien</author><volume>29</volume><first_page>443</first_page><cYear>1939</cYear><article_title>Katalog der Tenebrioniden. Teil II.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gebien H (1939) Katalog der Tenebrioniden. Teil II. Mitteilungen der Münchener Entomologischen Gesellschaft 29: 443–474.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><journal_title>Mitteilungen der Münchener Entomologischen Gesellschaft</journal_title><author>Gebien</author><volume>32</volume><first_page>308</first_page><cYear>1942</cYear><article_title>Katalog der Tenebrioniden. Teil II.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gebien H (1942a) Katalog der Tenebrioniden. Teil II. Mitteilungen der Münchener Entomologischen Gesellschaft 32: 308–346.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><journal_title>Mitteilungen der Münchner Entomologischen Gesellschaft</journal_title><author>Gebien</author><volume>32</volume><first_page>729</first_page><cYear>1942</cYear><article_title>Katalog der Tenebrioniden. Teil III.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gebien H (1942b) Katalog der Tenebrioniden. Teil III. Mitteilungen der Münchner Entomologischen Gesellschaft 32: 729–760.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref32"><journal_title>Mitteilungen der Münchner Entomologischen Gesellschaft</journal_title><author>Gebien</author><volume>33</volume><first_page>895</first_page><cYear>1943</cYear><article_title>Katalog der Tenebrioniden. Teil III.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gebien H (1943) Katalog der Tenebrioniden. Teil III. Mitteilungen der Münchner Entomologischen Gesellschaft 33: 895–926.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><author>Gemminger</author><first_page>753</first_page><cYear>1868</cYear><volume_title>Catalogus coleopterorum hucusque descriptorum synonymicus et systematicus Tom III Histeridae Phalacridae Nitidulidae Trogositidae Colydidae Rhysodidae Cucujidae Cryptophagidae Derodontidae Latrididae Othnidae Mycetophagidae Thorictidae Dermestidae Byrrhidae Georyssidae Parnidae Heteroceridae Lucanidae E H Gummi</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Gemminger M, Harold E von (1868) Catalogus coleopterorum hucusque descriptorum synonymicus et systematicus. Tom. III. Histeridae, Phalacridae, Nitidulidae, Trogositidae, Colydidae, Rhysodidae, Cucujidae, Cryptophagidae, Derodontidae, Latrididae, Othnidae, Mycetophagidae, Thorictidae, Dermestidae, Byrrhidae, Georyssidae, Parnidae, Heteroceridae, Lucanidae. E.H. Gummi, Monachii, pp. 753–978 + [5].</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Chevrolat LAA (1858) Description de longicornes nouveaux du vieux Calabar, côte occidentale d'Afrique. Revue et Magasin de Zoologie pure et appliquée (2e série) 10: 348–358.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Chûjô M (1969) Fauna Japonica. Erotylidae (Insecta: Coleoptera). Academic Press of Japan, Tokyo, xii + 316 pp. (+ 23 pls).</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Crotch GR (1874) A revision of the coleopterous family Coccinellidae. E.W. Janson, London, xvi + 311 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Curtis J (1838) British entomology; being illustrations and descriptions of the genera of insects found in Great Britain and Ireland: containing coloured figures from nature of the most rare and beautiful species, and in many instances of the plants upon which they are found. Vol. XV. London, pls 674–721.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Dahl G (1823) Coleoptera und Lepidoptera. Ein systematisches Verzeichniss, mit beygesetzten Preisen der Vorräthe. J.E. Akkermann, Wien, vi + 103 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Danilevsky ML (2011) Additions and corrections to the new Catalogue of Palaearctic Cerambycidae (Coleoptera) edited by I. Löbl and A. Smetana, 2010. Part II. Russian Entomological Journal 19 [2010]: 313–324.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Dejean PFMA (1821) Catalogue de la collection de Coléoptères de M. le Baron Dejean. Crevot, Paris, viii + 138 + [2] pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Dejean PFMA (1828) Species général des Coléoptères, de la collection de M. le Comte Dejean. Tome troisième. Méquignon-Marvis, Paris, vii + 556 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Dellacasa M, Dellacasa G (2006) Tribe Aphodiini Leach, 1815. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 3. Scarabaeoidea - Scirtoidea - Dascilloidea - Buprestoidea - Byrrhoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 105–143.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>De Moor PP (1975) Monograph of the Praeugenina. Transvaal Museum, Memoirs No. 17: 1–203.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Desmarest E (1860) Encyclopédie d'histoire naturelle ou traité complet de cette science d'après les travaux des naturalistes les plus éminents de tous les pays et de toutes les époques; Buffon, Daubenton, Lacépède, G. Cuvier, F. Cuvier, Geoffroy Saint-Hilaire, Latreille, de Jussieu, Brongniart, etc., etc. Ouvrage résumant les observations des auteurs anciens et comprenant toutes les découvertes modernes jusqu'à nos jours par le Dr Chenu. Coléoptères buprestiens, scarabéiens, pimeliens, curculioniens, scolytiens, chrysoméliens, etc. Troisième partie. Marescq et Compagnie, Paris, [3] + 360 pp. + 48 pls.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Döberl M (2010) Subfamily Alticinae Newman, 1835. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 6. Chrysomeloidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 491–563.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Drumont A, Komiya Z (2010) Subfamily Prioninae Latreille, 1802. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 6. Chrysomeloidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 86–95.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Duponchel P (1840) Ancylonycha [p. 481]. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.) Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle résumant et complétant tous les faits présentés par les encyclopédies, les anciens dictionnaires scientifiques, les oeuvres complètes de Buffon, et les meilleurs traités spéciaux sur les diverses branches des sciences naturelles; donnant la description des êtres et des divers phénomènes de la nature, l'étymologie et la définition des noms scientifiques, les principales applications des corps organiques et inorganiques, à l'agriculture, à la médecine, aux arts industriels, etc. Tome premier. [Livraisons 3-11]. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, pp. ?81–560.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Duponchel P (1842) Cerandria. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.). Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle… Tome troisième. [Livraisons 25–29]. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, 285.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Duponchel P (1843) Chalcophora. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.) Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle… Tome troisième. [Livraisons 30–36]. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, 372.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Duponchel P (1844) Epicauta. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.) Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle… Tome cinquième. [Livraisons 49–56]. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, 356.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Duponchel P (1845) Eurythyrea. Eutrapela. Heteronychus. Heterophaga. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.) Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle… Tome cinquième. [Livraisons 57–60]. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, 525, 533, 601.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Duponchel P, Chevrolat LAA (1841) Aplosonyx. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.) Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle… Tome deuxième. [Livraisons 13–17]. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, 17.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Duponchel P, Chevrolat LAA (1842a) Aulacophora; Barytopus. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.) Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle… Tome deuxième. [Livraisons 18–24]. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, 337, 483.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Duponchel P, Chevrolat LAA (1842b) Cassidaires. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.) Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle… Tome troisième. [Livraisons 25–29]. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, 210–211.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Erichson WF (1837a) Die Käfer der Mark Brandenburg. Erster Band. Erste Abtheilung. F.H. Morin, Berlin, viii + pp. 1–384.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Evenhuis NL (1997) Litteratura taxonomica dipterorum (1758-1930); being a selected list of the books and prints of Diptera taxonomy from the beginning of Linnaean zoological nomenclature to the end of the year 1930; containing information on the biographies, bibliographies, types, collections, and patronymic genera of the authors listed in this work; including detailed information on publication dates, original and subsequent editions, and other ancillary data concerning the publications listed herein. Volume I: A-K. Backhuys Publishers, Leiden, vii + 426 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Fabricius JC (1787) Mantissa insectorvm sistens eorvm species nvper detectas adiectis characteribvs genericis, differentiis specificis, emendationibvs, observationibvs. Tom. I. C.G. Proft, Hafniae, xx + 348 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Faldermann F (1835) Coleopterorum ab illustrissimo bungio in China boreali, Mongolia, et montibus Altaicus collectorum, nec non ab ill. Turczaninoffio et Stchukino e provincia Irkutzk missorum illustrationes. Mémoires présentés à l'Académie Impériale des Sciences de Saint-Pétersbourg par divers savans et lus dans ses assemblées (série 6) 2: 337–464.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Fowler WW (1908) Coleoptera. Fam. Erotylidae. Subfam. Languriinae. Genera insectorum publiés par P. Wytsman. 78me Fascicule. V. Verteneuil &amp; L. Desmet, 45 pp. + 3 pls.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Gebien H (1910) Coleopterorum Catalogus auspiciis et auxilio W. Junk editus a S. Schenkling. Pars 15: Tenebrionidae I. W. Junk, Berlin. 166 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Gebien H (1938) Katalog der Tenebrioniden. Teil II. Mitteilungen der Münchener Entomologischen Gesellschaft 28: 49–80, 283–314.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Geisthardt M, Satô M (2007) Family Lampyridae Latreille, 1817. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 4. Elateroidea - Derodontoidea - Bostrichoidea - Lymexyloidea - Cleroidea - Cucujoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 225–234.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Gemminger M, Harold E von (1869) Catalogus coleopterorum hucusque descriptorum synonymicus et systematicus. Tom. IV. Scarabaeidae. EH Gummi, Monachii, 979–1346.</unstructured_citation></citation>
</citation_list>
</doi_citations>
</body>
</doi_batch>
