<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doi_batch version="4.3.0" xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/doi_resources_schema/4.3.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/doi_resources_schema/4.3.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/deposit/doi_resources4.3.0.xsd">
<head>
<doi_batch_id>5118b851-23f2-41ee-b482-4681e494b027</doi_batch_id>
<depositor>
<name>pens</name>
<email_address>bozhin.karaivanov@gmail.com</email_address>
</depositor>
</head>
<body>
<doi_citations>
<doi>part-1-282-4401</doi>
<citation_list>
	<citation key="ref1"><author>Aalbu</author><volume>III</volume><first_page>499</first_page><cYear>2002</cYear><volume_title>Biodiversidad taxonomia y biogeografia de arthropodos de Mexico Hacia una sintesis de su conocimiento</volume_title><article_title>Tenebrionidae.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Aalbu RL, Flores GE, Triplehorn CA (2002b) Tenebrionidae. In: Bousquets JL, Morrone JJ (Eds) Biodiversidad, taxonomia y biogeografia de arthropodos de Mexico: Hacia una sintesis de su conocimiento Vol III. Universidad Nacional Autonoma de Mexico, Mexico, 499–512.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref1"><doi>10.1111/j.1365-3113.2005.00307.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref2"><journal_title>Entomologicheskoe Obozrenie</journal_title><author>Aksentjev</author><volume>67</volume><first_page>569</first_page><cYear>1988</cYear><article_title>A catalogue of the genus-group taxa of the beetle family Meloidae (Coleoptera).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Aksentjev SI (1988) A catalogue of the genus-group taxa of the beetle family Meloidae (Coleoptera). Entomologicheskoe Obozrenie 67: 569–582 [English translation in Entomological Review 68: 11–26]</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref3"><author>Alonso-Zarazaga</author><cYear>1999</cYear><volume_title>A world catalogue of families and genera of Curculionoidea (Insecta Coleoptera) (excepting Scolytidae and Platypodidae)</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Alonso-Zarazaga MA, Lyal CHC (1999) A world catalogue of families and genera of Curculionoidea (Insecta: Coleoptera) (excepting Scolytidae and Platypodidae). Entomopraxis, Barcelona, 315 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref4"><journal_title>Zoologia</journal_title><author>Alvarenga</author><volume>2</volume><first_page>75</first_page><cYear>1965</cYear><article_title>Especies tipos dos generos e subgeneros neotropicais da familia Erotylidae (Coleoptera). Boletim da Universidade Federal do Parana</article_title><unstructured_citation>Alvarenga M (1965) Especies tipos dos generos e subgeneros neotropicais da familia Erotylidae (Coleoptera). Boletim da Universidade Federal do Parana, Zoologia 2: 75–92.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref5"><journal_title>Bulletin de la Société Impériale des Naturalistes de Moscou</journal_title><volume>13</volume><first_page>371</first_page><cYear>1840</cYear><article_title>A vendre la collection d'insectes de Mr. le Cte Dejean.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Anonymous (1840a) A vendre la collection d'insectes de Mr. le Cte Dejean. Bulletin de la Société Impériale des Naturalistes de Moscou 13: 371–373.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref6"><cYear>1840</cYear><volume_title>Catalogue de livres la plupart relatifs à l entomologie provenant de la bibliothèque de M le Comte Dejean dont la vente se fera le mercredi 4 novembre et jours suivans six heures de relevée rue des Bons-Enfans n 30</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Anonymous (1840b) Catalogue de livres, la plupart relatifs à l'entomologie, provenant de la bibliothèque de M. le Comte Dejean, dont la vente se fera le mercredi 4 novembre et jours suivans, six heures de relevée, rue des Bons-Enfans, n.30. Silvestre, Paris, 30 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref7"><issn>00430439</issn><journal_title>J Wash Acad Sci</journal_title><author>Arnett</author><volume>40</volume><first_page>217</first_page><cYear>1950</cYear><article_title>Generic names of the beetle family Oedemeridae and their type species.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Arnett RH Jr (1950) Generic names of the beetle family Oedemeridae and their type species. Journal of the Washington Academy of Sciences 40: 217–225.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref8"><issn>00379271</issn><journal_title>Ann Soc Entomol Fr</journal_title><author>Audinet-Serville</author><volume>4</volume><first_page>5</first_page><cYear>1835</cYear><article_title>Nouvelle classification de la famille des longicornes (suite).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Audinet-Serville JG (1835) Nouvelle classification de la famille des longicornes (suite). Annales de la Société Entomologique de France 4: 5–100, 197–228.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref9"><journal_title>Arkiv för Zoologi</journal_title><author>Aurivillius</author><volume>3</volume><issue>18</issue><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1907</cYear><article_title>Neue oder wenig bekannte Coleoptera Longicornia. 9.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Aurivillius C (1907) Neue oder wenig bekannte Coleoptera Longicornia. 9. Arkiv för Zoologi 3(18): 1–38.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref10"><issn>00798835</issn><journal_title>Mem Queensl Mus</journal_title><author>Ballantyne</author><volume>46</volume><first_page>15</first_page><cYear>2000</cYear><article_title>Lampyridae of Australia (Coleoptera: Lampyridae: Luciolinae: Luciolini).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Ballantyne LA, Lambkin C (2000) Lampyridae of Australia (Coleoptera: Lampyridae: Luciolinae: Luciolini). Memoirs of the Queensland Museum 46: 15–93.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref11"><issn>00430439</issn><journal_title>J Wash Acad Sci</journal_title><author>Barber</author><volume>37</volume><first_page>242</first_page><cYear>1947</cYear><article_title>A new Schematiza on Cordia in Trinidad (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Barber HS (1947a) A new Schematiza on Cordia in Trinidad (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae). Journal of the Washington Academy of Sciences 37: 242–243.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref12"><issn>00138797</issn><journal_title>Proc Entomol Soc Wash</journal_title><author>Barber</author><volume>49</volume><first_page>151</first_page><cYear>1947</cYear><article_title>Diabrotica and two new genera (Coleoptera, Chrysomelidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Barber HS (1947b) Diabrotica and two new genera (Coleoptera, Chrysomelidae). Proceedings of the Entomological Society of Washington 49: 151–161.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref13"><journal_title>Entomologische Arbeiten</journal_title><author>Bechyné</author><volume>4</volume><first_page>26</first_page><cYear>1953</cYear><article_title>Katalog der neotropischen Eumolpiden (Col. Phytoph. Chrysomeloidea).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bechyné J (1953) Katalog der neotropischen Eumolpiden (Col. Phytoph. Chrysomeloidea). Entomologische Arbeiten 4: 26–303.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref14"><journal_title>Fragmenta Entomologica</journal_title><author>Bellamy</author><volume>29</volume><first_page>365</first_page><cYear>1997</cYear><article_title>A clarification of authorship of buprestid genera originally defined in the catalogues of P.F.M.A. Dejean (Coleoptera, Buprestidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bellamy CL (1997) A clarification of authorship of buprestid genera originally defined in the catalogues of P.F.M.A. Dejean (Coleoptera, Buprestidae). Fragmenta Entomologica 29: 365–382.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref15"><journal_title>United States National Museum Bulletin</journal_title><author>Blackwelder</author><volume>185</volume><first_page>343</first_page><cYear>1945</cYear><article_title>Checklist of the coleopterous insects of Mexico, Central America, the West Indies, and South America.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Blackwelder RE (1945) Checklist of the coleopterous insects of Mexico, Central America, the West Indies, and South America. United States National Museum Bulletin 185: 343–550.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref15"><doi>10.5479/si.00963801.82-2969.1</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref15"><doi>10.5479/si.00963801.103-3319.121</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref16"><journal_title>Annales Zoologici (Warszawa)</journal_title><author>Bocák</author><volume>48</volume><first_page>245</first_page><cYear>1998</cYear><article_title>Nomenclatural notes on taxa of the family Lycidae described by Guérin Méneville (Insecta: Coleoptera).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bocák L (1998) Nomenclatural notes on taxa of the family Lycidae described by Guérin Méneville (Insecta: Coleoptera). Annales Zoologici (Warszawa) 48: 245–251.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref16"><doi>10.1163/187631208788784101</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref17"><author>Borchmann</author><cYear>1910</cYear><volume_title>Coleopterorum Catalogus auspiciis et auxilio W Junk editus a S Schenkling Pars 2</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Borchmann F (1910) Coleopterorum Catalogus auspiciis et auxilio W. Junk editus a S. Schenkling. Pars 2. Nilionidae, Othniidae, Aegialitidae, Petriidae, Lagriidae. W. Junk, Berlin. 32 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref18"><author>Borowiec</author><cYear>1999</cYear><volume_title>A world catalogue of the Cassidinae (Coleoptera Chrysomelidae)</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Borowiec L (1999) A world catalogue of the Cassidinae (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae). Biologica Silesiae, Wrocław, 476 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref18"><doi>10.3897/zookeys.88.807</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref19"><journal_title>Annales Zoologici (Warszawa)</journal_title><author>Bouchard</author><volume>55</volume><first_page>499</first_page><cYear>2005</cYear><article_title>Synoptic classification of the world Tenebrionidae (Insecta: Coleoptera) with a review of family-group names.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bouchard P, Lawrence JF, Davies A, Newton AF (2005) Synoptic classification of the world Tenebrionidae (Insecta: Coleoptera) with a review of family-group names. Annales Zoologici (Warszawa) 55: 499–530.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><journal_title>Annales Zoologici (Warszawa)</journal_title><author>Bouchard</author><volume>57</volume><first_page>385</first_page><cYear>2007</cYear><article_title>Nomenclatural notes on tenebrionid beetles of the Palaearctic Region (Insecta, Coleoptera).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bouchard P, Löbl O, Merkl O (2007) Nomenclatural notes on tenebrionid beetles of the Palaearctic Region (Insecta, Coleoptera). Annales Zoologici (Warszawa) 57: 385–394.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref21"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Bouchard</author><volume>1972</volume><first_page>65</first_page><cYear>2009</cYear><article_title>Proposed conservation of the name Penthe Newman, 1838 (Coleoptera: Tetratomidae: Penthinae) threatened by the discovery of an older available name.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bouchard P, Pollock DA (2009) Proposed conservation of the name Penthe Newman, 1838 (Coleoptera: Tetratomidae: Penthinae) threatened by the discovery of an older available name. Zootaxa 1972: 65–68.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref22"><journal_title>Fabreries</journal_title><author>Bousquet</author><volume>29</volume><first_page>33</first_page><cYear>2004</cYear><article_title>The works of P.F.M.A. Dejean, with emphasis on publication dates and new carabid taxa proposed.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bousquet Y (2004) The works of P.F.M.A. Dejean, with emphasis on publication dates and new carabid taxa proposed. Fabreries 29: 33–48.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref23"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Branco</author><volume>1453</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2007</cYear><article_title>Scarabaeoidea (Coleoptera) of Portugal: genus-group names and their type species.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Branco T (2007) Scarabaeoidea (Coleoptera) of Portugal: genus-group names and their type species. Zootaxa 1453: 1–31.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref24"><journal_title>Catharsius</journal_title><author>Branco</author><volume>4</volume><first_page>9</first_page><cYear>2011</cYear><article_title>Scarabaeidae de l'Afrique de l'Ouest: les noms du niveau genre et leurs espèces types (Coleoptera).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Branco T (2011) Scarabaeidae de l'Afrique de l'Ouest: les noms du niveau genre et leurs espèces types (Coleoptera). Catharsius 4: 9–25.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref25"><author>Breuning</author><volume>1</volume><first_page>415</first_page><cYear>1950</cYear><volume_title>Longicornia Études et notes sur les longicornes</volume_title><article_title>Revision des Cloniocerini.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Breuning S (1950) Revision des Cloniocerini. In: Lepesme P (Ed.) Longicornia. Études et notes sur les longicornes. Volume 1. Paul Lechevalier, Paris, 415–421.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref26"><journal_title>Bulletin &amp; Annales de la Société Royale d Entomologie de Belgique</journal_title><author>Breuning</author><volume>106</volume><first_page>77</first_page><cYear>1970</cYear><article_title>Revision des Nyctimenini, Hyborhabdini et Zygocerini (Coleoptera, Cerambycidae, Lamiinae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Breuning S (1970) Revision des Nyctimenini, Hyborhabdini et Zygocerini (Coleoptera, Cerambycidae, Lamiinae). Bulletin &amp; Annales de la Société Royale d'Entomologie de Belgique 106: 77–117.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref27"><journal_title>Bulletin de l Institut Fondamental d Afrique Noire</journal_title><author>Breuning</author><volume>41</volume><first_page>366</first_page><cYear>1980</cYear><article_title>Révision des Acmocerini Thomson et données bionomiques les concernant (Coleoptera Cerambycidae Lamiinae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Breuning S, Teocchi P (1980) Révision des Acmocerini Thomson et données bionomiques les concernant (Coleoptera Cerambycidae Lamiinae). Bulletin de l'Institut Fondamental d'Afrique Noire 41: 366–407.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref28"><journal_title>Zeitschrift für die Entomologie</journal_title><author>Burmeister</author><volume>2</volume><first_page>353</first_page><cYear>1840</cYear><article_title>Kritische Revision der Lamellicornia melitophila. Erstes Stück. Trichiadae.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Burmeister H, Schaum H (1840) Kritische Revision der Lamellicornia melitophila. Erstes Stück. Trichiadae. Zeitschrift für die Entomologie 2: 353–420.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><journal_title>Proceedings of the Washington Academy of Sciences</journal_title><author>Casey</author><volume>11</volume><first_page>47</first_page><cYear>1909</cYear><article_title>Studies in the American Buprestidae.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Casey TL (1909) Studies in the American Buprestidae. Proceedings of the Washington Academy of Sciences 11: 47–178.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><author>Chapuis</author><cYear>1875</cYear><volume_title>Histoire naturelle des insectes Genera des coléoptères ou exposé méthodique et critique de tous les genres proposées jusqu ici dans cet ordre d insectes Par Mm Th Lacordaire et F Chapuis Tome onzième Famille des phytophages</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Chapuis F (1875) Histoire naturelle des insectes. Genera des coléoptères ou exposé méthodique et critique de tous les genres proposées jusqu'ici dans cet ordre d'insectes. Par Mm. Th. Lacordaire et F. Chapuis. Tome onzième. Famille des phytophages. Roret, Paris, 420 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><issn>00310603</issn><journal_title>Pan-Pac Entomol</journal_title><author>Chemsak</author><volume>40</volume><first_page>231</first_page><cYear>1964</cYear><article_title>Type species of generic names applied to North American Lepturinae (Coleoptera: Cerambycidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Chemsak JA (1964) Type species of generic names applied to North American Lepturinae (Coleoptera: Cerambycidae). The Pan-Pacific Entomologist 40: 231–237.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref32"><author>Chevrolat</author><first_page>361</first_page><cYear>1836</cYear><volume_title>Catalogue des Coléoptères de la collection de M le Comte Dejean</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Chevrolat LAA (1836) [new taxa]. In: Dejean PFMA. Catalogue des Coléoptères de la collection de M. le Comte Dejean. [Livraison 5]. Méquignon-Marvis, Paris, 361–443.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><author>Chevrolat</author><cYear>1846</cYear><volume_title>Dictionnaire universel d histoire naturelle… Tome septième MM</volume_title><article_title>Lygistopterus.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Chevrolat LAA (1846) Lygistopterus. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.) Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle… Tome septième. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, 515 p.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Aalbu RL, Triplehorn CA, Campbell JM, Brown KW, Somerby RE, Thomas DB (2002a) Tenebrionidae Latreille 1802. In: Arnett RH Jr, Thomas MC, Skelley PE, Frank JH (Eds) American Beetles Volume 2 Polyphaga: Scarabaeoidea through Curculionoidea. CRC Press, New York, 463–509.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Adlbauer K, Danilevsky ML, Hubweber L, Löbl I, Morati J, Rapuzzi P, Sama G, Smetana A, Weigel A (2010) Family Cerambycidae [excluding subfamily Prioninae, subfamily Apatophyseinae, and tribe Dorcadionini]. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 6. Chrysomeloidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 84–86, 95–241, 264–334.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Aurivillius C (1922) Coleopterorum Catalogus auspiciis et auxilio W. Junk editus a S. Schenkling. Pars 73: Cerambycidae: Lamiinae I. W. Junk, Berlin, 322 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Barber HS (1951) North American fireflies of the genus Photuris. With preface and notes by F.A. McDermott. Smithsonian Miscellaneous Collections No 117. vi + 58 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Batelka J (2008) Family Ripiphoridae Gemminger &amp; Harold, 1870. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 5. Tenebrionoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 73–78.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Beenen R (2010) Subfamily Galerucinae Latreille, 1802. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 6. Chrysomeloidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 443–491.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Bellamy CL (2008a) A world catalogue and bibliography of the jewel beetles (Coleoptera: Buprestoidea). Volume 1. Introduction; fossil taxa; Schizopodidae; Buprestidae: Julodinae - Chrysochroinae: Poecilonotini. Pensoft, Sofia–Moscow, 625 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Bellamy CL (2008b) A world catalogue and bibliography of the jewel beetles (Coleoptera: Buprestoidea). Volume 2. Chrysochroinae: Sphenopterini through Buprestinae: Stigmoderini. Pensoft, Sofia-Moscow, 632–1260.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Bellamy CL (2008c) A world catalogue and bibliography of the jewel beetles (Coleoptera: Buprestoidea). Volume 3. Buprestinae: Pterobothrini through Agrilinae: Rhaeboscelina. Pensoft, Sofia-Moscow, 1265–1931.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Bellamy CL (2008d) A world catalogue and bibliography of the jewel beetles (Coleoptera: Buprestoidea). Volume 4. Agrilinae: Agrilina through Trachyini. Pensoft, Sofia–Moscow, 1935–2684.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Bellamy CL (2008e) A world catalogue and bibliography of the jewel beetles (Coleoptera: Buprestoidea). Volume 5. Appendices, bibliography, indices. Pensoft, Sofia-Moscow, 2689–3264.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Bezděk A (2006a) New nomenclatorial and taxonomic acts, and comments. Scarabaeidae: Melolonthinae [p. 33]. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 3. Scarabaeoidea - Scirtoidea - Dascilloidea - Buprestoidea - Byrrhoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 690 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Bezděk A (2006b) Tribe Leucopholini Burmeister, 1855. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 3. Scarabaeoidea - Scirtoidea - Dascilloidea - Buprestoidea - Byrrhoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 190–191.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Bezděk A, Krell FT (2006) Tribe Onitini Laporte, 1840. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 3. Scarabaeoidea - Scirtoidea - Dascilloidea - Buprestoidea - Byrrhoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 158–159.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Bezzi M (1902) Neue Namen für einige Dipteren-Gattungen. Zeitschrift für systematische Hymenopterologie und Dipterologie 2: 190–192.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Bickhardt H (1916) Genera insectorum publiés par P. Wytsman. Coleoptera. Fam. Histeridae. 166a Fascicule. V. Verteneuil &amp; L. Desmet, Bruxelles, 112 pp. + 15 pls.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Blanchard CE (1845) Histoire des insectes, traitant de leurs moeurs et de leurs métamorphoses en général et comprenant une nouvelle classification fondée sur leurs rapports naturels. Coléoptères, Orthoptères, Thysanoptères, Neuroptères, Lépidoptères, Hémiptères, Aphaniptères, Strepsiptères, Diptères, Anoplures et Thysanures. Firmin Didot frères, Paris, 524 pp. + pls 11–20.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Boheman KH (1854) Monographia cassididarum. Tomus secundus cum Tab. II. Norstedtiana, Holmiae, 506 pp. + pls 5–6.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Boisduval JBA (1835) Voyage de découvertes de l'Astrolabe exécuté par ordre du Roi, pendant les années 1826-1827-1828-1829, sous le commandement de M. J. Dumont d'Urville. Faune entomologique de l'Océan Pacifique, avec l'illustration des insectes nouveaux receuillis pendant le voyage. Deuxième partie. Coléoptères et autres ordres. J. Tatsu, Paris. vii + 716 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Boisduval JBA (1846) Notice sur M. le Comte Dejean. Annales de la Société Entomologique de France (deuxième série) 3[1845]: 499–520.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Bologna MA (2008) Family Meloidae Gyllenhal, 1810. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 5. Tenebrionoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 370–412.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Borchmann F (1936) Genera insectorum publiés par P. Wytsman. Coleoptera Heteromera. Fam. Lagriidae. 204me Fascicule. Louis Desmet-Verteneuil, Bruxelles, 561 pp. + 9 pls.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Borowiec L, Sekerka L (2010) Subfamily Cassidinae Gyllenhal, 1813. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 6. Chrysomeloidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 368–390.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Breuning S (1959) Catalogue des Lamiaires du monde (Col. Céramb.). 2. Lieferung. Verlag des Museums G. Frey, Tutzing bei München, pp. 49–107.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Breuning S (1961) Catalogue des Lamiaires du monde (Col. Céramb.). 4. Lieferung. Verlag des Museums G. Frey, Tutzing bei München, pp. 183–284.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Breuning S (1962) Catalogue des Lamiaires du monde (Col. Céramb.). 6. Lieferung. Verlag des Museums G. Frey, Tutzing bei München, pp. 387–459.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Cassis G, Weir TA (1992) Scarabaeinae. In: Houston WWK (Ed.) Zoological catalogue of Australia. Vol. 9 Coleoptera: Scarabaeidae. AGPS Press, Canberra, 106–173.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Cate PC (2007) Family Elateridae Leach, 1815 [minus Cebrioninae, Lissominae, Subprotelaterinae]. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 4. Elateroidea - Derodontoidea - Bostrichoidea - Lymexyloidea - Cleroidea - Cucujoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 94–209.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Chapuis F (1874) Histoire naturelle des insectes. Genera des coléoptères ou exposé méthodique et critique de tous les genres proposées jusqu'ici dans cet ordre d'insectes. Par Mm. Th. Lacordaire et F. Chapuis. Tome dixième. Famille des phytophages. Roret, Paris, iv + 455 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Chevrolat LAA (1842) Blepharida [p. 606]. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.) Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle résumant et complétant tous les faits présentés par les encyclopédies, les anciens dictionnaires scientifiques, les oeuvres complètes de Buffon, et les meilleurs traités spéciaux sur les diverses branches des sciences naturelles; donnant la description des êtres et des divers phénomènes de la nature, l'étymologie et la définition des noms scientifiques, les principales applications des corps organiques et inorganiques, à l'agriculture, à la médecine, aux arts industriels, etc. Tome deuxième. [Livraisons 18–24]. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, ?321–795.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Chevrolat LAA (1843) Chrysomélines [pp. 654–657]. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.) Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle… Tome troisième. [Livraisons 30–36]. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, ?297–744.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Chevrolat LAA (1844) Diphaulaca [p. 46]. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.) Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle… Tome cinquième. [Livraisons 49–56]. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, 1–?488.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><unstructured_citation>Chevrolat LAA (1845) Galérucites; Gastrophysa; Graptodera; Hippodamia. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.) Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle… Tome sixième. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, 4–6, 34, 307, 622–623.</unstructured_citation></citation>
</citation_list>
</doi_citations>
</body>
</doi_batch>
