<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doi_batch version="4.3.0" xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/doi_resources_schema/4.3.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/doi_resources_schema/4.3.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/deposit/doi_resources4.3.0.xsd">
<head>
<doi_batch_id>cc020d86-f66c-4544-9951-4a4dcc0312db</doi_batch_id>
<depositor>
<name>pens</name>
<email_address>bozhin.karaivanov@gmail.com</email_address>
</depositor>
</head>
<body>
<doi_citations>
<doi>part-4-282-4401</doi>
<citation_list>
	<citation key="ref1"><author>Krajčik</author><cYear>2001</cYear><volume_title>Lucanidae of the world Catalogue - Part I Checklist of the stag beetles of the world (Coleoptera Lucanidae)</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Krajčik M (2001) Lucanidae of the world. Catalogue - Part I. Checklist of the stag beetles of the world (Coleoptera: Lucanidae). Most (Czech Republic), 108 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref2"><journal_title>Entomologische Blätter</journal_title><author>Krell</author><volume>98</volume><first_page>37</first_page><cYear>2002</cYear><article_title>On nomenclature and synonymy of Old World Dynastinae (Coleoptera, Scarabaeidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Krell FT (2002) On nomenclature and synonymy of Old World Dynastinae (Coleoptera, Scarabaeidae). Entomologische Blätter 98: 37–46.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref2"><doi>10.1649/952.1</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref3"><journal_title>Annales des Sciences Naturelles</journal_title><author>Lacordaire</author><volume>20</volume><first_page>185</first_page><cYear>1830</cYear><article_title>Mémoire sur les habitudes des insectes coléoptères de l'Amérique méridionale.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Lacordaire JT (1830) Mémoire sur les habitudes des insectes coléoptères de l'Amérique méridionale. Annales des Sciences Naturelles 20: 185–291.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref4"><author>Lacordaire</author><cYear>1857</cYear><volume_title>Histoire naturelle des insectes Genera des Coléoptères ou exposé méthodique et critique de tous les genres proposés jusqu ici dans cet ordre d insectes Tome quatrième contenant les familles des buprestides throscides eucnémides élatérides cébrionides cérophytides rhipicérides dascyllides malacodermes clérides lyméxylones cupésides ptiniores bostrichides et cissides</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Lacordaire JT (1857) Histoire naturelle des insectes. Genera des Coléoptères ou exposé méthodique et critique de tous les genres proposés jusqu'ici dans cet ordre d'insectes. Tome quatrième contenant les familles des buprestides, throscides, eucnémides, élatérides, cébrionides, cérophytides, rhipicérides, dascyllides, malacodermes, clérides, lyméxylones, cupésides, ptiniores, bostrichides et cissides. Roret, Paris, 579 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref5"><author>Lacordaire</author><cYear>1868</cYear><volume_title>Histoire naturelle des insectes Genera des Coléoptères ou exposé méthodique et critique de tous les genres proposés jusqu ici dans cet ordre d insectes Tome huitième contenant les familles des tricténotomides et des longicornes</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Lacordaire JT (1868) Histoire naturelle des insectes. Genera des Coléoptères ou exposé méthodique et critique de tous les genres proposés jusqu'ici dans cet ordre d'insectes. Tome huitième contenant les familles des tricténotomides et des longicornes. Roret, Paris, 552 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref6"><journal_title>Faune de Madagascar</journal_title><author>Lacroix</author><volume>73</volume><first_page>303</first_page><cYear>1993</cYear><article_title>Insectes coléoptères, Melolonthidae (2e partie).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Lacroix M (1993) Insectes coléoptères, Melolonthidae (2e partie). Faune de Madagascar 73. Pp. 303–875.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref7"><author>Lacroix</author><cYear>2007</cYear><volume_title>Pachydeminae du monde (Scarabaeoidea Melolonthidae) Genera et catalogue</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Lacroix M (2007) Pachydeminae du monde (Scarabaeoidea, Melolonthidae). Genera et catalogue. Collection Hannetons, Paris, 450 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref8"><journal_title>Revue Entomologique</journal_title><author>Laporte</author><volume>4</volume><first_page>5</first_page><cYear>1836</cYear><article_title>Études entomologiques, ou descriptions d'insectes nouveaux et observations sur la synonymie.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Laporte FLN (1836) Études entomologiques, ou descriptions d'insectes nouveaux et observations sur la synonymie. Revue Entomologique 4: 5–60.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref9"><author>Laporte</author><cYear>1840</cYear><volume_title>Histoire naturelle des insectes Coléoptères avec une introduction renfermant l anatomie et la physiologie des animaux articulés par M Brullé Tome deuxième</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Laporte FLN (1840) Histoire naturelle des insectes Coléoptères; avec une introduction renfermant l'anatomie et la physiologie des animaux articulés, par M. Brullé. Tome deuxième. P. Duménil, Paris, 563 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref10"><author>Latreille</author><cYear>1825</cYear><volume_title>Familles naturelles du règne animal exposées succinctement et dans un ordre analytique avec l indication de leurs genres J -B Baillière</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Latreille PA (1825) Familles naturelles du règne animal, exposées succinctement et dans un ordre analytique, avec l'indication de leurs genres. J.-B. Baillière [&amp;] Baudouin Frères, Paris. 570 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref11"><doi>10.1111/j.1365-3113.2012.00661.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref12"><author>von Linnaeus</author><cYear>1758</cYear><volume_title>Systema naturae per regna tria naturae secundum classes ordines genera species cum characteribus differentiis synonymis locis Editio decima reformata Tomus I Laurentii Salvii</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Linnaeus C von (1758) Systema naturae per regna tria naturae, secundum classes, ordines, genera, species, cum characteribus, differentiis, synonymis, locis. Editio decima, reformata. Tomus I. Laurentii Salvii, Holmiae, 823 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref13"><author>Linsley</author><volume>19</volume><cYear>1962</cYear><volume_title>The Cerambycidae of North America Part II Taxonomy and classification of the Parandrinae Prioninae Spondylinae and Aseminae</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Linsley EG (1962) The Cerambycidae of North America. Part II. Taxonomy and classification of the Parandrinae, Prioninae, Spondylinae, and Aseminae. University of California Publications in Entomology Volume 19. 102 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref14"><author>Lopatin</author><cYear>1977</cYear><volume_title>Leaf beetles (Chrysomelidae) of Central Asia and Kazakhstan</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Lopatin I (1977) Leaf beetles (Chrysomelidae) of Central Asia and Kazakhstan. Nauka, Leningrad, 268 pp. [in Russian]</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref14"><doi>10.3366/anh.1988.15.3.317</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref15"><author>Mahul</author><cYear>1869</cYear><volume_title>L entomologie en cent distiques dédiée aux jeunes garçons avec une préface également en vers contenant la biographie comme naturaliste du général Comte Dejean son père</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Mahul SE (1869) L'entomologie en cent distiques dédiée aux jeunes garçons avec une préface également en vers, contenant la biographie, comme naturaliste, du général Comte Dejean, son père. Héritiers Botta, Florence. 159 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref16"><journal_title>Revue de Zoologie Africaine</journal_title><author>Mal</author><volume>99</volume><first_page>195</first_page><cYear>1985</cYear><article_title>Description d'une espèce nouvelle du genre Odontopezus Alluaud, 1889 (Coleoptera, Tenebrionidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Mal N (1985) Description d'une espèce nouvelle du genre Odontopezus Alluaud, 1889 (Coleoptera, Tenebrionidae). Revue de Zoologie Africaine 99: 195–196.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref17"><journal_title>Bulletin de la Société Impériale des Naturalistes de Moscou</journal_title><author>Mannerheim</author><volume>15</volume><first_page>864</first_page><cYear>1842</cYear><article_title>Notice sur la c.d. collection de coléoptères de M. le Comte Dejean.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Mannerheim CG (1842) Notice sur la c.d. collection de coléoptères de M. le Comte Dejean. Bulletin de la Société Impériale des Naturalistes de Moscou 15: 864–870.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref18"><journal_title>Dusenia</journal_title><author>Marinoni</author><volume>10</volume><first_page>37</first_page><cYear>1977</cYear><article_title>Some genera of Lamiinae and their type-species (Coleoptera-Cerambycidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Marinoni RC (1977) Some genera of Lamiinae and their type-species (Coleoptera-Cerambycidae). Dusenia 10: 37–55.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref19"><journal_title>L Abeille</journal_title><author>Marseul</author><volume>1</volume><first_page>xli</first_page><cYear>1864</cYear><article_title>Bibliographie.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Marseul SA (1864) Bibliographie. L'Abeille 1: xli–lx.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><author>Maulik</author><cYear>1926</cYear><volume_title>The fauna of British India including Ceylon and Burma Coleoptera Chrysomelidae (Chrysomelinae and Halticinae)</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Maulik S (1926) The fauna of British India, including Ceylon and Burma. Coleoptera. Chrysomelidae (Chrysomelinae and Halticinae). Taylor and Francis, London, 442 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref21"><author>Mazur</author><cYear>2011</cYear><volume_title>A concise catalogue of the Histeridae (Insecta Coleoptera)</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Mazur S (2011) A concise catalogue of the Histeridae (Insecta: Coleoptera). Warsaw University of Life Sciences–SGGW Press, Warsaw, 332 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref21"><doi>10.3853/j.0067-1967.10.1947.477</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref21"><doi>10.1163/187631205788838500</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref22"><author>Medvedev</author><cYear>1949</cYear><volume_title>Fauna SSSR Coleoptera 10 (3) Lamellicornia (Scarabaeidae) subfamily Rutelinae (cereal beetles and related groups)</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Medvedev SI (1949) Fauna SSSR. Coleoptera 10 (3): Lamellicornia (Scarabaeidae) subfamily Rutelinae (cereal beetles and related groups) [in Russian]. Academia Nauk SSSR, Moscou &amp; Leningrad. 372 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref23"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Monné</author><volume>3213</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2012</cYear><article_title>Catalogue of the type-species of the genera of the Cerambycidae, Disteniidae, Oxypeltidae and Vesperidae (Coleoptera) of the Neotropical Region.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Monné MA (2012) Catalogue of the type-species of the genera of the Cerambycidae, Disteniidae, Oxypeltidae and Vesperidae (Coleoptera) of the Neotropical Region. Zootaxa 3213: 1–183.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref24"><author>Monné</author><cYear>2009</cYear><volume_title>Checklist of the Cerambycidae or longhorned wood-boring beetles of the Western Hemisphere</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Monné MA, Bezark LG (2009) Checklist of the Cerambycidae, or longhorned wood-boring beetles, of the Western Hemisphere. BioQuip Publications, Rancho Dominguez (CA), [1] + 482 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref25"><journal_title>Insecta Mundi</journal_title><author>Monné</author><volume>6</volume><first_page>249</first_page><cYear>1992</cYear><article_title>Nomenclatural notes on Western Hemisphere Cerambycidae (Coleoptera).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Monné MA, Giesbert EF (1992) Nomenclatural notes on Western Hemisphere Cerambycidae (Coleoptera). Insecta Mundi 6: 249–255.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref26"><journal_title>Bulletin</journal_title><author>Monrós</author><volume>7</volume><first_page>45</first_page><cYear>1953</cYear><article_title>Some corrections in the nomenclature of Clytrinae (Chrysomelidae). The Coleopterists'</article_title><unstructured_citation>Monrós F (1953) Some corrections in the nomenclature of Clytrinae (Chrysomelidae). The Coleopterists' Bulletin 7: 45–50.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref27"><journal_title>Frey</journal_title><author>Monrós</author><volume>7</volume><first_page>1118</first_page><cYear>1956</cYear><article_title>Über einige verkannte Chrysomeliden-Namen. Entomologische Arbeiten aus dem Museum G.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Monrós F, Bechyné J (1956) Über einige verkannte Chrysomeliden-Namen. Entomologische Arbeiten aus dem Museum G. Frey 7: 1118–1137.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref28"><journal_title>Etudes Entomologiques</journal_title><author>Motschulsky</author><volume>1</volume><first_page>25</first_page><cYear>1853</cYear><article_title>Lampyrides.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Motschulsky V (1853) Lampyrides. Etudes Entomologiques 1: 25–58.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><issn>00075167</issn><journal_title>Bull Zool Nomencl</journal_title><author>Mühle</author><volume>50</volume><first_page>27</first_page><cYear>1993</cYear><article_title>Case 2837/1. Poecilonota Eschscholtz, 1829, Palmar Schaefer, 1949 and Scintillatrix Obenberger, 1956 (Insecta, Coleoptera): proposed conservation by the designation of Buprestis variolosa Paykull, [1799] as the type species of Poecilonota and B. rutilans Fabricius, [1777] as the type species of Scintillatrix.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Mühle H (1993) Case 2837/1. Poecilonota Eschscholtz, 1829, Palmar Schaefer, 1949 and Scintillatrix Obenberger, 1956 (Insecta, Coleoptera): proposed conservation by the designation of Buprestis variolosa Paykull, [1799] as the type species of Poecilonota and B. rutilans Fabricius, [1777] as the type species of Scintillatrix. Bulletin of Zoological Nomenclature 50: 27–30.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><doi>10.1163/187631289X00348</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><author>Olivier</author><cYear>1795</cYear><volume_title>Entomologie ou histoire naturelle des insectes avec leurs caractères génériques et spécifiques leur description leur synonymie et leur figure enluminée Coléoptères Tome quatrième</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Olivier GA (1795) Entomologie, ou histoire naturelle des insectes, avec leurs caractères génériques et spécifiques, leur description, leur synonymie, et leur figure enluminée. Coléoptères. Tome quatrième. Baudouin, Paris.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><journal_title>Journal of Afrotropical Zoology</journal_title><author>Opitz</author><volume>7</volume><first_page>29</first_page><cYear>2011</cYear><article_title>Classification, natural history, and evolution of Korynetinae Laporte (Coleoptera: Cleridae). Part I. Generic composition of the subfamily and key to genera.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Opitz W (2011) Classification, natural history, and evolution of Korynetinae Laporte (Coleoptera: Cleridae). Part I. Generic composition of the subfamily and key to genera. Journal of Afrotropical Zoology 7: 29–67.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><unstructured_citation>Kovář I (2007) Family Coccinellidae Latreille, 1807. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 4. Elateroidea - Derodontoidea - Bostrichoidea - Lymexyloidea - Cleroidea - Cucujoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 568–631.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><unstructured_citation>Král D, Smetana A (2006) Tribe Adoretini Burmeister, 1844. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 3. Scarabaeoidea - Scirtoidea - Dascilloidea - Buprestoidea - Byrrhoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 248–251.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><unstructured_citation>Krell FT (2006) Subfamily Dynastinae MacLeay, 1819. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 3. Scarabaeoidea - Scirtoidea - Dascilloidea - Buprestoidea - Byrrhoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 277–283.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><unstructured_citation>Kurosawa Y (1982) A remarkable convergence found in Malayan buprestid beetles, with description of two new species from Thailand and Hainan. Bulletin of the National Science Museum (Series A, Zoology) 8: 173–204.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><unstructured_citation>Lawrence JF, Weir TA, Pyke JE (1987) Haliplidae, Hygrobiidae, Noteridae, Dytiscidae and Gyrinidae. In: Houston K, Richardson B (Eds) Zoological catalogue of Australia. Volume 4. Coleoptera: Archostemata, Myxophaga and Adephaga. Australian Government Publishing service, Canberra, 321–366.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><unstructured_citation>Leschen RAB, Skelley PE (2002) Languriidae Wiedeman 1823. In: Arnett RH Jr, Thomas MC, Skelley PE, Frank JH (Eds) American Beetles Volume 2 Polyphaga: Scarabaeoidea through Curculionoidea. CRC Press, New York, 343–347.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><unstructured_citation>Linnaeus C von (1767) Systema naturae per regna tria naturae, secundum classes, ordines, genera, species, cum characteribus, differentiis, synonymis, locis. Editio duodecima, reformata. Tom. I. Pars II. Laurentii Salvii, Holmiae, 533–1327.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><unstructured_citation>Lloyd JE (2002) Lampyridae Latreille 1817. In: Arnett RH Jr, Thomas MC, Skelley PE, Frank JH (Eds) American Beetles Volume 2 Polyphaga: Scarabaeoidea through Curculionoidea. CRC Press, New York, 187–196.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><unstructured_citation>Löbl I, Bouchard P, Merkl O, Iwan D (2008a) New nomenclatorial and taxonomic acts, and comments. Tenebrionidae. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 5. Tenebrionoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 40–45.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><unstructured_citation>Löbl I, Ando K, Bouchard P, Egorov LV, Iwan D, Lillig M, Masumoto K, Merkl O, Nabozhenko M, Novák V, Petterson R, Schawaller W, Soldati F (2008b) Family Tenebrionidae Latreille, 1802. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 5. Tenebrionoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 105–352.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><unstructured_citation>Löbl I, Smetana A (2011) Errata. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 7. Curculionoidea I. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 23–63.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><unstructured_citation>Lopatin I, Smetana A, Schöller M (2010) Genus Cryptocephalus Geoffroy, 1762. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 6. Chrysomeloidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 580–606.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><unstructured_citation>López-Colón JI (2006) Subfamily Orphninae Erichson, 1847. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 3. Scarabaeoidea - Scirtoidea - Dascilloidea - Buprestoidea - Byrrhoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 179–180.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><unstructured_citation>Machatschke JW (1972) Scarabaeoidea: Melolonthidae Rutelinae. Coleopterorum Catalogus Supplementa edita a J.A. Wilcox. Pars 66 Fasc. 1 (Editio Secunda). Uitgeverij Dr. W. Junk, 's-Gravenhage, 361 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><unstructured_citation>Mazzoldi P (2003) Family Gyrinidae Latreille, 1810. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 1. Archostemata - Myxophaga - Adephaga. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 26–30.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><unstructured_citation>McDermot FA (1966) Coleopterorum Catalogus Supplementa edita a W.O. Steel. Pars 9 (Editio Secunda). Lampyridae. Dr. W. Junk, 's-Gravenhage, 149 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><unstructured_citation>Miller RS (2002) Lycidae Laporte 1836. In: Arnett RH Jr, Thomas MC, Skelley PE, Frank JH (Eds) American Beetles Volume 2 Polyphaga: Scarabaeoidea through Curculionoidea. CRC Press, New York, 174–178.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><unstructured_citation>Montrouzier X (1856) Essai sur la faune de l'ile de Woodlark ou Moiou. Annales des Sciences Physiques et Naturelles, d'Agriculture et d'Industrie (deuxième série) 7(1) [1855]: 1–114.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><unstructured_citation>Moseyko AG, Sprecher-Uebersax E (2010) Subfamily Eumolpinae Hope, 1840. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 6. Chrysomeloidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 619–643.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><unstructured_citation>Motschulsky V (1860) Coléoptères de la Sibérie orientale et en particulier des rives de l'Amour. In: Reisen und Forschungen im Amur-Lande in den Jahren 1854-1856 im Auftrage der Kaiserl. Akademie der Wissenschaften zu St. Petersburg ausgeführt und in Verbindung mit mehreren Gelehrten herausgegeben von Dr Leopold v. Schrenck. Zweiter Band. Zoologie: Lepidopteren, Coleopteren, Mollusken. Eggers und Comp., H. Schmitzdorff und Jacques Issakof, St-Pétersburg, 77–257.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><unstructured_citation>Motschulsky V (1872) Enumération des nouvelles espèces de coléoptères rapportés de ses voyages. 11-ième article. Bulletin de la Société Impériale des Naturalistes de Moscou 45 (seconde partie): 23–55.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><unstructured_citation>Muona J (2007) Family Eucnemidae Eschscholtz, 1829. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 4. Elateroidea - Derodontoidea - Bostrichoidea - Lymexyloidea - Cleroidea - Cucujoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 81–87.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><unstructured_citation>Nilsson AN (2003) Family Dytiscidae Leach, 1815. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 1. Archostemata - Myxophaga - Adephaga. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 35–78.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><unstructured_citation>Nikitsky NB (2008) Family Tetratomidae Billberg, 1820. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 5. Tenebrionoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 62–64.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><unstructured_citation>Opitz W (2002) Cleridae Latreille 1804. In: Arnett RH Jr, Thomas MC, Skelley PE, Frank JH (Eds) American Beetles Volume 2 Polyphaga: Scarabaeoidea through Curculionoidea. CRC Press, New York, 267–280.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><unstructured_citation>Parsons MS, Scoble MJ, Honey MR, Pitkin LM, Pitkin BR (1999) Geometrid moths of the world: a catalogue (Lepidoptera, Geometridae). Volume 1. CSIRO, Collingwood, Victoria, i-xxv + 1–482 + I1–I129.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><unstructured_citation>Penrith ML (1979) Revision of the western southern African Adesmiini (Coleoptera: Tenebrionidae). Cimbebasia (Ser. A) 5(1): 1–94.</unstructured_citation></citation>
</citation_list>
</doi_citations>
</body>
</doi_batch>
