<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doi_batch version="4.3.0" xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/doi_resources_schema/4.3.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/doi_resources_schema/4.3.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/deposit/doi_resources4.3.0.xsd">
<head>
<doi_batch_id>5118b851-23f2-41ee-b482-4681e494b027</doi_batch_id>
<depositor>
<name>pens</name>
<email_address>bozhin.karaivanov@gmail.com</email_address>
</depositor>
</head>
<body>
<doi_citations>
<doi>10.3897/zookeys.282.4401</doi>
<citation_list>
	<citation key="ref1"><author>Aalbu</author><volume>III</volume><first_page>499</first_page><cYear>2002</cYear><volume_title>Biodiversidad taxonomia y biogeografia de arthropodos de Mexico Hacia una sintesis de su conocimiento</volume_title><article_title>Tenebrionidae.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Aalbu RL, Flores GE, Triplehorn CA (2002b) Tenebrionidae. In: Bousquets JL, Morrone JJ (Eds) Biodiversidad, taxonomia y biogeografia de arthropodos de Mexico: Hacia una sintesis de su conocimiento Vol III. Universidad Nacional Autonoma de Mexico, Mexico, 499–512.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref2"><doi>10.1111/j.1365-3113.2005.00307.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref3"><journal_title>Entomologicheskoe Obozrenie</journal_title><author>Aksentjev</author><volume>67</volume><first_page>569</first_page><cYear>1988</cYear><article_title>A catalogue of the genus-group taxa of the beetle family Meloidae (Coleoptera).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Aksentjev SI (1988) A catalogue of the genus-group taxa of the beetle family Meloidae (Coleoptera). Entomologicheskoe Obozrenie 67: 569–582 [English translation in Entomological Review 68: 11–26]</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref4"><author>Alonso-Zarazaga</author><cYear>1999</cYear><volume_title>A world catalogue of families and genera of Curculionoidea (Insecta Coleoptera) (excepting Scolytidae and Platypodidae)</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Alonso-Zarazaga MA, Lyal CHC (1999) A world catalogue of families and genera of Curculionoidea (Insecta: Coleoptera) (excepting Scolytidae and Platypodidae). Entomopraxis, Barcelona, 315 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref5"><journal_title>Zoologia</journal_title><author>Alvarenga</author><volume>2</volume><first_page>75</first_page><cYear>1965</cYear><article_title>Especies tipos dos generos e subgeneros neotropicais da familia Erotylidae (Coleoptera). Boletim da Universidade Federal do Parana</article_title><unstructured_citation>Alvarenga M (1965) Especies tipos dos generos e subgeneros neotropicais da familia Erotylidae (Coleoptera). Boletim da Universidade Federal do Parana, Zoologia 2: 75–92.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref6"><journal_title>Bulletin de la Société Impériale des Naturalistes de Moscou</journal_title><volume>13</volume><first_page>371</first_page><cYear>1840</cYear><article_title>A vendre la collection d'insectes de Mr. le Cte Dejean.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Anonymous (1840a) A vendre la collection d'insectes de Mr. le Cte Dejean. Bulletin de la Société Impériale des Naturalistes de Moscou 13: 371–373.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref7"><cYear>1840</cYear><volume_title>Catalogue de livres la plupart relatifs à l entomologie provenant de la bibliothèque de M le Comte Dejean dont la vente se fera le mercredi 4 novembre et jours suivans six heures de relevée rue des Bons-Enfans n 30</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Anonymous (1840b) Catalogue de livres, la plupart relatifs à l'entomologie, provenant de la bibliothèque de M. le Comte Dejean, dont la vente se fera le mercredi 4 novembre et jours suivans, six heures de relevée, rue des Bons-Enfans, n.30. Silvestre, Paris, 30 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref8"><issn>00430439</issn><journal_title>J Wash Acad Sci</journal_title><author>Arnett</author><volume>40</volume><first_page>217</first_page><cYear>1950</cYear><article_title>Generic names of the beetle family Oedemeridae and their type species.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Arnett RH Jr (1950) Generic names of the beetle family Oedemeridae and their type species. Journal of the Washington Academy of Sciences 40: 217–225.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref9"><issn>00379271</issn><journal_title>Ann Soc Entomol Fr</journal_title><author>Audinet-Serville</author><volume>4</volume><first_page>5</first_page><cYear>1835</cYear><article_title>Nouvelle classification de la famille des longicornes (suite).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Audinet-Serville JG (1835) Nouvelle classification de la famille des longicornes (suite). Annales de la Société Entomologique de France 4: 5–100, 197–228.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref10"><journal_title>Arkiv för Zoologi</journal_title><author>Aurivillius</author><volume>3</volume><issue>18</issue><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1907</cYear><article_title>Neue oder wenig bekannte Coleoptera Longicornia. 9.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Aurivillius C (1907) Neue oder wenig bekannte Coleoptera Longicornia. 9. Arkiv för Zoologi 3(18): 1–38.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref11"><issn>00798835</issn><journal_title>Mem Queensl Mus</journal_title><author>Ballantyne</author><volume>46</volume><first_page>15</first_page><cYear>2000</cYear><article_title>Lampyridae of Australia (Coleoptera: Lampyridae: Luciolinae: Luciolini).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Ballantyne LA, Lambkin C (2000) Lampyridae of Australia (Coleoptera: Lampyridae: Luciolinae: Luciolini). Memoirs of the Queensland Museum 46: 15–93.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref12"><issn>00430439</issn><journal_title>J Wash Acad Sci</journal_title><author>Barber</author><volume>37</volume><first_page>242</first_page><cYear>1947</cYear><article_title>A new Schematiza on Cordia in Trinidad (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Barber HS (1947a) A new Schematiza on Cordia in Trinidad (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae). Journal of the Washington Academy of Sciences 37: 242–243.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref13"><issn>00138797</issn><journal_title>Proc Entomol Soc Wash</journal_title><author>Barber</author><volume>49</volume><first_page>151</first_page><cYear>1947</cYear><article_title>Diabrotica and two new genera (Coleoptera, Chrysomelidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Barber HS (1947b) Diabrotica and two new genera (Coleoptera, Chrysomelidae). Proceedings of the Entomological Society of Washington 49: 151–161.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref14"><journal_title>Entomologische Arbeiten</journal_title><author>Bechyné</author><volume>4</volume><first_page>26</first_page><cYear>1953</cYear><article_title>Katalog der neotropischen Eumolpiden (Col. Phytoph. Chrysomeloidea).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bechyné J (1953) Katalog der neotropischen Eumolpiden (Col. Phytoph. Chrysomeloidea). Entomologische Arbeiten 4: 26–303.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref15"><journal_title>Fragmenta Entomologica</journal_title><author>Bellamy</author><volume>29</volume><first_page>365</first_page><cYear>1997</cYear><article_title>A clarification of authorship of buprestid genera originally defined in the catalogues of P.F.M.A. Dejean (Coleoptera, Buprestidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bellamy CL (1997) A clarification of authorship of buprestid genera originally defined in the catalogues of P.F.M.A. Dejean (Coleoptera, Buprestidae). Fragmenta Entomologica 29: 365–382.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref16"><journal_title>United States National Museum Bulletin</journal_title><author>Blackwelder</author><volume>185</volume><first_page>343</first_page><cYear>1945</cYear><article_title>Checklist of the coleopterous insects of Mexico, Central America, the West Indies, and South America.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Blackwelder RE (1945) Checklist of the coleopterous insects of Mexico, Central America, the West Indies, and South America. United States National Museum Bulletin 185: 343–550.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref17"><doi>10.5479/si.00963801.82-2969.1</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref18"><doi>10.5479/si.00963801.103-3319.121</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref19"><journal_title>Annales Zoologici (Warszawa)</journal_title><author>Bocák</author><volume>48</volume><first_page>245</first_page><cYear>1998</cYear><article_title>Nomenclatural notes on taxa of the family Lycidae described by Guérin Méneville (Insecta: Coleoptera).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bocák L (1998) Nomenclatural notes on taxa of the family Lycidae described by Guérin Méneville (Insecta: Coleoptera). Annales Zoologici (Warszawa) 48: 245–251.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><doi>10.1163/187631208788784101</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref21"><author>Borchmann</author><cYear>1910</cYear><volume_title>Coleopterorum Catalogus auspiciis et auxilio W Junk editus a S Schenkling Pars 2</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Borchmann F (1910) Coleopterorum Catalogus auspiciis et auxilio W. Junk editus a S. Schenkling. Pars 2. Nilionidae, Othniidae, Aegialitidae, Petriidae, Lagriidae. W. Junk, Berlin. 32 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref22"><author>Borowiec</author><cYear>1999</cYear><volume_title>A world catalogue of the Cassidinae (Coleoptera Chrysomelidae)</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Borowiec L (1999) A world catalogue of the Cassidinae (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae). Biologica Silesiae, Wrocław, 476 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref23"><doi>10.3897/zookeys.88.807</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref24"><journal_title>Annales Zoologici (Warszawa)</journal_title><author>Bouchard</author><volume>55</volume><first_page>499</first_page><cYear>2005</cYear><article_title>Synoptic classification of the world Tenebrionidae (Insecta: Coleoptera) with a review of family-group names.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bouchard P, Lawrence JF, Davies A, Newton AF (2005) Synoptic classification of the world Tenebrionidae (Insecta: Coleoptera) with a review of family-group names. Annales Zoologici (Warszawa) 55: 499–530.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref25"><journal_title>Annales Zoologici (Warszawa)</journal_title><author>Bouchard</author><volume>57</volume><first_page>385</first_page><cYear>2007</cYear><article_title>Nomenclatural notes on tenebrionid beetles of the Palaearctic Region (Insecta, Coleoptera).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bouchard P, Löbl O, Merkl O (2007) Nomenclatural notes on tenebrionid beetles of the Palaearctic Region (Insecta, Coleoptera). Annales Zoologici (Warszawa) 57: 385–394.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref26"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Bouchard</author><volume>1972</volume><first_page>65</first_page><cYear>2009</cYear><article_title>Proposed conservation of the name Penthe Newman, 1838 (Coleoptera: Tetratomidae: Penthinae) threatened by the discovery of an older available name.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bouchard P, Pollock DA (2009) Proposed conservation of the name Penthe Newman, 1838 (Coleoptera: Tetratomidae: Penthinae) threatened by the discovery of an older available name. Zootaxa 1972: 65–68.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref27"><journal_title>Fabreries</journal_title><author>Bousquet</author><volume>29</volume><first_page>33</first_page><cYear>2004</cYear><article_title>The works of P.F.M.A. Dejean, with emphasis on publication dates and new carabid taxa proposed.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bousquet Y (2004) The works of P.F.M.A. Dejean, with emphasis on publication dates and new carabid taxa proposed. Fabreries 29: 33–48.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref28"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Branco</author><volume>1453</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2007</cYear><article_title>Scarabaeoidea (Coleoptera) of Portugal: genus-group names and their type species.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Branco T (2007) Scarabaeoidea (Coleoptera) of Portugal: genus-group names and their type species. Zootaxa 1453: 1–31.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><journal_title>Catharsius</journal_title><author>Branco</author><volume>4</volume><first_page>9</first_page><cYear>2011</cYear><article_title>Scarabaeidae de l'Afrique de l'Ouest: les noms du niveau genre et leurs espèces types (Coleoptera).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Branco T (2011) Scarabaeidae de l'Afrique de l'Ouest: les noms du niveau genre et leurs espèces types (Coleoptera). Catharsius 4: 9–25.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><author>Breuning</author><volume>1</volume><first_page>415</first_page><cYear>1950</cYear><volume_title>Longicornia Études et notes sur les longicornes</volume_title><article_title>Revision des Cloniocerini.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Breuning S (1950) Revision des Cloniocerini. In: Lepesme P (Ed.) Longicornia. Études et notes sur les longicornes. Volume 1. Paul Lechevalier, Paris, 415–421.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><journal_title>Bulletin &amp; Annales de la Société Royale d Entomologie de Belgique</journal_title><author>Breuning</author><volume>106</volume><first_page>77</first_page><cYear>1970</cYear><article_title>Revision des Nyctimenini, Hyborhabdini et Zygocerini (Coleoptera, Cerambycidae, Lamiinae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Breuning S (1970) Revision des Nyctimenini, Hyborhabdini et Zygocerini (Coleoptera, Cerambycidae, Lamiinae). Bulletin &amp; Annales de la Société Royale d'Entomologie de Belgique 106: 77–117.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref32"><journal_title>Bulletin de l Institut Fondamental d Afrique Noire</journal_title><author>Breuning</author><volume>41</volume><first_page>366</first_page><cYear>1980</cYear><article_title>Révision des Acmocerini Thomson et données bionomiques les concernant (Coleoptera Cerambycidae Lamiinae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Breuning S, Teocchi P (1980) Révision des Acmocerini Thomson et données bionomiques les concernant (Coleoptera Cerambycidae Lamiinae). Bulletin de l'Institut Fondamental d'Afrique Noire 41: 366–407.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><journal_title>Zeitschrift für die Entomologie</journal_title><author>Burmeister</author><volume>2</volume><first_page>353</first_page><cYear>1840</cYear><article_title>Kritische Revision der Lamellicornia melitophila. Erstes Stück. Trichiadae.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Burmeister H, Schaum H (1840) Kritische Revision der Lamellicornia melitophila. Erstes Stück. Trichiadae. Zeitschrift für die Entomologie 2: 353–420.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref34"><journal_title>Proceedings of the Washington Academy of Sciences</journal_title><author>Casey</author><volume>11</volume><first_page>47</first_page><cYear>1909</cYear><article_title>Studies in the American Buprestidae.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Casey TL (1909) Studies in the American Buprestidae. Proceedings of the Washington Academy of Sciences 11: 47–178.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref35"><author>Chapuis</author><cYear>1875</cYear><volume_title>Histoire naturelle des insectes Genera des coléoptères ou exposé méthodique et critique de tous les genres proposées jusqu ici dans cet ordre d insectes Par Mm Th Lacordaire et F Chapuis Tome onzième Famille des phytophages</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Chapuis F (1875) Histoire naturelle des insectes. Genera des coléoptères ou exposé méthodique et critique de tous les genres proposées jusqu'ici dans cet ordre d'insectes. Par Mm. Th. Lacordaire et F. Chapuis. Tome onzième. Famille des phytophages. Roret, Paris, 420 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref36"><issn>00310603</issn><journal_title>Pan-Pac Entomol</journal_title><author>Chemsak</author><volume>40</volume><first_page>231</first_page><cYear>1964</cYear><article_title>Type species of generic names applied to North American Lepturinae (Coleoptera: Cerambycidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Chemsak JA (1964) Type species of generic names applied to North American Lepturinae (Coleoptera: Cerambycidae). The Pan-Pacific Entomologist 40: 231–237.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref37"><author>Chevrolat</author><first_page>361</first_page><cYear>1836</cYear><volume_title>Catalogue des Coléoptères de la collection de M le Comte Dejean</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Chevrolat LAA (1836) [new taxa]. In: Dejean PFMA. Catalogue des Coléoptères de la collection de M. le Comte Dejean. [Livraison 5]. Méquignon-Marvis, Paris, 361–443.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref38"><author>Chevrolat</author><cYear>1846</cYear><volume_title>Dictionnaire universel d histoire naturelle… Tome septième MM</volume_title><article_title>Lygistopterus.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Chevrolat LAA (1846) Lygistopterus. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.) Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle… Tome septième. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, 515 p.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref39"><unstructured_citation>Aalbu RL, Triplehorn CA, Campbell JM, Brown KW, Somerby RE, Thomas DB (2002a) Tenebrionidae Latreille 1802. In: Arnett RH Jr, Thomas MC, Skelley PE, Frank JH (Eds) American Beetles Volume 2 Polyphaga: Scarabaeoidea through Curculionoidea. CRC Press, New York, 463–509.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref40"><unstructured_citation>Adlbauer K, Danilevsky ML, Hubweber L, Löbl I, Morati J, Rapuzzi P, Sama G, Smetana A, Weigel A (2010) Family Cerambycidae [excluding subfamily Prioninae, subfamily Apatophyseinae, and tribe Dorcadionini]. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 6. Chrysomeloidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 84–86, 95–241, 264–334.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref41"><unstructured_citation>Aurivillius C (1922) Coleopterorum Catalogus auspiciis et auxilio W. Junk editus a S. Schenkling. Pars 73: Cerambycidae: Lamiinae I. W. Junk, Berlin, 322 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref42"><unstructured_citation>Barber HS (1951) North American fireflies of the genus Photuris. With preface and notes by F.A. McDermott. Smithsonian Miscellaneous Collections No 117. vi + 58 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref43"><unstructured_citation>Batelka J (2008) Family Ripiphoridae Gemminger &amp; Harold, 1870. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 5. Tenebrionoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 73–78.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref44"><unstructured_citation>Beenen R (2010) Subfamily Galerucinae Latreille, 1802. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 6. Chrysomeloidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 443–491.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref45"><unstructured_citation>Bellamy CL (2008a) A world catalogue and bibliography of the jewel beetles (Coleoptera: Buprestoidea). Volume 1. Introduction; fossil taxa; Schizopodidae; Buprestidae: Julodinae - Chrysochroinae: Poecilonotini. Pensoft, Sofia–Moscow, 625 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref46"><unstructured_citation>Bellamy CL (2008b) A world catalogue and bibliography of the jewel beetles (Coleoptera: Buprestoidea). Volume 2. Chrysochroinae: Sphenopterini through Buprestinae: Stigmoderini. Pensoft, Sofia-Moscow, 632–1260.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><unstructured_citation>Bellamy CL (2008c) A world catalogue and bibliography of the jewel beetles (Coleoptera: Buprestoidea). Volume 3. Buprestinae: Pterobothrini through Agrilinae: Rhaeboscelina. Pensoft, Sofia-Moscow, 1265–1931.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref48"><unstructured_citation>Bellamy CL (2008d) A world catalogue and bibliography of the jewel beetles (Coleoptera: Buprestoidea). Volume 4. Agrilinae: Agrilina through Trachyini. Pensoft, Sofia–Moscow, 1935–2684.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref49"><unstructured_citation>Bellamy CL (2008e) A world catalogue and bibliography of the jewel beetles (Coleoptera: Buprestoidea). Volume 5. Appendices, bibliography, indices. Pensoft, Sofia-Moscow, 2689–3264.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref50"><unstructured_citation>Bezděk A (2006a) New nomenclatorial and taxonomic acts, and comments. Scarabaeidae: Melolonthinae [p. 33]. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 3. Scarabaeoidea - Scirtoidea - Dascilloidea - Buprestoidea - Byrrhoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 690 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref51"><unstructured_citation>Bezděk A (2006b) Tribe Leucopholini Burmeister, 1855. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 3. Scarabaeoidea - Scirtoidea - Dascilloidea - Buprestoidea - Byrrhoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 190–191.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref52"><unstructured_citation>Bezděk A, Krell FT (2006) Tribe Onitini Laporte, 1840. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 3. Scarabaeoidea - Scirtoidea - Dascilloidea - Buprestoidea - Byrrhoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 158–159.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref53"><unstructured_citation>Bezzi M (1902) Neue Namen für einige Dipteren-Gattungen. Zeitschrift für systematische Hymenopterologie und Dipterologie 2: 190–192.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref54"><unstructured_citation>Bickhardt H (1916) Genera insectorum publiés par P. Wytsman. Coleoptera. Fam. Histeridae. 166a Fascicule. V. Verteneuil &amp; L. Desmet, Bruxelles, 112 pp. + 15 pls.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref55"><unstructured_citation>Blanchard CE (1845) Histoire des insectes, traitant de leurs moeurs et de leurs métamorphoses en général et comprenant une nouvelle classification fondée sur leurs rapports naturels. Coléoptères, Orthoptères, Thysanoptères, Neuroptères, Lépidoptères, Hémiptères, Aphaniptères, Strepsiptères, Diptères, Anoplures et Thysanures. Firmin Didot frères, Paris, 524 pp. + pls 11–20.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref56"><unstructured_citation>Boheman KH (1854) Monographia cassididarum. Tomus secundus cum Tab. II. Norstedtiana, Holmiae, 506 pp. + pls 5–6.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref57"><unstructured_citation>Boisduval JBA (1835) Voyage de découvertes de l'Astrolabe exécuté par ordre du Roi, pendant les années 1826-1827-1828-1829, sous le commandement de M. J. Dumont d'Urville. Faune entomologique de l'Océan Pacifique, avec l'illustration des insectes nouveaux receuillis pendant le voyage. Deuxième partie. Coléoptères et autres ordres. J. Tatsu, Paris. vii + 716 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref58"><unstructured_citation>Boisduval JBA (1846) Notice sur M. le Comte Dejean. Annales de la Société Entomologique de France (deuxième série) 3[1845]: 499–520.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref59"><unstructured_citation>Bologna MA (2008) Family Meloidae Gyllenhal, 1810. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 5. Tenebrionoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 370–412.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref60"><unstructured_citation>Borchmann F (1936) Genera insectorum publiés par P. Wytsman. Coleoptera Heteromera. Fam. Lagriidae. 204me Fascicule. Louis Desmet-Verteneuil, Bruxelles, 561 pp. + 9 pls.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref61"><unstructured_citation>Borowiec L, Sekerka L (2010) Subfamily Cassidinae Gyllenhal, 1813. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 6. Chrysomeloidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 368–390.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref62"><unstructured_citation>Breuning S (1959) Catalogue des Lamiaires du monde (Col. Céramb.). 2. Lieferung. Verlag des Museums G. Frey, Tutzing bei München, pp. 49–107.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref63"><unstructured_citation>Breuning S (1961) Catalogue des Lamiaires du monde (Col. Céramb.). 4. Lieferung. Verlag des Museums G. Frey, Tutzing bei München, pp. 183–284.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref64"><unstructured_citation>Breuning S (1962) Catalogue des Lamiaires du monde (Col. Céramb.). 6. Lieferung. Verlag des Museums G. Frey, Tutzing bei München, pp. 387–459.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref65"><unstructured_citation>Cassis G, Weir TA (1992) Scarabaeinae. In: Houston WWK (Ed.) Zoological catalogue of Australia. Vol. 9 Coleoptera: Scarabaeidae. AGPS Press, Canberra, 106–173.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref66"><unstructured_citation>Cate PC (2007) Family Elateridae Leach, 1815 [minus Cebrioninae, Lissominae, Subprotelaterinae]. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 4. Elateroidea - Derodontoidea - Bostrichoidea - Lymexyloidea - Cleroidea - Cucujoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 94–209.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref67"><unstructured_citation>Chapuis F (1874) Histoire naturelle des insectes. Genera des coléoptères ou exposé méthodique et critique de tous les genres proposées jusqu'ici dans cet ordre d'insectes. Par Mm. Th. Lacordaire et F. Chapuis. Tome dixième. Famille des phytophages. Roret, Paris, iv + 455 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref68"><unstructured_citation>Chevrolat LAA (1842) Blepharida [p. 606]. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.) Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle résumant et complétant tous les faits présentés par les encyclopédies, les anciens dictionnaires scientifiques, les oeuvres complètes de Buffon, et les meilleurs traités spéciaux sur les diverses branches des sciences naturelles; donnant la description des êtres et des divers phénomènes de la nature, l'étymologie et la définition des noms scientifiques, les principales applications des corps organiques et inorganiques, à l'agriculture, à la médecine, aux arts industriels, etc. Tome deuxième. [Livraisons 18–24]. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, ?321–795.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref69"><unstructured_citation>Chevrolat LAA (1843) Chrysomélines [pp. 654–657]. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.) Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle… Tome troisième. [Livraisons 30–36]. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, ?297–744.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref70"><unstructured_citation>Chevrolat LAA (1844) Diphaulaca [p. 46]. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.) Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle… Tome cinquième. [Livraisons 49–56]. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, 1–?488.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref71"><unstructured_citation>Chevrolat LAA (1845) Galérucites; Gastrophysa; Graptodera; Hippodamia. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.) Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle… Tome sixième. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, 4–6, 34, 307, 622–623.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref72"><author>Chevrolat</author><first_page>735</first_page><cYear>1847</cYear><volume_title>Dictionnaire universel d histoire naturelle… Tome neuvième MM</volume_title><article_title>Philochlaenia.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Chevrolat LAA (1847a) Philochlaenia. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.) Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle… Tome neuvième. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, 735–736.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref73"><author>Chevrolat</author><volume>267</volume><first_page>602</first_page><cYear>1847</cYear><volume_title>Dictionnaire universel d histoire naturelle… Tome dixième MM</volume_title><article_title>Plectroscelis. Psomeles.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Chevrolat LAA (1847b) Plectroscelis. Psomeles. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.) Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle… Tome dixième. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, 267, 602.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref74"><author>Chevrolat</author><volume>52</volume><cYear>1848</cYear><volume_title>Dictionnaire universel d histoire naturelle… Tome douzième MM</volume_title><article_title>Strabala.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Chevrolat LAA (1848) Strabala. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.) Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle… Tome douzième. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, 52.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref75"><journal_title>EOS Revista Espa-ola de Entomologia</journal_title><author>Cobos</author><volume>55–56</volume><issue>1979–1980</issue><first_page>23</first_page><cYear>1981</cYear><article_title>Ensayo sobre los géneros de la subfamilia Polycestinae (Coleoptera, Buprestidae) (Parte II).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Cobos A (1981) Ensayo sobre los géneros de la subfamilia Polycestinae (Coleoptera, Buprestidae) (Parte II). EOS, Revista Espa-ola de Entomologia 55–56 [1979–1980]: 23–94.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref76"><issn>00973157</issn><journal_title>Proc Acad Nat Sci Philadelphia</journal_title><author>Crotch</author><volume>25</volume><first_page>19</first_page><cYear>1873</cYear><article_title>Materials for the study of the Phytophaga of the United States.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Crotch GR (1873a). Materials for the study of the Phytophaga of the United States. Proceedings of the Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia 25: 19–83.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref77"><issn>00028320</issn><journal_title>Trans Am Entomol Soc</journal_title><author>Crotch</author><volume>4</volume><first_page>363</first_page><cYear>1873</cYear><article_title>Revision of the Coccinellidae of the United States.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Crotch GR (1873b) Revision of the Coccinellidae of the United States. Transactions of the American Entomological Society 4: 363–382.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref78"><journal_title>Cistula Entomologica</journal_title><author>Crotch</author><volume>1</volume><first_page>377</first_page><cYear>1876</cYear><article_title>A revision of the coleopterous family Erotylidae.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Crotch GR (1876) A revision of the coleopterous family Erotylidae. Cistula Entomologica 1: 377–572.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref79"><author>von Dalla Torre</author><first_page>291</first_page><cYear>1913</cYear><volume_title>Coleopterorum Catalogus auspiciis et auxilio W Junk editus a S Schenkling Pars 50 Scarabaeidae Melolonthinae IV</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Dalla Torre KW von (1913) Coleopterorum Catalogus auspiciis et auxilio W. Junk editus a S. Schenkling. Pars 50: Scarabaeidae: Melolonthinae IV. W. Junk, Berlin, 291–450.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref80"><author>Dejean</author><cYear>1802</cYear><volume_title>Catalogue des coléoptères de la collection d Auguste Dejean classés suivant le Systema Eleutheratorum Fabricii</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Dejean PFMA (1802) Catalogue des coléoptères de la collection d'Auguste Dejean: classés suivant le Systema Eleutheratorum Fabricii. Impr. de la République, Paris, [2] + 11 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref81"><author>Dejean</author><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1833</cYear><volume_title>Catalogue des Coléoptères de la collection de M le Comte Dejean</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Dejean PFMA (1833) Catalogue des Coléoptères de la collection de M. le Comte Dejean. [Livraisons 1-2]. Méquignon-Marvis, Paris, 1–176.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref82"><author>Dejean</author><first_page>177</first_page><cYear>1834</cYear><volume_title>Catalogue des Coléoptères de la collection de M le Comte Dejean</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Dejean PFMA (1834) Catalogue des Coléoptères de la collection de M. le Comte Dejean. [Livraison 3]. Méquignon-Marvis, Paris, 177–256.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref83"><author>Dejean</author><first_page>257</first_page><cYear>1835</cYear><volume_title>Catalogue des Coléoptères de la collection de M le Comte Dejean</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Dejean PFMA (1835) Catalogue des Coléoptères de la collection de M. le Comte Dejean. [Livraison 4]. Méquignon-Marvis, Paris, 257–360.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref84"><author>Dejean</author><first_page>361</first_page><cYear>1836</cYear><volume_title>Catalogue des Coléoptères de la collection de M le Comte Dejean</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Dejean PFMA (1836a) Catalogue des Coléoptères de la collection de M. le Comte Dejean. [Livraison 5]. Méquignon-Marvis, Paris, 361–443.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref85"><author>Dejean</author><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1836</cYear><volume_title>Catalogue des coléoptères de la collection de M le comte Dejean Troisième édition revue corrigée et augmentée</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Dejean PFMA (1836b) Catalogue des coléoptères de la collection de M. le comte Dejean. Troisième édition, revue, corrigée et augmentée. [Livraisons 1-4]. Méquignon-Marvis Père et Fils, Paris, 1–384.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref86"><author>Dejean</author><first_page>385</first_page><cYear>1837</cYear><volume_title>Catalogue des coléoptères de la collection de M le comte Dejean Troisième édition revue corrigée et augmentée</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Dejean PFMA (1837) Catalogue des coléoptères de la collection de M. le comte Dejean. Troisième édition, revue, corrigée et augmentée. [Livraison 5]. Méquignon-Marvis Père et Fils, Paris, 385–503.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref87"><author>Delkeskamp</author><cYear>1977</cYear><volume_title>Cantharidae Coleopterorum Catalogus Supplementa Pars 165 Fasc 1</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Delkeskamp K (1977) Cantharidae. Coleopterorum Catalogus Supplementa. Pars 165, Fasc. 1. Dr W. Junk, The Hague, 485 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref88"><author>Delkeskamp</author><cYear>1981</cYear><volume_title>Erotylidae von Afrika und Madagascar Coleopterorum Catalogus Supplementa Pars 34</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Delkeskamp K (1981) Erotylidae von Afrika und Madagascar. Coleopterorum Catalogus Supplementa. Pars 34. Dr W. Junk, The Hague, 65 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref89"><journal_title>Coleoptera</journal_title><author>Dombrow</author><volume>5</volume><first_page>107</first_page><cYear>2001</cYear><article_title>Revision of the genus Gymnoloma Burmeister 1844 with observations on three new genera (Coleoptera: Scarabaeidae: Melolonthinae: Hopliini). 14th contribution to the knowledge of African Hopliini.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Dombrow H (2001) Revision of the genus Gymnoloma Burmeister 1844 with observations on three new genera (Coleoptera: Scarabaeidae: Melolonthinae: Hopliini). 14th contribution to the knowledge of African Hopliini. Coleoptera 5: 107–148.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref90"><author>Drapiez</author><cYear>1837</cYear><volume_title>Dictionnaire classique des sciences naturelles présentant la définition l analyse et l histoire de tous les êtres qui composent les trois règnes leur application générale aux arts à l agriculture à la médecine à l économie domestique etc résumant tous les faits présentés par les dictionnaires d histoire naturelle augmentée des nombreuses découvertes acquises depuis la publication de ces ouvrages Tome second</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Drapiez PAJ (1837) Dictionnaire classique des sciences naturelles, présentant la définition, l'analyse et l'histoire de tous les êtres qui composent les trois règnes, leur application générale aux arts, à l'agriculture, à la médecine, à l'économie domestique, etc.; résumant tous les faits présentés par les dictionnaires d'histoire naturelle; augmentée des nombreuses découvertes acquises depuis la publication de ces ouvrages. Tome second. Meline, Cans et compagnie, Bruxelles, 570 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref91"><journal_title>Series Entomologica (Dordrecht)</journal_title><author>Endrödi</author><volume>28</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1985</cYear><article_title>The Dynastinae of the world.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Endrödi S (1985) The Dynastinae of the world. Series Entomologica (Dordrecht) 28: 1–800.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref92"><journal_title>Archiv für Naturgeschichte</journal_title><author>Erichson</author><volume>3</volume><issue>2</issue><first_page>281</first_page><cYear>1837</cYear><article_title>Bericht über die Leistungen in der Entomologie während des Jahres 1836.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Erichson WF (1837b) Bericht über die Leistungen in der Entomologie während des Jahres 1836. Archiv für Naturgeschichte 3(2): 281–339.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref93"><journal_title>Archiv für Naturgeschichte</journal_title><author>Erichson</author><volume>8</volume><issue>1</issue><first_page>83</first_page><cYear>1842</cYear><article_title>Beitrag zur Insecten-Fauna von Vandiemensland, mit besonderer Berücksichtigung der geographischen Verbreitung der Insecten.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Erichson WF (1842) Beitrag zur Insecten-Fauna von Vandiemensland, mit besonderer Berücksichtigung der geographischen Verbreitung der Insecten. Archiv für Naturgeschichte 8(1): 83–287.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref94"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Evans</author><volume>211</volume><first_page>3</first_page><cYear>2003</cYear><article_title>A checklist of the New World chafers (Coleoptera: Scarabaeidae: Melolonthinae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Evans AV (2003) A checklist of the New World chafers (Coleoptera: Scarabaeidae: Melolonthinae). Zootaxa 211: 3–458.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref95"><doi>10.5962/bhl.title.36510</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref96"><author>Fabricius</author><cYear>1781</cYear><volume_title>Species insectorum exhibentes eorum differentias specificas synonyma auctorum loca natalia metamorphosin adiectis observationibus descriptionibus Tom I C E Bohnii</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Fabricius JC (1781) Species insectorum exhibentes eorum differentias specificas, synonyma auctorum, loca natalia, metamorphosin adiectis observationibus, descriptionibus. Tom. I. C.E. Bohnii, Hamburgi et Kilonii, [8] + 552 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref97"><doi>10.5962/bhl.title.36532</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref98"><journal_title>Zeitschrift für Entomologie</journal_title><author>Ferrer</author><volume>27</volume><first_page>229</first_page><cYear>2006</cYear><article_title>Description d'un genre nouveau et note synonymique et systématique sur les genres Alobates Motschoulsky, 1872 et Acanthobas Gebien, 1928 (Coleoptera, Tenebrionidae, Tenebrionini). Entomofauna</article_title><unstructured_citation>Ferrer J (2006) Description d'un genre nouveau et note synonymique et systématique sur les genres Alobates Motschoulsky, 1872 et Acanthobas Gebien, 1928 (Coleoptera, Tenebrionidae, Tenebrionini). Entomofauna, Zeitschrift für Entomologie 27: 229–240.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref99"><author>Fischer von Waldheim</author><cYear>1829</cYear><volume_title>Museum historiae naturalis Universitatis Caesareae Mosquensis Pars II Insecta Typis Universitatis Caesareae</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Fischer von Waldheim G (1829) Museum historiae naturalis Universitatis Caesareae Mosquensis. Pars II. Insecta. Typis Universitatis Caesareae, Mosquae, 147 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref100"><journal_title>Entomologische Arbeiten aus dem Museum Georg Frey</journal_title><author>Freude</author><volume>18</volume><first_page>137</first_page><cYear>1967</cYear><article_title>Revision der Epitragini (Coleoptera, Tenebrionidae). I. Teil.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Freude H (1967) Revision der Epitragini (Coleoptera, Tenebrionidae). I. Teil. Entomologische Arbeiten aus dem Museum Georg Frey 18: 137–307.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref101"><journal_title>Pietro Rossi</journal_title><author>Gebien</author><volume>2</volume><first_page>505</first_page><cYear>1937</cYear><article_title>Katalog der Tenebrioniden (Col. Heteromera). Teil I. Publicazioni del Museo Entomologico</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gebien H (1937) Katalog der Tenebrioniden (Col. Heteromera). Teil I. Publicazioni del Museo Entomologico «Pietro Rossi» 2: 505–883.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref102"><journal_title>Mitteilungen der Münchener Entomologischen Gesellschaft</journal_title><author>Gebien</author><volume>29</volume><first_page>443</first_page><cYear>1939</cYear><article_title>Katalog der Tenebrioniden. Teil II.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gebien H (1939) Katalog der Tenebrioniden. Teil II. Mitteilungen der Münchener Entomologischen Gesellschaft 29: 443–474.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref103"><journal_title>Mitteilungen der Münchener Entomologischen Gesellschaft</journal_title><author>Gebien</author><volume>32</volume><first_page>308</first_page><cYear>1942</cYear><article_title>Katalog der Tenebrioniden. Teil II.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gebien H (1942a) Katalog der Tenebrioniden. Teil II. Mitteilungen der Münchener Entomologischen Gesellschaft 32: 308–346.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref104"><journal_title>Mitteilungen der Münchner Entomologischen Gesellschaft</journal_title><author>Gebien</author><volume>32</volume><first_page>729</first_page><cYear>1942</cYear><article_title>Katalog der Tenebrioniden. Teil III.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gebien H (1942b) Katalog der Tenebrioniden. Teil III. Mitteilungen der Münchner Entomologischen Gesellschaft 32: 729–760.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref105"><journal_title>Mitteilungen der Münchner Entomologischen Gesellschaft</journal_title><author>Gebien</author><volume>33</volume><first_page>895</first_page><cYear>1943</cYear><article_title>Katalog der Tenebrioniden. Teil III.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gebien H (1943) Katalog der Tenebrioniden. Teil III. Mitteilungen der Münchner Entomologischen Gesellschaft 33: 895–926.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref106"><author>Gemminger</author><first_page>753</first_page><cYear>1868</cYear><volume_title>Catalogus coleopterorum hucusque descriptorum synonymicus et systematicus Tom III Histeridae Phalacridae Nitidulidae Trogositidae Colydidae Rhysodidae Cucujidae Cryptophagidae Derodontidae Latrididae Othnidae Mycetophagidae Thorictidae Dermestidae Byrrhidae Georyssidae Parnidae Heteroceridae Lucanidae E H Gummi</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Gemminger M, Harold E von (1868) Catalogus coleopterorum hucusque descriptorum synonymicus et systematicus. Tom. III. Histeridae, Phalacridae, Nitidulidae, Trogositidae, Colydidae, Rhysodidae, Cucujidae, Cryptophagidae, Derodontidae, Latrididae, Othnidae, Mycetophagidae, Thorictidae, Dermestidae, Byrrhidae, Georyssidae, Parnidae, Heteroceridae, Lucanidae. E.H. Gummi, Monachii, pp. 753–978 + [5].</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref107"><unstructured_citation>Chevrolat LAA (1858) Description de longicornes nouveaux du vieux Calabar, côte occidentale d'Afrique. Revue et Magasin de Zoologie pure et appliquée (2e série) 10: 348–358.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref108"><unstructured_citation>Chûjô M (1969) Fauna Japonica. Erotylidae (Insecta: Coleoptera). Academic Press of Japan, Tokyo, xii + 316 pp. (+ 23 pls).</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref109"><unstructured_citation>Crotch GR (1874) A revision of the coleopterous family Coccinellidae. E.W. Janson, London, xvi + 311 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref110"><unstructured_citation>Curtis J (1838) British entomology; being illustrations and descriptions of the genera of insects found in Great Britain and Ireland: containing coloured figures from nature of the most rare and beautiful species, and in many instances of the plants upon which they are found. Vol. XV. London, pls 674–721.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref111"><unstructured_citation>Dahl G (1823) Coleoptera und Lepidoptera. Ein systematisches Verzeichniss, mit beygesetzten Preisen der Vorräthe. J.E. Akkermann, Wien, vi + 103 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref112"><unstructured_citation>Danilevsky ML (2011) Additions and corrections to the new Catalogue of Palaearctic Cerambycidae (Coleoptera) edited by I. Löbl and A. Smetana, 2010. Part II. Russian Entomological Journal 19 [2010]: 313–324.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref113"><unstructured_citation>Dejean PFMA (1821) Catalogue de la collection de Coléoptères de M. le Baron Dejean. Crevot, Paris, viii + 138 + [2] pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref114"><unstructured_citation>Dejean PFMA (1828) Species général des Coléoptères, de la collection de M. le Comte Dejean. Tome troisième. Méquignon-Marvis, Paris, vii + 556 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref115"><unstructured_citation>Dellacasa M, Dellacasa G (2006) Tribe Aphodiini Leach, 1815. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 3. Scarabaeoidea - Scirtoidea - Dascilloidea - Buprestoidea - Byrrhoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 105–143.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref116"><unstructured_citation>De Moor PP (1975) Monograph of the Praeugenina. Transvaal Museum, Memoirs No. 17: 1–203.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref117"><unstructured_citation>Desmarest E (1860) Encyclopédie d'histoire naturelle ou traité complet de cette science d'après les travaux des naturalistes les plus éminents de tous les pays et de toutes les époques; Buffon, Daubenton, Lacépède, G. Cuvier, F. Cuvier, Geoffroy Saint-Hilaire, Latreille, de Jussieu, Brongniart, etc., etc. Ouvrage résumant les observations des auteurs anciens et comprenant toutes les découvertes modernes jusqu'à nos jours par le Dr Chenu. Coléoptères buprestiens, scarabéiens, pimeliens, curculioniens, scolytiens, chrysoméliens, etc. Troisième partie. Marescq et Compagnie, Paris, [3] + 360 pp. + 48 pls.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref118"><unstructured_citation>Döberl M (2010) Subfamily Alticinae Newman, 1835. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 6. Chrysomeloidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 491–563.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref119"><unstructured_citation>Drumont A, Komiya Z (2010) Subfamily Prioninae Latreille, 1802. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 6. Chrysomeloidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 86–95.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref120"><unstructured_citation>Duponchel P (1840) Ancylonycha [p. 481]. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.) Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle résumant et complétant tous les faits présentés par les encyclopédies, les anciens dictionnaires scientifiques, les oeuvres complètes de Buffon, et les meilleurs traités spéciaux sur les diverses branches des sciences naturelles; donnant la description des êtres et des divers phénomènes de la nature, l'étymologie et la définition des noms scientifiques, les principales applications des corps organiques et inorganiques, à l'agriculture, à la médecine, aux arts industriels, etc. Tome premier. [Livraisons 3-11]. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, pp. ?81–560.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref121"><unstructured_citation>Duponchel P (1842) Cerandria. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.). Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle… Tome troisième. [Livraisons 25–29]. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, 285.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref122"><unstructured_citation>Duponchel P (1843) Chalcophora. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.) Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle… Tome troisième. [Livraisons 30–36]. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, 372.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref123"><unstructured_citation>Duponchel P (1844) Epicauta. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.) Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle… Tome cinquième. [Livraisons 49–56]. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, 356.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref124"><unstructured_citation>Duponchel P (1845) Eurythyrea. Eutrapela. Heteronychus. Heterophaga. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.) Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle… Tome cinquième. [Livraisons 57–60]. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, 525, 533, 601.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref125"><unstructured_citation>Duponchel P, Chevrolat LAA (1841) Aplosonyx. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.) Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle… Tome deuxième. [Livraisons 13–17]. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, 17.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref126"><unstructured_citation>Duponchel P, Chevrolat LAA (1842a) Aulacophora; Barytopus. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.) Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle… Tome deuxième. [Livraisons 18–24]. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, 337, 483.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref127"><unstructured_citation>Duponchel P, Chevrolat LAA (1842b) Cassidaires. In: d'Orbigny C (Ed.) Dictionnaire universel d'histoire naturelle… Tome troisième. [Livraisons 25–29]. MM. Renard, Martinet et Cie., Paris, 210–211.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref128"><unstructured_citation>Erichson WF (1837a) Die Käfer der Mark Brandenburg. Erster Band. Erste Abtheilung. F.H. Morin, Berlin, viii + pp. 1–384.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref129"><unstructured_citation>Evenhuis NL (1997) Litteratura taxonomica dipterorum (1758-1930); being a selected list of the books and prints of Diptera taxonomy from the beginning of Linnaean zoological nomenclature to the end of the year 1930; containing information on the biographies, bibliographies, types, collections, and patronymic genera of the authors listed in this work; including detailed information on publication dates, original and subsequent editions, and other ancillary data concerning the publications listed herein. Volume I: A-K. Backhuys Publishers, Leiden, vii + 426 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref130"><unstructured_citation>Fabricius JC (1787) Mantissa insectorvm sistens eorvm species nvper detectas adiectis characteribvs genericis, differentiis specificis, emendationibvs, observationibvs. Tom. I. C.G. Proft, Hafniae, xx + 348 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref131"><unstructured_citation>Faldermann F (1835) Coleopterorum ab illustrissimo bungio in China boreali, Mongolia, et montibus Altaicus collectorum, nec non ab ill. Turczaninoffio et Stchukino e provincia Irkutzk missorum illustrationes. Mémoires présentés à l'Académie Impériale des Sciences de Saint-Pétersbourg par divers savans et lus dans ses assemblées (série 6) 2: 337–464.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref132"><unstructured_citation>Fowler WW (1908) Coleoptera. Fam. Erotylidae. Subfam. Languriinae. Genera insectorum publiés par P. Wytsman. 78me Fascicule. V. Verteneuil &amp; L. Desmet, 45 pp. + 3 pls.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref133"><unstructured_citation>Gebien H (1910) Coleopterorum Catalogus auspiciis et auxilio W. Junk editus a S. Schenkling. Pars 15: Tenebrionidae I. W. Junk, Berlin. 166 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref134"><unstructured_citation>Gebien H (1938) Katalog der Tenebrioniden. Teil II. Mitteilungen der Münchener Entomologischen Gesellschaft 28: 49–80, 283–314.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref135"><unstructured_citation>Geisthardt M, Satô M (2007) Family Lampyridae Latreille, 1817. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 4. Elateroidea - Derodontoidea - Bostrichoidea - Lymexyloidea - Cleroidea - Cucujoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 225–234.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref136"><unstructured_citation>Gemminger M, Harold E von (1869) Catalogus coleopterorum hucusque descriptorum synonymicus et systematicus. Tom. IV. Scarabaeidae. EH Gummi, Monachii, 979–1346.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref137"><journal_title>Zeitschrift für die Entomologie</journal_title><author>Germar</author><volume>4</volume><first_page>109</first_page><cYear>1843</cYear><article_title>Ueber die Gruppe der kugelförmigen Trogiden.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Germar EF (1843) Ueber die Gruppe der kugelförmigen Trogiden. Zeitschrift für die Entomologie 4: 109–148.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref138"><issn>03733491</issn><journal_title>Boll Soc Entomol Ital</journal_title><author>Gianfranco</author><volume>123</volume><first_page>121</first_page><cYear>1991</cYear><article_title>Note sulla nomenclatura dei Cerambycidae della regione Mediterranea (Coleoptera).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gianfranco S (1991) Note sulla nomenclatura dei Cerambycidae della regione Mediterranea (Coleoptera). Bollettino della Società Entomologica Italiana 123: 121–128.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref139"><issn>00287199</issn><journal_title>J N Y Entomol Soc</journal_title><author>Gordon</author><volume>93</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1985</cYear><article_title>The Coccinellidae (Coleoptera) of America north of Mexico.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gordon RD (1985) The Coccinellidae (Coleoptera) of America north of Mexico. Journal of the New York Entomological Society 93: 1–912.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref140"><journal_title>Archives Entomologiques</journal_title><author>Guérin-Méneville</author><volume>1</volume><first_page>237</first_page><cYear>1857</cYear><article_title>Matériaux pour une monographie des coléoptères du groupe des Eumorphides, et plus spécialement du genre Eumorphus.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Guérin-Méneville FE (1857) Matériaux pour une monographie des coléoptères du groupe des Eumorphides, et plus spécialement du genre Eumorphus. Archives Entomologiques 1: 237–280.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref141"><doi>10.1206/0003-0090(2001)264&lt;0003:NCITSI&gt;2.0.CO;2</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref142"><issn>00030090</issn><journal_title>Bull Am Mus Nat Hist</journal_title><author>Herman</author><volume>265</volume><first_page>651</first_page><cYear>2001</cYear><article_title>Catalog of the Staphylinidae (Insecta: Coleoptera). 1758 to the end of the second millennium. II. Tachyporine group.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Herman LH (2001b) Catalog of the Staphylinidae (Insecta: Coleoptera). 1758 to the end of the second millennium. II. Tachyporine group. Bulletin of the American Museum of Natural History 265: 651–1066.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref143"><issn>00030090</issn><journal_title>Bull Am Mus Nat Hist</journal_title><author>Herman</author><volume>265</volume><first_page>3021</first_page><cYear>2001</cYear><article_title>Catalog of the Staphylinidae (Insecta: Coleoptera). 1758 to the end of the second millennium. VI. Staphylinine group (part 3) Staphylininae: Staphylinini (Quediina, Staphylinina, Tanygnathinina, Xanthopygina), Xantholinini. Staphylinidae incertae sedis. Fossils, Protactinae.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Herman LH (2001c) Catalog of the Staphylinidae (Insecta: Coleoptera). 1758 to the end of the second millennium. VI. Staphylinine group (part 3) Staphylininae: Staphylinini (Quediina, Staphylinina, Tanygnathinina, Xanthopygina), Xantholinini. Staphylinidae incertae sedis. Fossils, Protactinae. Bulletin of the American Museum of Natural History 265: 3021–3839.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref144"><doi>10.1080/00222934908654009</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref145"><doi>10.1111/j.1365-2311.1952.tb01061.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref146"><issn>03616525</issn><journal_title>Sociobiology</journal_title><author>Howden</author><volume>35</volume><first_page>281</first_page><cYear>2000</cYear><article_title>Tribes of New World Ceratocanthinae, with keys to genera and descriptions of new species (Coleoptera: Scarabaeidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Howden HF, Gill BD (2000) Tribes of New World Ceratocanthinae, with keys to genera and descriptions of new species (Coleoptera: Scarabaeidae). Sociobiology 35: 281–329.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref147"><doi>10.5479/si.00963801.2353.621</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref148"><journal_title>Opinion and Declarations Rendered by the International Commission on Zoological Nomenclature</journal_title><volume>8</volume><first_page>73</first_page><cYear>1954</cYear><article_title>Opinion 289. Acceptance of the type selection for the genus Rantus Dejean, 1833 (Class Insecta, Order Coleoptera) made by Hope in 1839 and emendation of the foregoing name to Rhantus.</article_title><unstructured_citation>ICZN (1954) Opinion 289. Acceptance of the type selection for the genus Rantus Dejean, 1833 (Class Insecta, Order Coleoptera) made by Hope in 1839 and emendation of the foregoing name to Rhantus. Opinion and Declarations Rendered by the International Commission on Zoological Nomenclature 8: 73–88.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref149"><journal_title>Opinion and Declarations Rendered by the International Commission on Zoological Nomenclature</journal_title><volume>11</volume><first_page>49</first_page><cYear>1955</cYear><article_title>Opinion 353. Validation under the Plenary Powers of the generic name &quot;Hoplites&quot; Neumayr, 1875 (Class Cephalopoda, Order Ammomoidea).</article_title><unstructured_citation>ICZN (1955) Opinion 353. Validation under the Plenary Powers of the generic name &quot;Hoplites&quot; Neumayr, 1875 (Class Cephalopoda, Order Ammomoidea). Opinion and Declarations Rendered by the International Commission on Zoological Nomenclature 11: 49–78.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref150"><issn>00075167</issn><journal_title>Bull Zool Nomencl</journal_title><volume>21</volume><first_page>242</first_page><cYear>1964</cYear><article_title>Opinion 710. Enhydrus Laporte, 1834 (Insecta, Coleoptera): validated under the plenary powers.</article_title><unstructured_citation>ICZN (1964) Opinion 710. Enhydrus Laporte, 1834 (Insecta, Coleoptera): validated under the plenary powers. Bulletin of Zoological Nomenclature 21: 242–245.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref151"><issn>00075167</issn><journal_title>Bull Zool Nomencl</journal_title><volume>41</volume><first_page>218</first_page><cYear>1984</cYear><article_title>Opinion 1279. Chrysolina Motschulsky, 1860 (Insecta, Coleoptera): conserved.</article_title><unstructured_citation>ICZN (1984) Opinion 1279. Chrysolina Motschulsky, 1860 (Insecta, Coleoptera): conserved. Bulletin of Zoological Nomenclature 41: 218–220.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref152"><issn>00075167</issn><journal_title>Bull Zool Nomencl</journal_title><volume>42</volume><first_page>21</first_page><cYear>1985</cYear><article_title>Opinion 1290. Leptinotarsa Chevrolat, 1837 (Insecta, Coleoptera); conserved.</article_title><unstructured_citation>ICZN (1985a) Opinion 1290. Leptinotarsa Chevrolat, 1837 (Insecta, Coleoptera); conserved. Bulletin of Zoological Nomenclature 42: 21–23.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref153"><issn>00075167</issn><journal_title>Bull Zool Nomencl</journal_title><volume>42</volume><first_page>344</first_page><cYear>1985</cYear><article_title>Opinion 1359. Uroplat- as the stem of family-group names in Reptilia, Sauria and Insecta, Coleoptera: a ruling to remove the homonymy.</article_title><unstructured_citation>ICZN (1985b) Opinion 1359. Uroplat- as the stem of family-group names in Reptilia, Sauria and Insecta, Coleoptera: a ruling to remove the homonymy. Bulletin of Zoological Nomenclature 42: 344–346.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref154"><issn>00075167</issn><journal_title>Bull Zool Nomencl</journal_title><volume>43</volume><first_page>243</first_page><cYear>1986</cYear><article_title>Opinion 1407. Lamia aethiops Fabricius, 1775 designated as type species of Ceroplesis Serville, 1835 (Insecta, Coleoptera).</article_title><unstructured_citation>ICZN (1986) Opinion 1407. Lamia aethiops Fabricius, 1775 designated as type species of Ceroplesis Serville, 1835 (Insecta, Coleoptera). Bulletin of Zoological Nomenclature 43: 243–244.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref155"><issn>00075167</issn><journal_title>Bull Zool Nomencl</journal_title><volume>45</volume><first_page>71</first_page><cYear>1988</cYear><article_title>Opinion 1473. Tetropium Kirby, 1837 (Insecta, Coleoptera): conserved.</article_title><unstructured_citation>ICZN (1988) Opinion 1473. Tetropium Kirby, 1837 (Insecta, Coleoptera): conserved. Bulletin of Zoological Nomenclature 45: 71–72.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref156"><issn>00075167</issn><journal_title>Bull Zool Nomencl</journal_title><volume>46</volume><first_page>65</first_page><cYear>1989</cYear><article_title>Opinion 1525. Phymatodes Mulsant, 1839 and Phymatestes Pascoe, 1867 (Insecta, Coleoptera): conserved.</article_title><unstructured_citation>ICZN (1989a) Opinion 1525. Phymatodes Mulsant, 1839 and Phymatestes Pascoe, 1867 (Insecta, Coleoptera): conserved. Bulletin of Zoological Nomenclature 46: 65–66.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref157"><issn>00075167</issn><journal_title>Bull Zool Nomencl</journal_title><volume>46</volume><first_page>71</first_page><cYear>1989</cYear><article_title>Opinion 1529. Ceutorhynchus Germar, 1824, Rhinoncus Schoenherr, 1825 and Curculio assimilis Paykull, 1792 (Insecta, Diptera [sic]): conserved, and Curculio assimilis Paykull, 1792 and Curculio pericarpius Linnaeus, 1758 designated as the type species of Ceutorhynchus and Rhinoncus respectively.</article_title><unstructured_citation>ICZN (1989b) Opinion 1529. Ceutorhynchus Germar, 1824, Rhinoncus Schoenherr, 1825 and Curculio assimilis Paykull, 1792 (Insecta, Diptera [sic]): conserved, and Curculio assimilis Paykull, 1792 and Curculio pericarpius Linnaeus, 1758 designated as the type species of Ceutorhynchus and Rhinoncus respectively. Bulletin of Zoological Nomenclature 46: 71–73.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref158"><issn>00075167</issn><journal_title>Bull Zool Nomencl</journal_title><volume>48</volume><first_page>74</first_page><cYear>1991</cYear><article_title>Opinion 1628. Castiarina Gory &amp; Laporte, 1837 (Insecta, Coleoptera): conserved.</article_title><unstructured_citation>ICZN (1991) Opinion 1628. Castiarina Gory &amp; Laporte, 1837 (Insecta, Coleoptera): conserved. Bulletin of Zoological Nomenclature 48: 74–75.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref159"><issn>00075167</issn><journal_title>Bull Zool Nomencl</journal_title><volume>50</volume><first_page>169</first_page><cYear>1993</cYear><article_title>Opinion 1725. Meladema Laporte, 1835 (Insecta, Coleoptera): conserved.</article_title><unstructured_citation>ICZN (1993) Opinion 1725. Meladema Laporte, 1835 (Insecta, Coleoptera): conserved. Bulletin of Zoological Nomenclature 50: 169–170.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref160"><issn>00075167</issn><journal_title>Bull Zool Nomencl</journal_title><volume>53</volume><first_page>54</first_page><cYear>1996</cYear><article_title>Opinion 1824. Ischyrus Lacordaire, 1842, Lybas Lacordaire, 1842, Mycotretus Lacordaire, 1842 and Megischyrus Crotch, 1873 (Insecta, Coleoptera): conserved.</article_title><unstructured_citation>ICZN (1996a) Opinion 1824. Ischyrus Lacordaire, 1842, Lybas Lacordaire, 1842, Mycotretus Lacordaire, 1842 and Megischyrus Crotch, 1873 (Insecta, Coleoptera): conserved. Bulletin of Zoological Nomenclature 53: 54–56.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref161"><issn>00075167</issn><journal_title>Bull Zool Nomencl</journal_title><volume>53</volume><first_page>57</first_page><cYear>1996</cYear><article_title>Opinion 1825. Poecilonota Eschscholtz, 1829, Palmar Schaefer, 1949 and Scintillatrix Obenberger, 1956 (Insecta, Coleoptera): conserved by the designation of Buprestis variolosa Paykull, [1799] as the type species of Poecilonota and B. rutilans Fabricius, [1777] as the type species of Scintillatrix.</article_title><unstructured_citation>ICZN (1996b). Opinion 1825. Poecilonota Eschscholtz, 1829, Palmar Schaefer, 1949 and Scintillatrix Obenberger, 1956 (Insecta, Coleoptera): conserved by the designation of Buprestis variolosa Paykull, [1799] as the type species of Poecilonota and B. rutilans Fabricius, [1777] as the type species of Scintillatrix. Bulletin of Zoological Nomenclature 53: 57–59.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref162"><issn>00075167</issn><journal_title>Bull Zool Nomencl</journal_title><volume>53</volume><first_page>60</first_page><cYear>1996</cYear><article_title>Opinion 1826. Melanophila Eschscholtz, 1829 and Phaenops Dejean, 1833 (Insecta, Coleoptera): conserved by the designation of Buprestis acuminata De Geer, 1774 as the type species of Melanophila.</article_title><unstructured_citation>ICZN (1996c) Opinion 1826. Melanophila Eschscholtz, 1829 and Phaenops Dejean, 1833 (Insecta, Coleoptera): conserved by the designation of Buprestis acuminata De Geer, 1774 as the type species of Melanophila. Bulletin of Zoological Nomenclature 53: 60–61.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref163"><issn>00075167</issn><journal_title>Bull Zool Nomencl</journal_title><volume>53</volume><first_page>134</first_page><cYear>1996</cYear><article_title>Opinion 1838. Temnorhynchus Hope, 1837 (Insecta, Coleoptera): conserved.</article_title><unstructured_citation>ICZN (1996d) Opinion 1838. Temnorhynchus Hope, 1837 (Insecta, Coleoptera): conserved. Bulletin of Zoological Nomenclature 53: 134–135.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref164"><issn>00075167</issn><journal_title>Bull Zool Nomencl</journal_title><volume>58</volume><first_page>70</first_page><cYear>2001</cYear><article_title>Opinion 1968. Phytobius Schönherr, 1833 (Insecta, Coleoptera): placed on the Official List.</article_title><unstructured_citation>ICZN (2001) Opinion 1968. Phytobius Schönherr, 1833 (Insecta, Coleoptera): placed on the Official List. Bulletin of Zoological Nomenclature 58: 70–71.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref165"><issn>00075167</issn><journal_title>Bull Zool Nomencl</journal_title><volume>59</volume><first_page>211</first_page><cYear>2002</cYear><article_title>Opinion 2008 (Case 3149). 30 species-group names originally published as junior primary homonyms in Buprestis Linnaeus, 1758 (Insecta, Coleoptera): conserved.</article_title><unstructured_citation>ICZN (2002) Opinion 2008 (Case 3149). 30 species-group names originally published as junior primary homonyms in Buprestis Linnaeus, 1758 (Insecta, Coleoptera): conserved. Bulletin of Zoological Nomenclature 59: 211–216.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref166"><issn>00075167</issn><journal_title>Bull Zool Nomencl</journal_title><volume>61</volume><first_page>188</first_page><cYear>2004</cYear><article_title>Opinion 2083 (Case 3205). Cyphosoma Mannerheim, 1837 (Insecta, Coleoptera): conserved.</article_title><unstructured_citation>ICZN (2004) Opinion 2083 (Case 3205). Cyphosoma Mannerheim, 1837 (Insecta, Coleoptera): conserved. Bulletin of Zoological Nomenclature 61: 188–189.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref167"><issn>00075167</issn><journal_title>Bull Zool Nomencl</journal_title><volume>62</volume><first_page>110</first_page><cYear>2005</cYear><article_title>Opinion 2115 (Case 3272). Microsaurus Dejean, 1833 (Insecta, Coleoptera): usage conserved by designation of Staphylinus ochripennis Ménétriés, 1832 as the type species.</article_title><unstructured_citation>ICZN (2005) Opinion 2115 (Case 3272). Microsaurus Dejean, 1833 (Insecta, Coleoptera): usage conserved by designation of Staphylinus ochripennis Ménétriés, 1832 as the type species. Bulletin of Zoological Nomenclature 62: 110–111.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref168"><issn>00075167</issn><journal_title>Bull Zool Nomencl</journal_title><volume>65</volume><first_page>325</first_page><cYear>2008</cYear><article_title>Opinion 2214 (Case 3366). Cisseis Gory &amp; Laporte de Castelnau, 1839 and Curis Gory &amp; Laporte de Castelnau, 1838 (Insecta, Coleoptera, Buprestidae): generic names not conserved.</article_title><unstructured_citation>ICZN (2008) Opinion 2214 (Case 3366). Cisseis Gory &amp; Laporte de Castelnau, 1839 and Curis Gory &amp; Laporte de Castelnau, 1838 (Insecta, Coleoptera, Buprestidae): generic names not conserved. Bulletin of Zoological Nomenclature 65: 325–326.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref169"><issn>00075167</issn><journal_title>Bull Zool Nomencl</journal_title><volume>69</volume><first_page>147</first_page><cYear>2012</cYear><article_title>Opinion 2298 (Case 3519). Eumolpus Weber, 1801, Chrysochus Chevrolat in Dejean, 1836 and Bromius Chevrolat in Dejean, 1826 (Insecta, Coleoptera, Chrysomelidae): usage conserved.</article_title><unstructured_citation>ICZN (2012) Opinion 2298 (Case 3519). Eumolpus Weber, 1801, Chrysochus Chevrolat in Dejean, 1836 and Bromius Chevrolat in Dejean, 1826 (Insecta, Coleoptera, Chrysomelidae): usage conserved. Bulletin of Zoological Nomenclature 69: 147–149.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref170"><author>Janssens</author><cYear>1938</cYear><volume_title>Exploration du Parc National Albert Mission G F de Witte (1933-1935) Fascicule 21</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Janssens A (1938) Exploration du Parc National Albert. Mission G.F. de Witte (1933-1935). Fascicule 21. Scarabaeini. Coleoptera Lamellicornia. Fam. Scarabaeidae. Institut des Parcs Nationaux du Congo Belge, Bruxelles, 76 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref171"><journal_title>Insecta Mundi</journal_title><author>Katovich</author><volume>0023</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2008</cYear><article_title>A generic-level phylogenetic review of the Macrodactylini (Coleoptera: Scarabaeidae: Melolonthinae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Katovich K (2008) A generic-level phylogenetic review of the Macrodactylini (Coleoptera: Scarabaeidae: Melolonthinae). Insecta Mundi 0023: 1–78.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref172"><author>Kertész</author><cYear>1909</cYear><volume_title>Catalogus Dipterorum hucusque descriptorum</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Kertész C (1909) Catalogus Dipterorum hucusque descriptorum. Volumen V. Bombyliidae, Therevidae, Omphralidae. Budapestini, 199 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref173"><journal_title>Entomological Review of Japan</journal_title><author>Kimoto</author><volume>41</volume><first_page>123</first_page><cYear>1986</cYear><article_title>New or little known Chrysomelidae (Coleoptera) from Japan and its adjacent regions, V.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Kimoto S (1986) New or little known Chrysomelidae (Coleoptera) from Japan and its adjacent regions, V.  Entomological Review of Japan 41: 123–129.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref174"><journal_title>Transvaal Museum Memoir</journal_title><author>Koch</author><volume>7</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1955</cYear><article_title>Monograph of the Tenebrionidae of southern Africa. Vol. I. (Tentyriinae, Molurini. Trachynotina: Somaticus Hope).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Koch C (1955) Monograph of the Tenebrionidae of southern Africa. Vol. I. (Tentyriinae, Molurini. Trachynotina: Somaticus Hope). Transvaal Museum Memoir 7: 1–242.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref175"><journal_title>Entomologica Basiliensia</journal_title><author>Kolibáč</author><volume>31</volume><first_page>127</first_page><cYear>2009</cYear><article_title>Some nomenclatorial notes on the family Trogossitidae (Coleoptera, Cleroidea).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Kolibáč J (2009) Some nomenclatorial notes on the family Trogossitidae (Coleoptera, Cleroidea). Entomologica Basiliensia 31: 127–129.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref176"><author>Konstantinov</author><cYear>2011</cYear><volume_title>Revision of the Palearctic Chaetocnema species (Coleoptera Chrysomelidae Galerucinae Alticini)</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Konstantinov AS, Baselga A, Grebennikov VV, Prena J, Lingalfelter SW (2011). Revision of the Palearctic Chaetocnema species (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae: Galerucinae: Alticini). Pensoft, Sofia &amp; Moscow, 363 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref177"><author>Korschefsky</author><first_page>225</first_page><cYear>1932</cYear><volume_title>Coleopterorum Catalogus auspiciis et auxilio W Junk editus a S Schenkling Pars 120 Coccinellidae II</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Korschefsky R (1932) Coleopterorum Catalogus auspiciis et auxilio W. Junk editus a S. Schenkling. Pars 120: Coccinellidae II. W. Junk, Berlin, 225–659.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref178"><unstructured_citation>Gemminger M, Harold E von (1870) Catalogus coleopterorum hucusque descriptorum synonymicus et systematicus. Tom. VII. Tenebrionidae, Nilionidae, Pythidae, Melandryidae, Lagriidae, Pedilidae, Anthicidae, Pyrochroidae, Mordellidae, Rhipidophoridae, Cantharidae, Oedemeridae. E.H. Gummi, Monachii, 1801–2179.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref179"><unstructured_citation>Gemminger M, Harold E von (1872) Catalogus coleopterorum hucusque descriptorum synonymicus et systematicus. Tom IX. Scolytidae, Brentidae, Anthotribidae, Cerambycidae. E.H. Gummi, Monachii, 2669–2988.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref180"><unstructured_citation>Gemminger M, Harold E von (1873) Catalogus coleopterorum hucusque descriptorum synonymicus et systematicus. Tom. X. Cerambycidae (Lamiini), Bruchidae. G. Beck, Monachii, 2989–3232.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref181"><unstructured_citation>Germar EF (1844) Fauna Insectorum Europae. Fasc. vicesimus tertius. Car. Aug. Kümmel, Halae, 25 pls.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref182"><unstructured_citation>Guérin-Méneville FE (1831) Voyage autour du monde, exécuté par ordre du Roi, sur la corvette de Sa Majesté, La Coquille, pendant les années 1822, 1823, 1824 et 1825, sous le ministère et conformément aux instructions de S. E. M. Le Marquis de Clermont-Tonnerre, ministre de la marine; et publié sous les auspices de son Excellence Mgr. Le Cte De Chabrol, Ministre de la Marine et des Colonies, par M.L.I. Duperrey. Zoologie, par M. Lesson. Tome second. – 2e partie. Arthus Bertrand, Paris, plate 5.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref183"><unstructured_citation>Guérin-Méneville FE (1834) Matériaux pour une classification des Mélasomes (extraits d'une monographie de cette famille). Magasin de Zoologie 4: 1–39 + pls 101–118.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref184"><unstructured_citation>Hansen M (1999) World catalogue of insects. Volume 2. Hydrophiloidea (s.str.) (Coleoptera). Apollo Books, Strenstrup, 416 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref185"><unstructured_citation>Hansen M (2004) Family Hydrophilidae Latreille, 1802. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 2. Hydrophiloidea - Histeroidea - Staphylinoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 44–68.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref186"><unstructured_citation>Hardy AR (1977) A revision of the Hoplia of the Nearctic realm (Coleoptera: Scarabaeidae). California Department of Food and Agriculture Laboratory Services–Entomology Occasional Papers Supplement No. 23. 48 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref187"><unstructured_citation>Hope FW (1837) The coleopterist's manual, containing the lamellicorn insects of Linneus and Fabricius. Henry G. Bohn, London, 15–121 + 3 pls.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref188"><unstructured_citation>Hope FW (1838) The coleopterist's manual, part the second, containing the predaceous land and water beetles of Linneus and Fabricius. Henry G. Bohn, London, xvi + 168 + [1] pp. + 3 pls.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref189"><unstructured_citation>Hope FW (1840) The coleopterist's manual, part the third, containing various families, genera, and species, of beetles, recorded by Linneus and Fabricius. Also, descriptions of newly discovered and unpublished insects. J. C. Bridgewater and Bowdery &amp; Kerby, London, 191 + [2] pp. + 3 pls.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref190"><unstructured_citation>Hope FW (1841) Observations sur les Érotylés, avec la description de plusieurs nouveaux genres et de quelques espèces inédites. Revue Zoologique (Année 1841): 109–115.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref191"><unstructured_citation>ICZN (1999) International Code of Zoological Nomenclature, Fourth Edition, adopted by the International Union of Biological Sciences. International Trust for Zoological Nomenclature, London, xxix + 306 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref192"><unstructured_citation>Ivie MA (2002a) Bostrichidae Latreille 1802. In: Arnett RH Jr, Thomas MC, Skelley PE, Frank JH (Eds) American Beetles Volume 2 Polyphaga: Scarabaeoidea through Curculionoidea. CRC Press, New York, 233–244.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref193"><unstructured_citation>Ivie MA (2002b) Monommatidae Blanchard 1845. In: Arnett RH Jr, Thomas MC, Skelley PE, Frank JH (Eds) American Beetles Volume 2 Polyphaga: Scarabaeoidea through Curculionoidea. CRC Press, New York, 454–456.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref194"><unstructured_citation>Jacoby M (1908) The fauna of British India including Ceylon and Burma. Coleoptera. Chrysomelidae. Vol. I. Taylor and Francis, London, xx + 534 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref195"><unstructured_citation>Janssens A (1937) Révision des Onitides. Mémoires du Musée Royal d'Histoire Naturelle de Belgique (2e série) 11: 1–200.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref196"><unstructured_citation>Kazantsev S, Brancucci M (2007) Family Cantharidae Imhoff, 1856. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 4. Elateroidea - Derodontoidea - Bostrichoidea - Lymexyloidea - Cleroidea - Cucujoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 234–298.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref197"><unstructured_citation>Kippenberg H (2010) Subfamily Chrysomelinae Latreille, 1802 [excluding genus Timarcha Latreille, 1829]. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 6. Chrysomeloidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 390–437.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref198"><unstructured_citation>Klug JCF (1829) Preis-Verzeichniss vorräthiger Insectendoubletten des Königl. zoologischen Museums der Universität. Berlin, 18 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref199"><author>Krajčik</author><cYear>2001</cYear><volume_title>Lucanidae of the world Catalogue - Part I Checklist of the stag beetles of the world (Coleoptera Lucanidae)</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Krajčik M (2001) Lucanidae of the world. Catalogue - Part I. Checklist of the stag beetles of the world (Coleoptera: Lucanidae). Most (Czech Republic), 108 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref200"><journal_title>Entomologische Blätter</journal_title><author>Krell</author><volume>98</volume><first_page>37</first_page><cYear>2002</cYear><article_title>On nomenclature and synonymy of Old World Dynastinae (Coleoptera, Scarabaeidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Krell FT (2002) On nomenclature and synonymy of Old World Dynastinae (Coleoptera, Scarabaeidae). Entomologische Blätter 98: 37–46.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref201"><doi>10.1649/952.1</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref202"><journal_title>Annales des Sciences Naturelles</journal_title><author>Lacordaire</author><volume>20</volume><first_page>185</first_page><cYear>1830</cYear><article_title>Mémoire sur les habitudes des insectes coléoptères de l'Amérique méridionale.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Lacordaire JT (1830) Mémoire sur les habitudes des insectes coléoptères de l'Amérique méridionale. Annales des Sciences Naturelles 20: 185–291.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref203"><author>Lacordaire</author><cYear>1857</cYear><volume_title>Histoire naturelle des insectes Genera des Coléoptères ou exposé méthodique et critique de tous les genres proposés jusqu ici dans cet ordre d insectes Tome quatrième contenant les familles des buprestides throscides eucnémides élatérides cébrionides cérophytides rhipicérides dascyllides malacodermes clérides lyméxylones cupésides ptiniores bostrichides et cissides</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Lacordaire JT (1857) Histoire naturelle des insectes. Genera des Coléoptères ou exposé méthodique et critique de tous les genres proposés jusqu'ici dans cet ordre d'insectes. Tome quatrième contenant les familles des buprestides, throscides, eucnémides, élatérides, cébrionides, cérophytides, rhipicérides, dascyllides, malacodermes, clérides, lyméxylones, cupésides, ptiniores, bostrichides et cissides. Roret, Paris, 579 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref204"><author>Lacordaire</author><cYear>1868</cYear><volume_title>Histoire naturelle des insectes Genera des Coléoptères ou exposé méthodique et critique de tous les genres proposés jusqu ici dans cet ordre d insectes Tome huitième contenant les familles des tricténotomides et des longicornes</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Lacordaire JT (1868) Histoire naturelle des insectes. Genera des Coléoptères ou exposé méthodique et critique de tous les genres proposés jusqu'ici dans cet ordre d'insectes. Tome huitième contenant les familles des tricténotomides et des longicornes. Roret, Paris, 552 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref205"><journal_title>Faune de Madagascar</journal_title><author>Lacroix</author><volume>73</volume><first_page>303</first_page><cYear>1993</cYear><article_title>Insectes coléoptères, Melolonthidae (2e partie).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Lacroix M (1993) Insectes coléoptères, Melolonthidae (2e partie). Faune de Madagascar 73. Pp. 303–875.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref206"><author>Lacroix</author><cYear>2007</cYear><volume_title>Pachydeminae du monde (Scarabaeoidea Melolonthidae) Genera et catalogue</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Lacroix M (2007) Pachydeminae du monde (Scarabaeoidea, Melolonthidae). Genera et catalogue. Collection Hannetons, Paris, 450 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref207"><journal_title>Revue Entomologique</journal_title><author>Laporte</author><volume>4</volume><first_page>5</first_page><cYear>1836</cYear><article_title>Études entomologiques, ou descriptions d'insectes nouveaux et observations sur la synonymie.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Laporte FLN (1836) Études entomologiques, ou descriptions d'insectes nouveaux et observations sur la synonymie. Revue Entomologique 4: 5–60.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref208"><author>Laporte</author><cYear>1840</cYear><volume_title>Histoire naturelle des insectes Coléoptères avec une introduction renfermant l anatomie et la physiologie des animaux articulés par M Brullé Tome deuxième</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Laporte FLN (1840) Histoire naturelle des insectes Coléoptères; avec une introduction renfermant l'anatomie et la physiologie des animaux articulés, par M. Brullé. Tome deuxième. P. Duménil, Paris, 563 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref209"><author>Latreille</author><cYear>1825</cYear><volume_title>Familles naturelles du règne animal exposées succinctement et dans un ordre analytique avec l indication de leurs genres J -B Baillière</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Latreille PA (1825) Familles naturelles du règne animal, exposées succinctement et dans un ordre analytique, avec l'indication de leurs genres. J.-B. Baillière [&amp;] Baudouin Frères, Paris. 570 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref210"><doi>10.1111/j.1365-3113.2012.00661.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref211"><author>von Linnaeus</author><cYear>1758</cYear><volume_title>Systema naturae per regna tria naturae secundum classes ordines genera species cum characteribus differentiis synonymis locis Editio decima reformata Tomus I Laurentii Salvii</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Linnaeus C von (1758) Systema naturae per regna tria naturae, secundum classes, ordines, genera, species, cum characteribus, differentiis, synonymis, locis. Editio decima, reformata. Tomus I. Laurentii Salvii, Holmiae, 823 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref212"><author>Linsley</author><volume>19</volume><cYear>1962</cYear><volume_title>The Cerambycidae of North America Part II Taxonomy and classification of the Parandrinae Prioninae Spondylinae and Aseminae</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Linsley EG (1962) The Cerambycidae of North America. Part II. Taxonomy and classification of the Parandrinae, Prioninae, Spondylinae, and Aseminae. University of California Publications in Entomology Volume 19. 102 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref213"><author>Lopatin</author><cYear>1977</cYear><volume_title>Leaf beetles (Chrysomelidae) of Central Asia and Kazakhstan</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Lopatin I (1977) Leaf beetles (Chrysomelidae) of Central Asia and Kazakhstan. Nauka, Leningrad, 268 pp. [in Russian]</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref214"><doi>10.3366/anh.1988.15.3.317</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref215"><author>Mahul</author><cYear>1869</cYear><volume_title>L entomologie en cent distiques dédiée aux jeunes garçons avec une préface également en vers contenant la biographie comme naturaliste du général Comte Dejean son père</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Mahul SE (1869) L'entomologie en cent distiques dédiée aux jeunes garçons avec une préface également en vers, contenant la biographie, comme naturaliste, du général Comte Dejean, son père. Héritiers Botta, Florence. 159 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref216"><journal_title>Revue de Zoologie Africaine</journal_title><author>Mal</author><volume>99</volume><first_page>195</first_page><cYear>1985</cYear><article_title>Description d'une espèce nouvelle du genre Odontopezus Alluaud, 1889 (Coleoptera, Tenebrionidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Mal N (1985) Description d'une espèce nouvelle du genre Odontopezus Alluaud, 1889 (Coleoptera, Tenebrionidae). Revue de Zoologie Africaine 99: 195–196.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref217"><journal_title>Bulletin de la Société Impériale des Naturalistes de Moscou</journal_title><author>Mannerheim</author><volume>15</volume><first_page>864</first_page><cYear>1842</cYear><article_title>Notice sur la c.d. collection de coléoptères de M. le Comte Dejean.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Mannerheim CG (1842) Notice sur la c.d. collection de coléoptères de M. le Comte Dejean. Bulletin de la Société Impériale des Naturalistes de Moscou 15: 864–870.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref218"><journal_title>Dusenia</journal_title><author>Marinoni</author><volume>10</volume><first_page>37</first_page><cYear>1977</cYear><article_title>Some genera of Lamiinae and their type-species (Coleoptera-Cerambycidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Marinoni RC (1977) Some genera of Lamiinae and their type-species (Coleoptera-Cerambycidae). Dusenia 10: 37–55.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref219"><journal_title>L Abeille</journal_title><author>Marseul</author><volume>1</volume><first_page>xli</first_page><cYear>1864</cYear><article_title>Bibliographie.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Marseul SA (1864) Bibliographie. L'Abeille 1: xli–lx.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref220"><author>Maulik</author><cYear>1926</cYear><volume_title>The fauna of British India including Ceylon and Burma Coleoptera Chrysomelidae (Chrysomelinae and Halticinae)</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Maulik S (1926) The fauna of British India, including Ceylon and Burma. Coleoptera. Chrysomelidae (Chrysomelinae and Halticinae). Taylor and Francis, London, 442 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref221"><author>Mazur</author><cYear>2011</cYear><volume_title>A concise catalogue of the Histeridae (Insecta Coleoptera)</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Mazur S (2011) A concise catalogue of the Histeridae (Insecta: Coleoptera). Warsaw University of Life Sciences–SGGW Press, Warsaw, 332 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref222"><doi>10.3853/j.0067-1967.10.1947.477</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref223"><doi>10.1163/187631205788838500</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref224"><author>Medvedev</author><cYear>1949</cYear><volume_title>Fauna SSSR Coleoptera 10 (3) Lamellicornia (Scarabaeidae) subfamily Rutelinae (cereal beetles and related groups)</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Medvedev SI (1949) Fauna SSSR. Coleoptera 10 (3): Lamellicornia (Scarabaeidae) subfamily Rutelinae (cereal beetles and related groups) [in Russian]. Academia Nauk SSSR, Moscou &amp; Leningrad. 372 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref225"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Monné</author><volume>3213</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2012</cYear><article_title>Catalogue of the type-species of the genera of the Cerambycidae, Disteniidae, Oxypeltidae and Vesperidae (Coleoptera) of the Neotropical Region.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Monné MA (2012) Catalogue of the type-species of the genera of the Cerambycidae, Disteniidae, Oxypeltidae and Vesperidae (Coleoptera) of the Neotropical Region. Zootaxa 3213: 1–183.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref226"><author>Monné</author><cYear>2009</cYear><volume_title>Checklist of the Cerambycidae or longhorned wood-boring beetles of the Western Hemisphere</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Monné MA, Bezark LG (2009) Checklist of the Cerambycidae, or longhorned wood-boring beetles, of the Western Hemisphere. BioQuip Publications, Rancho Dominguez (CA), [1] + 482 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref227"><journal_title>Insecta Mundi</journal_title><author>Monné</author><volume>6</volume><first_page>249</first_page><cYear>1992</cYear><article_title>Nomenclatural notes on Western Hemisphere Cerambycidae (Coleoptera).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Monné MA, Giesbert EF (1992) Nomenclatural notes on Western Hemisphere Cerambycidae (Coleoptera). Insecta Mundi 6: 249–255.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref228"><journal_title>Bulletin</journal_title><author>Monrós</author><volume>7</volume><first_page>45</first_page><cYear>1953</cYear><article_title>Some corrections in the nomenclature of Clytrinae (Chrysomelidae). The Coleopterists'</article_title><unstructured_citation>Monrós F (1953) Some corrections in the nomenclature of Clytrinae (Chrysomelidae). The Coleopterists' Bulletin 7: 45–50.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref229"><journal_title>Frey</journal_title><author>Monrós</author><volume>7</volume><first_page>1118</first_page><cYear>1956</cYear><article_title>Über einige verkannte Chrysomeliden-Namen. Entomologische Arbeiten aus dem Museum G.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Monrós F, Bechyné J (1956) Über einige verkannte Chrysomeliden-Namen. Entomologische Arbeiten aus dem Museum G. Frey 7: 1118–1137.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref230"><journal_title>Etudes Entomologiques</journal_title><author>Motschulsky</author><volume>1</volume><first_page>25</first_page><cYear>1853</cYear><article_title>Lampyrides.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Motschulsky V (1853) Lampyrides. Etudes Entomologiques 1: 25–58.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref231"><issn>00075167</issn><journal_title>Bull Zool Nomencl</journal_title><author>Mühle</author><volume>50</volume><first_page>27</first_page><cYear>1993</cYear><article_title>Case 2837/1. Poecilonota Eschscholtz, 1829, Palmar Schaefer, 1949 and Scintillatrix Obenberger, 1956 (Insecta, Coleoptera): proposed conservation by the designation of Buprestis variolosa Paykull, [1799] as the type species of Poecilonota and B. rutilans Fabricius, [1777] as the type species of Scintillatrix.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Mühle H (1993) Case 2837/1. Poecilonota Eschscholtz, 1829, Palmar Schaefer, 1949 and Scintillatrix Obenberger, 1956 (Insecta, Coleoptera): proposed conservation by the designation of Buprestis variolosa Paykull, [1799] as the type species of Poecilonota and B. rutilans Fabricius, [1777] as the type species of Scintillatrix. Bulletin of Zoological Nomenclature 50: 27–30.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref232"><doi>10.1163/187631289X00348</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref233"><author>Olivier</author><cYear>1795</cYear><volume_title>Entomologie ou histoire naturelle des insectes avec leurs caractères génériques et spécifiques leur description leur synonymie et leur figure enluminée Coléoptères Tome quatrième</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Olivier GA (1795) Entomologie, ou histoire naturelle des insectes, avec leurs caractères génériques et spécifiques, leur description, leur synonymie, et leur figure enluminée. Coléoptères. Tome quatrième. Baudouin, Paris.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref234"><journal_title>Journal of Afrotropical Zoology</journal_title><author>Opitz</author><volume>7</volume><first_page>29</first_page><cYear>2011</cYear><article_title>Classification, natural history, and evolution of Korynetinae Laporte (Coleoptera: Cleridae). Part I. Generic composition of the subfamily and key to genera.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Opitz W (2011) Classification, natural history, and evolution of Korynetinae Laporte (Coleoptera: Cleridae). Part I. Generic composition of the subfamily and key to genera. Journal of Afrotropical Zoology 7: 29–67.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref235"><unstructured_citation>Kovář I (2007) Family Coccinellidae Latreille, 1807. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 4. Elateroidea - Derodontoidea - Bostrichoidea - Lymexyloidea - Cleroidea - Cucujoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 568–631.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref236"><unstructured_citation>Král D, Smetana A (2006) Tribe Adoretini Burmeister, 1844. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 3. Scarabaeoidea - Scirtoidea - Dascilloidea - Buprestoidea - Byrrhoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 248–251.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref237"><unstructured_citation>Krell FT (2006) Subfamily Dynastinae MacLeay, 1819. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 3. Scarabaeoidea - Scirtoidea - Dascilloidea - Buprestoidea - Byrrhoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 277–283.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref238"><unstructured_citation>Kurosawa Y (1982) A remarkable convergence found in Malayan buprestid beetles, with description of two new species from Thailand and Hainan. Bulletin of the National Science Museum (Series A, Zoology) 8: 173–204.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref239"><unstructured_citation>Lawrence JF, Weir TA, Pyke JE (1987) Haliplidae, Hygrobiidae, Noteridae, Dytiscidae and Gyrinidae. In: Houston K, Richardson B (Eds) Zoological catalogue of Australia. Volume 4. Coleoptera: Archostemata, Myxophaga and Adephaga. Australian Government Publishing service, Canberra, 321–366.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref240"><unstructured_citation>Leschen RAB, Skelley PE (2002) Languriidae Wiedeman 1823. In: Arnett RH Jr, Thomas MC, Skelley PE, Frank JH (Eds) American Beetles Volume 2 Polyphaga: Scarabaeoidea through Curculionoidea. CRC Press, New York, 343–347.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref241"><unstructured_citation>Linnaeus C von (1767) Systema naturae per regna tria naturae, secundum classes, ordines, genera, species, cum characteribus, differentiis, synonymis, locis. Editio duodecima, reformata. Tom. I. Pars II. Laurentii Salvii, Holmiae, 533–1327.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref242"><unstructured_citation>Lloyd JE (2002) Lampyridae Latreille 1817. In: Arnett RH Jr, Thomas MC, Skelley PE, Frank JH (Eds) American Beetles Volume 2 Polyphaga: Scarabaeoidea through Curculionoidea. CRC Press, New York, 187–196.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref243"><unstructured_citation>Löbl I, Bouchard P, Merkl O, Iwan D (2008a) New nomenclatorial and taxonomic acts, and comments. Tenebrionidae. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 5. Tenebrionoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 40–45.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref244"><unstructured_citation>Löbl I, Ando K, Bouchard P, Egorov LV, Iwan D, Lillig M, Masumoto K, Merkl O, Nabozhenko M, Novák V, Petterson R, Schawaller W, Soldati F (2008b) Family Tenebrionidae Latreille, 1802. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 5. Tenebrionoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 105–352.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref245"><unstructured_citation>Löbl I, Smetana A (2011) Errata. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 7. Curculionoidea I. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 23–63.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref246"><unstructured_citation>Lopatin I, Smetana A, Schöller M (2010) Genus Cryptocephalus Geoffroy, 1762. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 6. Chrysomeloidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 580–606.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref247"><unstructured_citation>López-Colón JI (2006) Subfamily Orphninae Erichson, 1847. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 3. Scarabaeoidea - Scirtoidea - Dascilloidea - Buprestoidea - Byrrhoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 179–180.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref248"><unstructured_citation>Machatschke JW (1972) Scarabaeoidea: Melolonthidae Rutelinae. Coleopterorum Catalogus Supplementa edita a J.A. Wilcox. Pars 66 Fasc. 1 (Editio Secunda). Uitgeverij Dr. W. Junk, 's-Gravenhage, 361 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref249"><unstructured_citation>Mazzoldi P (2003) Family Gyrinidae Latreille, 1810. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 1. Archostemata - Myxophaga - Adephaga. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 26–30.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref250"><unstructured_citation>McDermot FA (1966) Coleopterorum Catalogus Supplementa edita a W.O. Steel. Pars 9 (Editio Secunda). Lampyridae. Dr. W. Junk, 's-Gravenhage, 149 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref251"><unstructured_citation>Miller RS (2002) Lycidae Laporte 1836. In: Arnett RH Jr, Thomas MC, Skelley PE, Frank JH (Eds) American Beetles Volume 2 Polyphaga: Scarabaeoidea through Curculionoidea. CRC Press, New York, 174–178.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref252"><unstructured_citation>Montrouzier X (1856) Essai sur la faune de l'ile de Woodlark ou Moiou. Annales des Sciences Physiques et Naturelles, d'Agriculture et d'Industrie (deuxième série) 7(1) [1855]: 1–114.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref253"><unstructured_citation>Moseyko AG, Sprecher-Uebersax E (2010) Subfamily Eumolpinae Hope, 1840. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 6. Chrysomeloidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 619–643.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref254"><unstructured_citation>Motschulsky V (1860) Coléoptères de la Sibérie orientale et en particulier des rives de l'Amour. In: Reisen und Forschungen im Amur-Lande in den Jahren 1854-1856 im Auftrage der Kaiserl. Akademie der Wissenschaften zu St. Petersburg ausgeführt und in Verbindung mit mehreren Gelehrten herausgegeben von Dr Leopold v. Schrenck. Zweiter Band. Zoologie: Lepidopteren, Coleopteren, Mollusken. Eggers und Comp., H. Schmitzdorff und Jacques Issakof, St-Pétersburg, 77–257.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref255"><unstructured_citation>Motschulsky V (1872) Enumération des nouvelles espèces de coléoptères rapportés de ses voyages. 11-ième article. Bulletin de la Société Impériale des Naturalistes de Moscou 45 (seconde partie): 23–55.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref256"><unstructured_citation>Muona J (2007) Family Eucnemidae Eschscholtz, 1829. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 4. Elateroidea - Derodontoidea - Bostrichoidea - Lymexyloidea - Cleroidea - Cucujoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 81–87.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref257"><unstructured_citation>Nilsson AN (2003) Family Dytiscidae Leach, 1815. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 1. Archostemata - Myxophaga - Adephaga. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 35–78.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref258"><unstructured_citation>Nikitsky NB (2008) Family Tetratomidae Billberg, 1820. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 5. Tenebrionoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 62–64.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref259"><unstructured_citation>Opitz W (2002) Cleridae Latreille 1804. In: Arnett RH Jr, Thomas MC, Skelley PE, Frank JH (Eds) American Beetles Volume 2 Polyphaga: Scarabaeoidea through Curculionoidea. CRC Press, New York, 267–280.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref260"><unstructured_citation>Parsons MS, Scoble MJ, Honey MR, Pitkin LM, Pitkin BR (1999) Geometrid moths of the world: a catalogue (Lepidoptera, Geometridae). Volume 1. CSIRO, Collingwood, Victoria, i-xxv + 1–482 + I1–I129.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref261"><unstructured_citation>Penrith ML (1979) Revision of the western southern African Adesmiini (Coleoptera: Tenebrionidae). Cimbebasia (Ser. A) 5(1): 1–94.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref262"><journal_title>Entomology</journal_title><author>Pope</author><volume>9</volume><first_page>65</first_page><cYear>1960</cYear><article_title>A revision of the species of Schizonycha Dejean (Col: Melolonthidae) from southern Africa. Bulletin of the British Museum (Natural History)</article_title><unstructured_citation>Pope RD (1960) A revision of the species of Schizonycha Dejean (Col: Melolonthidae) from southern Africa. Bulletin of the British Museum (Natural History), Entomology 9: 65–219.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref263"><journal_title>Boston Journal of Natural History</journal_title><author>Randall</author><volume>2</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1838</cYear><article_title>Description of new species of coleopterous insects inhabiting the state of Maine.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Randall JW (1838) Description of new species of coleopterous insects inhabiting the state of Maine. Boston Journal of Natural History 2: 1–33.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref264"><journal_title>Bulletin of the University of Nebraska State Museum</journal_title><author>Ratcliffe</author><volume>16</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2003</cYear><article_title>The dynastine scarab beetles of Costa Rica and Panama (Coleoptera: Scarabaeidae: Dynastinae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Ratcliffe BC (2003) The dynastine scarab beetles of Costa Rica and Panama (Coleoptera: Scarabaeidae: Dynastinae). Bulletin of the University of Nebraska State Museum 16: 1–506.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref265"><issn>00379271</issn><journal_title>Ann Soc Entomol Fr</journal_title><author>Régimbart</author><volume>75</volume><first_page>235</first_page><cYear>1906</cYear><article_title>Voyage de M. Ch. Alluaud dans l'Afrique orientale. Dytiscidae, Gyrinidae, Hydrophilidae.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Régimbart M (1906) Voyage de M. Ch. Alluaud dans l'Afrique orientale. Dytiscidae, Gyrinidae, Hydrophilidae. Annales de la Société Entomologique de France 75: 235–278.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref266"><author>Reiche</author><first_page>211</first_page><cYear>1841</cYear><volume_title>Tableau d une division systématique de la tribu des Coprophages dans la famille des Lamellicornes</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Reiche L (1841) Tableau d'une division systématique de la tribu des Coprophages, dans la famille des Lamellicornes. Revue Zoologique [4]: 211–213.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref267"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Reid</author><volume>1292</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2006</cYear><article_title>A taxonomic revision of the Australian Chrysomelinae, with a key to the genera (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Reid CAM (2006) A taxonomic revision of the Australian Chrysomelinae, with a key to the genera (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae). Zootaxa 1292: 1–119.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref268"><issn>03733491</issn><journal_title>Boll Soc Entomol Ital</journal_title><author>Ricchiardi</author><volume>141</volume><first_page>147</first_page><cYear>2009</cYear><article_title>Preliminary notes for the revision of the African genus Myodermum, with descriptions of two new species (Coleoptera Cetoniidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Ricchiardi E, Gill BD (2009) Preliminary notes for the revision of the African genus Myodermum, with descriptions of two new species (Coleoptera Cetoniidae). Bollettino della Societa Entomologica Italiana 141: 147–154.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref269"><issn>01510517</issn><journal_title>Bull Soc Entomol Fr</journal_title><author>Robiche</author><volume>113</volume><first_page>525</first_page><cYear>2008</cYear><article_title>Contribution à l'étude du genre Oncosoma Westwood, 1842 de la région afrotropicale (Coleoptera, Tenebrionidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Robiche G (2008) Contribution à l'étude du genre Oncosoma Westwood, 1842 de la région afrotropicale (Coleoptera, Tenebrionidae). Bulletin de la Société Entomologique de France 113: 525–532.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref270"><journal_title>Entomologia Africana</journal_title><author>Sama</author><volume>14</volume><first_page>22</first_page><cYear>2009</cYear><article_title>New nomenclatural acts in Cerambycidae (Coleoptera, Cerambycidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Sama G (2009) New nomenclatural acts in Cerambycidae (Coleoptera, Cerambycidae). Entomologia Africana 14: 22–26.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref271"><doi>10.5479/si.00963801.92-3145.157</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref272"><journal_title>Journal of the Entomological Society of Southern Africa</journal_title><author>Scholtz</author><volume>50</volume><first_page>121</first_page><cYear>1987</cYear><article_title>A revision of the southern African genus Epirinus Reiche (Coleoptera: Scarabaeidae: Scarabaeinae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Scholtz CH, Howden HF (1987) A revision of the southern African genus Epirinus Reiche (Coleoptera: Scarabaeidae: Scarabaeinae). Journal of the Entomological Society of Southern Africa 50: 121–154.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref273"><author>Schönherr</author><cYear>1835</cYear><volume_title>Genera et species curculionidum cum synonymia hujus familiae species novae aut hactenus minus cognitae descriptionibus A Dom Leonardo Gyllenhal C H Boheman et entomologis aliis illustratae Tomus tertius Pars prima Roret</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Schönherr CJ (1835) Genera et species curculionidum, cum synonymia hujus familiae; species novae aut hactenus minus cognitae, descriptionibus A Dom. Leonardo Gyllenhal, C. H. Boheman, et entomologis aliis illustratae. Tomus tertius. Pars prima. Roret, Parisiis, 505 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref274"><author>Schönherr</author><cYear>1837</cYear><volume_title>Genera et species curculionidum cum synonymia hujus familiae species novae aut hactenus minus cognitae descriptionibus A Dom Leonardo Gyllenhal C H Boheman et entomologis aliis illustratae Tomus quartus Pars prima Roret</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Schönherr CJ (1837) Genera et species curculionidum, cum synonymia hujus familiae; species novae aut hactenus minus cognitae, descriptionibus A Dom. Leonardo Gyllenhal, C. H. Boheman, et entomologis aliis illustratae. Tomus quartus. Pars prima. Roret, Parisiis, 600 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref275"><journal_title>Entomography</journal_title><author>Seeno</author><volume>1</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1982</cYear><article_title>Leaf beetle genera (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Seeno T, Wilcox J (1982) Leaf beetle genera (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae). Entomography 1: 1–221.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref276"><issn>00028320</issn><journal_title>Trans Am Entomol Soc</journal_title><author>Selander</author><volume>112</volume><first_page>95</first_page><cYear>1986</cYear><article_title>An annotated catalog and summary of bionomics of blister beetles of the genus Cyaneolytta (Coleoptera, Meloidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Selander RB (1986) An annotated catalog and summary of bionomics of blister beetles of the genus Cyaneolytta (Coleoptera, Meloidae). Transactions of the American Entomological Society 112: 95–128.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref277"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Shockley</author><volume>1999</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2009</cYear><article_title>An annotated checklist of the handsome fungus beetles of the world (Coleoptera: Cucujoidea: Endomychidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Shockley F, Tomaszewska K, McHugh J (2009) An annotated checklist of the handsome fungus beetles of the world (Coleoptera: Cucujoidea: Endomychidae). Zootaxa 1999: 1–113.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref278"><journal_title>Annales Entomologici Fennici</journal_title><author>Silfverberg</author><volume>49</volume><first_page>115</first_page><cYear>1983</cYear><article_title>The coleopteran genera of Dejean 1821. 1. Carabidae.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Silfverberg H (1983) The coleopteran genera of Dejean 1821. 1. Carabidae. Annales Entomologici Fennici 49: 115–116.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref279"><journal_title>Annales Entomologici Fennici</journal_title><author>Silfverberg</author><volume>50</volume><first_page>58</first_page><cYear>1984</cYear><article_title>The coleopteran genera of Dejean 1821. 2. Polyphaga. 1.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Silfverberg H (1984a) The coleopteran genera of Dejean 1821. 2. Polyphaga. 1. Annales Entomologici Fennici 50: 58–60.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref280"><journal_title>Annales Entomologici Fennici</journal_title><author>Silfverberg</author><volume>50</volume><first_page>61</first_page><cYear>1984</cYear><article_title>The coleopteran genera of Dejean 1821. 3. Curculionoidea and Chrysomeloidea.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Silfverberg H (1984b) The coleopteran genera of Dejean 1821. 3. Curculionoidea and Chrysomeloidea. Annales Entomologici Fennici 50: 61–63.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref281"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Smetana</author><volume>1220</volume><first_page>47</first_page><cYear>2006</cYear><article_title>Type species designations and other nomenclatural notes on Palaearctic Melolonthinae and Cetoniinae (Coleoptera: Scarabaeoidea: Scarabaeidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Smetana A, Smith ABT (2006) Type species designations and other nomenclatural notes on Palaearctic Melolonthinae and Cetoniinae (Coleoptera: Scarabaeoidea: Scarabaeidae). Zootaxa 1220: 47–53.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref282"><journal_title>Bulletin of the University of Nebraska State Museum</journal_title><author>Smith</author><volume>15</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2003</cYear><article_title>A monographic revision of the genus Platycoelia Dejean (Coleoptera: Scarabaeidae: Rutelinae: Anoplognathini).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Smith ABT (2003) A monographic revision of the genus Platycoelia Dejean (Coleoptera: Scarabaeidae: Rutelinae: Anoplognathini). Bulletin of the University of Nebraska State Museum 15: 1–202.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref283"><doi>10.1649/0010-065X(2006)60[144:AROTFN]2.0.CO;2</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref284"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Smith</author><volume>1032</volume><first_page>29</first_page><cYear>2005</cYear><article_title>A supplement to the checklist of the New World chafers (Coleoptera: Scarabaeidae: Melolonthinae) with notes on their tribal classification.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Smith ABT, Evans AV (2005) A supplement to the checklist of the New World chafers (Coleoptera: Scarabaeidae: Melolonthinae) with notes on their tribal classification. Zootaxa 1032: 29–60.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref285"><issn>00379271</issn><journal_title>Ann Soc Entomol Fr</journal_title><author>Solier</author><volume>4</volume><first_page>229</first_page><cYear>1835</cYear><article_title>Prodrome de la famille des Xystropides.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Solier AJJ (1835) Prodrome de la famille des Xystropides. Annales de la Société Entomologique de France 4: 229–248.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref286"><issn>00138797</issn><journal_title>Proc Entomol Soc Wash</journal_title><author>Spilman</author><volume>75</volume><first_page>39</first_page><cYear>1973</cYear><article_title>Nomenclatural problems in six genera of Tenebrionidae (Coleoptera).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Spilman TJ (1973) Nomenclatural problems in six genera of Tenebrionidae (Coleoptera). Proceedings of the Entomological Society of Washington 75: 39–44.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref287"><journal_title>Insecta Mundi</journal_title><author>Staines</author><volume>5</volume><first_page>247</first_page><cYear>1991</cYear><article_title>Type species of New World Hispinae genera (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Staines CL (1991) Type species of New World Hispinae genera (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae). Insecta Mundi 5: 247–248.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref288"><journal_title>Insecta Mundi</journal_title><author>Staines</author><volume>0122</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2010</cYear><article_title>Nomenclatural notes on Chalepini and Sceloenopliini (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae: Cassidinae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Staines CL (2010) Nomenclatural notes on Chalepini and Sceloenopliini (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae: Cassidinae). Insecta Mundi 0122: 1–2.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref289"><author>Stephens</author><volume>V</volume><first_page>369</first_page><cYear>1835</cYear><volume_title>Illustrations of British entomology or a synopsis of indigenous insects containing their generic and specific distinctions with an account of their metamorphoses times of appearance localities food and economy as far as practicable Embellished with coloured figures of the rarer and more interesting species Mandibulata</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Stephens JF (1835) Illustrations of British entomology; or, a synopsis of indigenous insects: containing their generic and specific distinctions; with an account of their metamorphoses, times of appearance, localities, food, and economy, as far as practicable. Embellished with coloured figures of the rarer and more interesting species. Mandibulata. Vol. V. [Parts 56–58]. Baldwin &amp; Cradock, London, 369–447.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref290"><author>Strohecker</author><cYear>1953</cYear><volume_title>Coleoptera Fam Endomychidae Genera Insectorum de P Wytsman 210e fascicule</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Strohecker HF (1953) Coleoptera. Fam. Endomychidae. Genera Insectorum de P. Wytsman. 210e fascicule. Louis Desmet-Verteneuil, Bruxelles, 140 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref291"><journal_title>Bulletin de la Société Linnéenne de Bordeaux</journal_title><author>Sudre</author><volume>30</volume><first_page>111</first_page><cYear>2002</cYear><article_title>A propos des genres Hecyra Thomson, Niphona Mulsant et Nyphona Dejean (Coleoptera Cerambycidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Sudre J, Téocchi P (2002) A propos des genres Hecyra Thomson, Niphona Mulsant et Nyphona Dejean (Coleoptera Cerambycidae). Bulletin de la Société Linnéenne de Bordeaux 30: 111–116.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref292"><issn>0005805X</issn><journal_title>Beitr Entomol</journal_title><author>Taeger</author><volume>46</volume><first_page>251</first_page><cYear>1996</cYear><article_title>Kommentare zur Taxonomie der Symphyta (Hymenoptera) (Vorarbeiten zu einem Katalog der Pflanzenwespen, Teil 1).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Taeger A, Blank SM (1996) Kommentare zur Taxonomie der Symphyta (Hymenoptera) (Vorarbeiten zu einem Katalog der Pflanzenwespen, Teil 1). Beiträge zur Entomologie 46: 251–275.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref293"><author>Théry</author><cYear>1942</cYear><volume_title>Coléoptères Buprestides Faune de France 41</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Théry A (1942) Coléoptères Buprestides. Faune de France 41. Librairie de la Faculté des Sciences, Paris, 223 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref294"><author>Thomson</author><cYear>1859</cYear><volume_title>Skandinaviens Coleoptera synoptiskt bearbetade</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Thomson CG (1859) Skandinaviens Coleoptera, synoptiskt bearbetade. Tom. I. Berlingska Boktryckeriet, Lund, [3] + 290 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref295"><journal_title>Annales Zoologici (Warszawa)</journal_title><author>Tomaszewska</author><volume>55</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2005</cYear><article_title>Phylogeny and generic classification of the subfamily Lycoperdininae with a re-analysis of the family Endomychidae (Coleoptera: Cucujoidea).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Tomaszewska KW (2005) Phylogeny and generic classification of the subfamily Lycoperdininae with a re-analysis of the family Endomychidae (Coleoptera: Cucujoidea). Annales Zoologici (Warszawa) 55 (Supplement 1): 1–172.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref296"><author>Tranié</author><cYear>2001</cYear><volume_title>Napoléon et son entourage</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Tranié J (2001) Napoléon et son entourage. Pygmalion/Gérard Watelet, Paris, 460 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref297"><author>Vidal</author><cYear>2007</cYear><volume_title>Los tenebriónidos de Chile</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Vidal GHP, Guerrero MG (2007) Los tenebriónidos de Chile. Pontificia Universidad Católica de Chile [Santiago], 478 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref298"><journal_title>Zoosystematica Rossica</journal_title><author>Volkovitsh</author><volume>11</volume><first_page>166</first_page><cYear>2002</cYear><article_title>Type species designations for Sphenoptera Dejean and Rhaphidochila Jakovlev (Coleoptera: Buprestidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Volkovitsh MG, Kalashian MY (2002) Type species designations for Sphenoptera Dejean and Rhaphidochila Jakovlev (Coleoptera: Buprestidae). Zoosystematica Rossica 11: 166.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref299"><author>Weise</author><cYear>1916</cYear><volume_title>Coleopterorum Catalogus auspiciis et auxilio W Junk editus a S Schenkling Pars 68 Chrysomelidae 12</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Weise J (1916) Coleopterorum Catalogus auspiciis et auxilio W. Junk editus a S. Schenkling. Pars 68: Chrysomelidae: 12. Chrysomelinae. W. Junk, Berlin. 255 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref300"><journal_title>Arkiv för Zoologi</journal_title><author>Weise</author><volume>15</volume><issue>12</issue><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1923</cYear><article_title>Results of Dr. E. Mjöberg's Swedish scientific expedition to Australia 1910-1913. 31. Chrysomeliden und Coccinelliden aus Queensland.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Weise J (1923) Results of Dr. E. Mjöberg's Swedish scientific expedition to Australia 1910-1913. 31. Chrysomeliden und Coccinelliden aus Queensland. Arkiv för Zoologi 15(12): 1–150.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref301"><author>Weise</author><cYear>1924</cYear><volume_title>Coleopterorum Catalogus auspiciis et auxilio W Junk editus a S Schenkling Pars 78 Chrysomelidae 13</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Weise J (1924) Coleopterorum Catalogus auspiciis et auxilio W. Junk editus a S. Schenkling. Pars 78: Chrysomelidae: 13. Galerucinae. W. Junk, Berlin, 225 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref302"><journal_title>Bulletin of the Museum of Comparative Zoology</journal_title><author>Werner</author><volume>95</volume><first_page>421</first_page><cYear>1945</cYear><article_title>A revision of the genus Epicauta in America north of Mexico (Coleoptera, Meloidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Werner FG (1945) A revision of the genus Epicauta in America north of Mexico (Coleoptera, Meloidae). Bulletin of the Museum of Comparative Zoology 95: 421–517.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref303"><issn>00138797</issn><journal_title>Proc Entomol Soc Wash</journal_title><author>White</author><volume>83</volume><first_page>713</first_page><cYear>1981</cYear><article_title>The genus Uroplata, type-species and authorship (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>White RE (1981) The genus Uroplata, type-species and authorship (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae). Proceedings of the Entomological Society of Washington 83: 713–715.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref304"><issn>00075167</issn><journal_title>Bull Zool Nomencl</journal_title><author>Willems</author><volume>64</volume><first_page>218</first_page><cYear>2007</cYear><article_title>Case 3405. Trigonostomum Schmidt, 1852 (Platyhelminthes, Trigonostomidae) and Trigonostomus Brenske, 1893 (Coleoptera, Scarabaeidae), proposed conservation of the generic names and proposed emendation of the current spelling of Trigonostomina Ohaus, 1912 (Coleoptera, Scarabaeidae) to remove homonymy with Trigonostomidae Graff, 1905 (Platyhelminthes).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Willems WR, Krell FT (2007) Case 3405. Trigonostomum Schmidt, 1852 (Platyhelminthes, Trigonostomidae) and Trigonostomus Brenske, 1893 (Coleoptera, Scarabaeidae), proposed conservation of the generic names and proposed emendation of the current spelling of Trigonostomina Ohaus, 1912 (Coleoptera, Scarabaeidae) to remove homonymy with Trigonostomidae Graff, 1905 (Platyhelminthes). Bulletin of Zoological Nomenclature 64: 218–223.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref305"><unstructured_citation>Pinto JD, Bologna MA (2002) Meloidae Gyllenhal 1810. In: Arnett RH Jr, Thomas MC, Skelley PE, Frank JH (Eds) American Beetles Volume 2 Polyphaga: Scarabaeoidea through Curculionoidea. CRC Press, New York, 522–529.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref306"><unstructured_citation>Ramsdale AS (2002) Cantharidae Imhoff 1856. In: Arnett RH Jr, Thomas MC, Skelley PE, Frank JH (Eds) American Beetles Volume 2 Polyphaga: Scarabaeoidea through Curculionoidea. CRC Press, New York, 202–218.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref307"><unstructured_citation>Regalin R, Medvedev LN (2010) Tribe Clytrini Kirby, 1837. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 6. Chrysomeloidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 564–580.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref308"><unstructured_citation>Riley EG, Clark SM, Seeno TN (2003) Catalog of the leaf beetles of America north of Mexico (Coleoptera: Megalopodidae, Orsodacnidae and Chrysomelidae, excluding Bruchinae). Coleopterists Society Special Publication No. 1. 290 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref309"><unstructured_citation>Robiche G (2006) Description d'une nouvelle espèce de la région Afrotropicale appartenant au genre Eupezus Blanchard, 1845 (Coleoptera, Tenebridonidae). Lambillionea 106 [Supplement: (Tome I)]: 382–386.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref310"><unstructured_citation>Sama G (2002) Atlas of the Cerambycidae of Europe and the Mediterranean area. Volume I: northern, western, central and eastern Europe. British Isles and continental Europe from France (excl. Corsica) to Scandinavia and Urals. Nakladatelstvi Kabourek, Zlin, 173 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref311"><unstructured_citation>Sama G (2010) Cerambycidae. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 6. Chrysomeloidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 49–58.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref312"><unstructured_citation>Saunders E (1871) Catalogus buprestidarum synonymicus et systematicus. E.W. Janson, London, xxiii + [1] + 171 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref313"><unstructured_citation>Schöller M, Löbl I, Lopatin I (2010) Tribe Cryptocephalini Gyllenhal, 1813 [excluding genus Cryptocephalus Geoffroy, 1762]. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 6. Chrysomeloidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 606–617.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref314"><unstructured_citation>Schönherr CJ (1833) Genera et species curculionidum, cum synonymia hujus familiae; species novae aut hactenus minus cognitae, descriptionibus A Dom. Leonardo Gyllenhal, C. H. Boheman, et entomologis aliis illustratae. Tomus primus. Pars prima. Roret, Parisiis, xv + 381 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref315"><unstructured_citation>Schönherr CJ (1836) Genera et species curculionidum, cum synonymia hujus familiae; species novae aut hactenus minus cognitae, descriptionibus A Dom. Leonardo Gyllenhal, C. H. Boheman, et entomologis aliis illustratae. Tomus tertius. Pars secunda. Roret, Parisiis, 507–858.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref316"><unstructured_citation>Schönherr CJ (1840) Genera et species curculionidum, cum synonymia hujus familiae; species novae aut hactenus minus cognitae, descriptionibus A Dom. Leonardo Gyllenhal, C. H. Boheman, et entomologis aliis illustratae. Tomus quintus. Pars secunda. Supplementum continens. Roret, Parisiis, 465–970.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref317"><unstructured_citation>Silfverberg H (2010) Subfamily Synetinae LeConte &amp; Horn, 1883. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 6. Chrysomeloidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 643.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref318"><unstructured_citation>Ślipiński SA (2007) Family Bothrideridae Erichson, 1845. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 4. Elateroidea - Derodontoidea - Bostrichoidea - Lymexyloidea - Cleroidea - Cucujoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 548–552.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref319"><unstructured_citation>Ślipiński SA, Schuh R (2008) Family Zopheridae Solier, 1834. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 5. Tenebrionoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 78–87.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref320"><unstructured_citation>Smetana A (2004a) Subfamily Paederinae Fleming, 1821. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 2. Hydrophiloidea - Histeroidea - Staphylinoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 579–624.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref321"><unstructured_citation>Smetana A (2004b) Subfamily Staphylininae Latreille, 1802. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 2. Hydrophiloidea - Histeroidea - Staphylinoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 624–698.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref322"><unstructured_citation>Smetana A (2006) Tribe Hoplini Latreille, 1829. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 3. Scarabaeoidea - Scirtoidea - Dascilloidea - Buprestoidea - Byrrhoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 184–189.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref323"><unstructured_citation>Smetana A, Král D (2006) Tribe Rhizotrogini Burmeister, 1855. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 3. Scarabaeoidea - Scirtoidea - Dascilloidea - Buprestoidea - Byrrhoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 207–228.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref324"><unstructured_citation>Švihla V (2008) Family Oedemeridae Latreille, 1810. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 5. Tenebrionoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 353–369.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref325"><unstructured_citation>Thomson J (1860–1861) Essai d'une classification de la famille des cérambycides et matériaux pour servir à une monographie de cette famille. Paris, xvi + 404 pp. + 3 pls. [1–128, 1860; 129–404, 1861].</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref326"><unstructured_citation>Thomson J (1864–1865) Systema cerambycidarum ou exposé de tous les genres compris dans la famille des cérambycides et familles limitrophes. H. Dessain, Liége, 578 pp. [1–352, 1864; pp. 353–578, 1865].</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref327"><unstructured_citation>Thomson J (1878) Typi buprestidarum musaei Thomsoniani. Emile Deyrolle, Paris, 103 + 4 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref328"><unstructured_citation>Timberlake PH (1943) The Coccinellidae or ladybeetles of the Koebele Collection — Part 1. Bulletin of the Experiment Station of the Hawaiian Sugar Planters' Association, Entomological series 22: 1–67.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref329"><unstructured_citation>Tomaszewska KW (2007) Family Alexiidae Imhoff, 1856. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 4. Elateroidea - Derodontoidea - Bostrichoidea - Lymexyloidea - Cleroidea - Cucujoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 555–556.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref330"><unstructured_citation>Veiga Ferreira G da (1966) Longicórnios de Moçambique. I. Revista de Entomologia de Moçambique 7 [1964]: 451–838.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref331"><unstructured_citation>Wegrzynowicz P (2007a) Family Laemophloeidae Ganglbauer, 1899. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 4. Elateroidea - Derodontoidea - Bostrichoidea - Lymexyloidea - Cleroidea - Cucujoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 503–506.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref332"><unstructured_citation>Wegrzynowicz P (2007b) Family Erotylidae Latreille, 1802. In: Löbl I, Smetana A (Eds) Catalogue of Palaearctic Coleoptera. Volume 4. Elateroidea - Derodontoidea - Bostrichoidea - Lymexyloidea - Cleroidea - Cucujoidea. Apollo Books, Stenstrup, 531–546.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref333"><unstructured_citation>Westwood JO (1838) Synopsis of the genera of British insects. Longman, Orme, Brown, Green, and Longmans, London, 48 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref334"><unstructured_citation>Wilcox JA (1971) Chrysomelidae: Galerucinae Oidini, Galerucini, Metacyclini, Sermylini. Coleopterorum Catalogus Supplementa. Pars 78, Fasc. 1 (Editio Secunda). Dr W. Junk, 's-Gravenhage, 220 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
</citation_list>
</doi_citations>
</body>
</doi_batch>
