<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doi_batch version="4.3.0" xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/doi_resources_schema/4.3.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/doi_resources_schema/4.3.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/deposit/doi_resources4.3.0.xsd">
<head>
<doi_batch_id>dfbe0ec2-ec7f-4e4e-9a3a-478f258283d6</doi_batch_id>
<depositor>
<name>pens</name>
<email_address>bozhin.karaivanov@gmail.com</email_address>
</depositor>
</head>
<body>
<doi_citations>
<doi>part-3-266-3982</doi>
<citation_list>
	<citation key="ref1"><author>Lavieren</author><first_page>159</first_page><cYear>2009</cYear><volume_title>Crossing Boundaries</volume_title><article_title>Managing coastal Resources of the Northern Sierra Madre Natural Park.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Lavieren H, van Iongh HH, de Belen A, van Weerd M (2009) Managing coastal Resources of the Northern Sierra Madre Natural Park. In: Persoon G, Ploeg J, van der Masipiquena A, Weerd M van (Eds) Crossing Boundaries. Manila: Studio Graphics Corporation, 159–167.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref2"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Leviton</author><volume>91</volume><first_page>365</first_page><cYear>1962</cYear><article_title>Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, I. The snakes of the genus Oligodon.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Leviton AE (1962) Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, I. The snakes of the genus Oligodon. Philippine Journal of Science 91: 365–381.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref3"><issn>0068547X</issn><journal_title>Proc Calif Acad Sci</journal_title><author>Leviton</author><volume>4</volume><issue>31</issue><first_page>369</first_page><cYear>1963</cYear><article_title>Remarks on the zoogeography of Philippine terrestrial snakes.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Leviton AE (1963a) Remarks on the zoogeography of Philippine terrestrial snakes. Proceedings of the California Academy of Science 4(31): 369–416.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref4"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Leviton</author><volume>92</volume><first_page>523</first_page><cYear>1963</cYear><article_title>Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, III. The genera Maticora and Calliophis.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Leviton AE (1963b) Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, III. The genera Maticora and Calliophis. Philippine Journal of Science 92: 523–550.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref5"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Leviton</author><volume>93</volume><issue>2</issue><first_page>251</first_page><cYear>1964</cYear><article_title>Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, V. The snakes of the genus Trimeresurus.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Leviton AE (1964a) Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, V. The snakes of the genus Trimeresurus. Philippine Journal of Science 93(2): 251–276.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref6"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Leviton</author><volume>93</volume><first_page>531</first_page><cYear>1964</cYear><article_title>Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, VII. The snakes of the genera Naja and Ophiophagus.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Leviton AE (1964b) Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, VII. The snakes of the genera Naja and Ophiophagus. Philippine Journal of Science 93: 531–550.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref7"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Leviton</author><volume>93</volume><first_page>407</first_page><cYear>1964</cYear><article_title>Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, VI. The snakes of the genus Oxyrabdion.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Leviton AE (1964c) Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, VI. The snakes of the genus Oxyrabdion. Philippine Journal of Science 93: 407–422.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref8"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Leviton</author><volume>94</volume><issue>4</issue><first_page>519</first_page><cYear>1965</cYear><article_title>Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, IX. The snakes of the genus Cyclocorus.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Leviton AE (1965a) Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, IX. The snakes of the genus Cyclocorus. Philippine Journal of Science 94(4): 519–533.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref9"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Leviton</author><volume>94</volume><first_page>117</first_page><cYear>1965</cYear><article_title>Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, VIII. The snakes of the genus Lycodon H. Boie.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Leviton AE (1965b) Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, VIII. The snakes of the genus Lycodon H. Boie. Philippine Journal of Science 94: 117–140.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref10"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Leviton</author><volume>96</volume><issue>1</issue><first_page>73</first_page><cYear>1967</cYear><article_title>Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, X. The snakes of the genus Ahaetulla.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Leviton AE (1967) Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, X. The snakes of the genus Ahaetulla. Philippine Journal of Science 96(1): 73–90.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref11"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Leviton</author><volume>97</volume><first_page>371</first_page><cYear>1968</cYear><article_title>Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, VII. The Philippine snakes of the genus Dendrelaphis (Serpentes: Colubridae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Leviton AE (1968) Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, VII. The Philippine snakes of the genus Dendrelaphis (Serpentes: Colubridae). Philippine Journal of Science 97: 371–396.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref12"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Leviton</author><volume>97</volume><issue>3</issue><first_page>291</first_page><cYear>1970</cYear><article_title>Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, XI. The snakes of the genus Boiga.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Leviton AE (1970) Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, XI. The snakes of the genus Boiga. Philippine Journal of Science 97(3): 291–314.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref13"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Leviton</author><volume>106</volume><first_page>99</first_page><cYear>1979</cYear><article_title>Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, XIII. The snakes of the Genus Elaphe.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Leviton AE (1979) Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, XIII. The snakes of the Genus Elaphe. Philippine Journal of Science 106: 99–128.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref14"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Leviton</author><volume>112</volume><first_page>195</first_page><cYear>1983</cYear><article_title>Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, XIV. The Snakes of the Genus Xenopeltis, Zaocys, Psammodynastes, and Myersophis.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Leviton AE (1983) Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, XIV. The Snakes of the Genus Xenopeltis, Zaocys, Psammodynastes, and Myersophis. Philippine Journal of Science 112: 195–223.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref15"><issn>0068547X</issn><journal_title>Proc Calif Acad Sci</journal_title><author>Leviton</author><volume>29</volume><first_page>475</first_page><cYear>1959</cYear><article_title>A review of the snakes of the genus Pseudorabdion with remarks on the status of the genera Agryophis and Typhlogeophis (Serpentes: Colubridae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Leviton AE, Brown WC (1959) A review of the snakes of the genus Pseudorabdion with remarks on the status of the genera Agryophis and Typhlogeophis (Serpentes: Colubridae). Proceedings of the California Academy of Science 29: 475–508.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref16"><author>Lim</author><cYear>1999</cYear><volume_title>Turtles of Borneo and Peninsular Malaysia Natural History Publications</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Lim BL, Das I (1999) Turtles of Borneo and Peninsular Malaysia. Natural History Publications (Borneo) Kota Kinabalu, Malaysia. 151 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref17"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Linkem</author><article_title>Systematic revision of the Parvoscincus decipiens (Boulenger 1894) complex of Philippine forest skinks (Squamata: Scincidae: Lygosominae) with descriptions of seven new species.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Linkem CW, Brown RM (in review) Systematic revision of the Parvoscincus decipiens (Boulenger 1894) complex of Philippine forest skinks (Squamata: Scincidae: Lygosominae) with descriptions of seven new species. Zootaxa.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref17"><doi>10.1111/jbi.12022</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref17"><doi>10.1111/j.1096-3642.2011.00747.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref17"><doi>10.1016/j.ympev.2010.03.043</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref18"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Linkem</author><volume>2396</volume><first_page>37</first_page><cYear>2010</cYear><article_title>A new species of Gekko (Squamata: Gekkonidae) from central Luzon Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Linkem CW, Siler CD, Diesmos AC, Brown RM (2010) A new species of Gekko (Squamata: Gekkonidae) from central Luzon Island, Philippines. Zootaxa 2396: 37–94.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref18"><doi>10.1016/0378-1127(93)90158-J</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref19"><author>Lomolino</author><cYear>2010</cYear><volume_title>Biogeography</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Lomolino MV, Riddle BR, Whittaker RJ, Brown JH (2010) Biogeography, Fourth edition. Sinauer Associates, Inc, Massachusetts.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><issn>00973157</issn><journal_title>Proc Acad Nat Sci Philadelphia</journal_title><author>Malnate</author><volume>140</volume><first_page>59</first_page><cYear>1988</cYear><article_title>Australasian natricine snakes of the genus Tropidonophis.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Malnate EV, Underwood G (1988) Australasian natricine snakes of the genus Tropidonophis. Proceedings of the Academy of Natural Science of Philadelphia 140: 59–201.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref21"><author>Manthey</author><cYear>1997</cYear><volume_title>Amphibien und Reptilien Südostasiens</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Manthey U, Grossman W (1997) Amphibien und Reptilien Südostasiens. Natur und Tier, Verlag, Germany, 512 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref21"><doi>10.2307/1563076</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref21"><doi>10.2307/1467046</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref22"><journal_title>Asian Herpetological Research</journal_title><author>McLeod</author><volume>2011</volume><first_page>177</first_page><cYear>2011</cYear><article_title>Amphibians and Reptiles of Luzon Island, V: the herpetofauna of Angat Dam Watershed, Bulacan Province, Luzon Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>McLeod DS, Siler CD, Diesmos AC, Diesmos MLD, Garcia VS, Arkonceo AO, Balaquit KL, Uy CC, Villaseran MM, Yarra EC, Brown RM (2011) Amphibians and Reptiles of Luzon Island, V: the herpetofauna of Angat Dam Watershed, Bulacan Province, Luzon Island, Philippines. Asian Herpetological Research 2011: 177–198.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref22"><doi>10.1080/08941920.2012.676160</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref23"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Murphy</author><volume>3484</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2012</cYear><article_title>The dog-faced water snakes, a revision of the genus Cerberus Cuvier, (Squamata, Serpentes, Homalopsidae), with the description of a new species.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Murphy JC, Voris HK, Karns DR (2012) The dog-faced water snakes, a revision of the genus Cerberus Cuvier, (Squamata, Serpentes, Homalopsidae), with the description of a new species. Zootaxa 3484: 1–34.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref23"><doi>10.2307/2405975</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref24"><author>Myers</author><first_page>19</first_page><cYear>1962</cYear><volume_title>Proceedings of the Seventh Pacific Science Congress 4</volume_title><article_title>Ability of amphibians to cross sea barriers with especial reference to Pacific zoogeography.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Myers GS (1962) Ability of amphibians to cross sea barriers with especial reference to Pacific zoogeography. Proceedings of the Seventh Pacific Science Congress 4: 19–27.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref24"><doi>10.1007/s10531-009-9742-z</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref25"><journal_title>Scientific Publications of the Natural History Museum of the University of Kansas</journal_title><author>Oliveros</author><volume>43</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2011</cYear><article_title>The Herpetofauna of the Babuyan group of islands, northern Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Oliveros CH, Ota H, Crombie RI, Brown RM (2011) The Herpetofauna of the Babuyan group of islands, northern Philippines. Scientific Publications of the Natural History Museum of the University of Kansas 43: 1–20.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref26"><author>Ota</author><first_page>222</first_page><cYear>1989</cYear><volume_title>Current Herpetology in East Asia</volume_title><article_title>A review of the geckos (Lacertilia: Reptilia) of the Ryukyu Archipelago and Taiwan.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Ota H (1989) A review of the geckos (Lacertilia: Reptilia) of the Ryukyu Archipelago and Taiwan. In: Matsui M, Hikida T, Goris RC (Eds) Current Herpetology in East Asia. Herpetological Society of Japan, Kyoto, Japan, 222–261.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref27"><issn>0006324X</issn><journal_title>Proc Biol Soc Wash</journal_title><author>Ota</author><volume>102</volume><first_page>559</first_page><cYear>1989</cYear><article_title>A new lizard of the genus Lepidodactylus (Reptilia: Gekkonidae) from Batan island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Ota H, Crombie RI (1989) A new lizard of the genus Lepidodactylus (Reptilia: Gekkonidae) from Batan island, Philippines. Proceedings of the Biological Society of Washington 102: 559–567.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref27"><doi>10.2307/1564316</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref28"><issn>00221511</issn><journal_title>J Herpetol</journal_title><author>Ota</author><volume>13</volume><first_page>35</first_page><cYear>1989</cYear><article_title>A record of a triploid gecko, Hemidactylus stejnegeri, from the northern Philippines Japanese</article_title><unstructured_citation>Ota H, Hikida T (1989b) A record of a triploid gecko, Hemidactylus stejnegeri, from the northern Philippines Japanese Journal of Herpetology 13: 35–39.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref28"><doi>10.2307/1446682</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref28"><doi>10.1080/03946975.1993.10539214</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><journal_title>Monatsbericht der Königlich-Preussischen Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin</journal_title><author>Peters</author><volume>1867</volume><first_page>13</first_page><cYear>1867</cYear><article_title>Herpetologische Notizen.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Peters WCH (1867) Herpetologische Notizen. Monatsbericht der Königlich-Preussischen Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin 1867: 13–37.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><issn>0018084X</issn><journal_title>Herpetol Rev</journal_title><author>Phenix</author><volume>43</volume><first_page>614</first_page><cYear>2011</cYear><article_title>Hologerrhum philipinum—reproductive mode.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Phenix E, Phenix JW, Siler C, Brown RM, Diesmos AC (2011) Hologerrhum philipinum—reproductive mode. Herpetological Review 43: 614.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Roesler</author><volume>2989</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2011</cYear><article_title>Phylogeny, taxonomy, and zoogeography of the genu Gekko Laurenti, 1768 with the revalidation of G. reevesii Gray, 1831 (Sauria: Gekkonidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Roesler H, Bauer AM, Heinicke MP, Greenbaum E, Jackman T, Nguyen TQ, Ziegler T (2011) Phylogeny, taxonomy, and zoogeography of the genu Gekko Laurenti, 1768 with the revalidation of G. reevesii Gray, 1831 (Sauria: Gekkonidae). Zootaxa 2989: 1–50.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref32"><author>Ron</author><first_page>133</first_page><cYear>2008</cYear><volume_title>Threatened Amphibians of the World Lynx Ediciones Barcelona Spain IUCN - The World Conservation Union Gland Switzerland and Conservation International</volume_title><article_title>Filling the black hole: challenges in taxonomy to protect amphibians.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Ron S, Brown RM (2008) Filling the black hole: challenges in taxonomy to protect amphibians. Pp. 133 In: Stuart SN, Hoffmann M, Chanson JS, Cox NA, Berridge R, Ramani P, Young BE (Eds.) Threatened Amphibians of the World. Lynx Ediciones, Barcelona, Spain; IUCN - The World Conservation Union, Gland, Switzerland; and Conservation International, Arlington Virginia, USA.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><journal_title>Silliman Journal</journal_title><author>Ross</author><volume>34</volume><first_page>29</first_page><cYear>1987</cYear><article_title>Distribution of Zoacys luzonensis (Serpentes: Colubridae) in the Visayan Islands, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Ross CA, Alcala AC, Sison RV (1987) Distribution of Zoacys luzonensis (Serpentes: Colubridae) in the Visayan Islands, Philippines. Silliman Journal 34: 29–31.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref34"><journal_title>National Museum Papers (Manila)</journal_title><author>Ross</author><volume>2</volume><first_page>50</first_page><cYear>1992</cYear><article_title>Amphibians and reptiles of Catanduanes Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Ross CA, Gonzales PC (1992) Amphibians and reptiles of Catanduanes Island, Philippines. National Museum Papers (Manila) 2: 50–76.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref35"><journal_title>Check List</journal_title><author>Siler</author><volume>6</volume><first_page>616</first_page><cYear>2010</cYear><article_title>Reptilia, Squamata, Scincidae, Brachymeles elerae (Taylor 1917): Rediscovery in Old Balbalan, Cordillera Mountain Range, Luzon Island, Philippines, and natural history.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Siler CD (2010) Reptilia, Squamata, Scincidae, Brachymeles elerae (Taylor 1917): Rediscovery in Old Balbalan, Cordillera Mountain Range, Luzon Island, Philippines, and natural history. Check List 6: 616–618.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref35"><doi>10.1655/HERPMONOGRAPHS-D-10-00003.1</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref35"><doi>10.1111/j.1558-5646.2011.01315.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref35"><doi>10.1670/10-103.1</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref35"><doi>10.1670/08-318.1</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref36"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Siler</author><volume>2482</volume><first_page>49</first_page><cYear>2010</cYear><article_title>A new species of limestone-forest frog, genus Platymantis (Amphibia: Anura: Ceratobatrachidae) from central Luzon Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Siler CD, Diesmos AC, Linkem CW, Diesmos M, Brown RM (2010b) A new species of limestone-forest frog, genus Platymantis (Amphibia: Anura: Ceratobatrachidae) from central Luzon Island, Philippines. Zootaxa 2482: 49–63.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref36"><doi>10.1016/j.ympev.2010.12.019</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref37"><issn>0018084X</issn><journal_title>Herpetol Rev</journal_title><author>Siler</author><volume>42</volume><first_page>605</first_page><cYear>2011</cYear><article_title>Natural history notes on color variation of Lamprolepis smaragdina.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Siler CD, Linkem CW (2011) Natural history notes on color variation of Lamprolepis smaragdina. Herpetological Review 42: 605.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref37"><doi>10.1016/j.ympev.2010.01.027</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref37"><doi>10.1111/j.1365-2699.2011.02680.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref37"><doi>10.1111/zsc.12007</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref37"><doi>10.1655/08-076.1</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref37"><unstructured_citation>Leviton AE (1961) Description of a new subspecies of the Philippine snake Dendrelalaphis caudolineatus. Occasional Papers Natural History Museum of Stanford University 9: 1–6.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref37"><unstructured_citation>McDiarmid RW, Cambell JA, Touré TA (1999) Snake Species of the World: A Taxonomic and Geographic Reference. The Herpetologists' League, Washington DC. 511 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref37"><unstructured_citation>National Statistics Office (NSO) (2010) Final results 2010 census of population. Available at: http://www.census.gov.ph/data/census2010/index.html</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref37"><unstructured_citation>Nordic Agency for Development and Ecology (NORDECO) and Department of Environment and Natural Resources (DENR) (1998) Technical Report: Integrating Conservation and Development in Protected Area Management in the Norhern Sierra Madre Natural Park, The Philippines. NORDECO, Copenhagen and DENR, Manila. 205 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref37"><unstructured_citation>Siler CD, Jones RM, Diesmos AC, Diesmos ML, Brown RM (2012) Phylogeny-based species delimitation in Philippine slender skinks (Reptilia: Squamata: Scincidae) III: taxonomic revision of Brachymeles gracilis and description of three new species. Herpetological Monographs.</unstructured_citation></citation>
</citation_list>
</doi_citations>
</body>
</doi_batch>
