<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doi_batch version="4.3.0" xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/doi_resources_schema/4.3.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/doi_resources_schema/4.3.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/deposit/doi_resources4.3.0.xsd">
<head>
<doi_batch_id>019de811-5479-4766-ac1a-b6475a09d90b</doi_batch_id>
<depositor>
<name>pens</name>
<email_address>bozhin.karaivanov@gmail.com</email_address>
</depositor>
</head>
<body>
<doi_citations>
<doi>part-2-266-3982</doi>
<citation_list>
	<citation key="ref0"><doi>10.1130/0016-7606(1989)101&lt;0663:GATSOT&gt;2.3.CO;2</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref0"><doi>10.3724/SP.J.1245.2012.00001</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref0"><doi>10.2307/3544090</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref1"><author>Dickerson</author><cYear>1928</cYear><volume_title>Distribution of life in the Philippines</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Dickerson RE (1928) Distribution of life in the Philippines. Philippine Bureau of Science, Manila.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref1"><doi>10.1643/0045-8511(2002)002[1037:NSONMF]2.0.CO;2</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref1"><doi>10.2744/CCB-0672.1</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref2"><author>Diesmos</author><first_page>26</first_page><cYear>2002</cYear><volume_title>Philippine Biodiversity Conservation Priorities a Second Iteration of the National Biodiversity Strategy and Action Plan</volume_title><article_title>Philippine amphibians and reptiles.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Diesmos AC, Brown RM, Alcala AC, Sison RV, Afuang LE, Gee GVA (2002) Philippine amphibians and reptiles. Pp. 26–44 In: Ong PS, Afuang LE, Rosell-Ambal RG (Eds) Philippine Biodiversity Conservation Priorities: a Second Iteration of the National Biodiversity Strategy and Action Plan. Department of the Environment and Natural Resources–Protected Areas and Wildlife Bureau, Conservation International Philippines, Biodiversity Conservation Program–University of the Philippines Center for Integrative and Developmental Studies, and Foundation for the Philippine Environment, Quezon City, Philippines.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref3"><journal_title>Sylvatrop Technical Journal of Philippine Ecosystems and Natural Resources</journal_title><author>Diesmos</author><volume>13</volume><first_page>63</first_page><cYear>2005</cYear><article_title>Preliminary report on the amphibians and reptiles of Balbalasang-Balbalan National Park, Luzon Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Diesmos AC, Brown RM, Gee GVA (2005) Preliminary report on the amphibians and reptiles of Balbalasang-Balbalan National Park, Luzon Island, Philippines. Sylvatrop Technical Journal of Philippine Ecosystems and Natural Resources 13: 63–80.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref4"><journal_title>Journal of Environmental Science and Management Philippines</journal_title><author>Diesmos</author><volume>9</volume><first_page>41</first_page><cYear>2006</cYear><article_title>Status and distribution of alien invasive frogs in the Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Diesmos AC, Diesmos ML, Brown RM (2006) Status and distribution of alien invasive frogs in the Philippines. Journal of Environmental Science and Management, Philippines 9: 41–53.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref5"><author>Dickinson</author><cYear>1991</cYear><volume_title>The birds of the Philippines</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Dickinson EC, Kennedy RS, Parkes KC (1991) The birds of the Philippines. British Ornithologist's Union, Dorset.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref6"><author>Ernst</author><cYear>2000</cYear><volume_title>Turtles of the World</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Ernst CH, Altenburg RGM, Barbour RW (2000) Turtles of the World. Amsterdam: Expert Center for Taxo- nomic Identification, World Biodiversity Database, CD-ROM Series, University of Amsterdam.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref6"><doi>10.1016/j.ympev.2009.05.034</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref7"><issn>03050270</issn><journal_title>J Biogeogr</journal_title><author>Esselstyn</author><volume>37</volume><first_page>1504</first_page><cYear>2010</cYear><article_title>Colonization of the Philippines from Taiwan: a multi-locus test of the biogeographic and phylogenetic relationships of isolated populations of shrews.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Esselstyn JA, Oliveros CA (2010) Colonization of the Philippines from Taiwan: a multi-locus test of the biogeographic and phylogenetic relationships of isolated populations of shrews.  Journal of Biogeography 37: 1504–1514.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref7"><doi>10.1111/j.1558-5646.2009.00743.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref8"><issn>0006324X</issn><journal_title>Proc Biol Soc Wash</journal_title><author>Esselstyn</author><volume>117</volume><first_page>271</first_page><cYear>2004</cYear><article_title>The mammals of Palawan Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Esselstyn JA, Widmann P, Heaney LR (2004) The mammals of Palawan Island, Philippines. Proceedings of the Biological Society of Washington 117: 271–302.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref9"><issn>01150243</issn><journal_title>Philipp Q Cult Soc</journal_title><author>Estioko–Griffin</author><volume>3</volume><first_page>237</first_page><cYear>1975</cYear><article_title>The Ebuked Agta of northeast Luzon.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Estioko–Griffin AA, Griffin PB (1975) The Ebuked Agta of northeast Luzon. Philippine Quarterly of Culture and Society 3: 237–244.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref10"><issn>10635157</issn><journal_title>Syst Biol</journal_title><author>Evans</author><volume>52</volume><first_page>794</first_page><cYear>2003</cYear><article_title>Phylogenetics of fanged frogs: testing biogeographical hypotheses at the interface of the Asian and Australian faunal zones.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Evans BJ, Brown RM, McGuire JA, Supriatna J, Andayani N, Diesmos A, Iskandar D, Melnick DJ, Cannatella DC (2003) Phylogenetics of fanged frogs: testing biogeographical hypotheses at the interface of the Asian and Australian faunal zones. Systematic Biology 52: 794–819.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref11"><issn>03702774</issn><journal_title>Proc Zool Soc Lond</journal_title><author>Everett</author><volume>1889</volume><first_page>220</first_page><cYear>1889</cYear><article_title>Remarks on the zoogeographical relationships of the island of Palawan and some adjacent islands.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Everett AH (1889) Remarks on the zoogeographical relationships of the island of Palawan and some adjacent islands. Proceedings of the Zoological Society of London 1889: 220–228.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref11"><doi>10.2307/1565386</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref12"><issn>10513825</issn><journal_title>Asiat Herpetol Res</journal_title><author>Ferner</author><volume>9</volume><first_page>34</first_page><cYear>2001</cYear><article_title>The amphibians and reptiles of Panay Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Ferner JW, Brown RM, Sison RV, Kennedy RS (2001) The amphibians and reptiles of Panay Island, Philippines. Asiatic Herpetological Research 9: 34–70.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref12"><doi>10.1029/94TC00453</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref13"><journal_title>Vertebrate Zoology</journal_title><author>Fritz</author><volume>57</volume><first_page>149</first_page><cYear>2007</cYear><article_title>Checklist of the chelonians of the world.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Fritz U, Havas P (2007) Checklist of the chelonians of the world. Vertebrate Zoology 57: 149–368.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref13"><doi>10.1655/HERPETOLOGICA-D-10-00042.1</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref14"><issn>09346643</issn><journal_title>Mertensiella</journal_title><author>Gaulke</author><volume>15</volume><first_page>143</first_page><cYear>1991</cYear><article_title>On the diet of the water monitor, Varanus salvator, in the Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gaulke M (1991a) On the diet of the water monitor, Varanus salvator, in the Philippines. Mertensiella 15: 143–153.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref15"><issn>09346643</issn><journal_title>Mertensiella</journal_title><author>Gaulke</author><volume>15</volume><first_page>154</first_page><cYear>1991</cYear><article_title>Systematic relationships of the Philippine water monitors as compared with Varanus salvator salvator, with a discussion of possible dispersal routes.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gaulke M (1991b) Systematic relationships of the Philippine water monitors as compared with Varanus salvator salvator, with a discussion of possible dispersal routes. Mertensiella 15: 154–167.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref16"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Gaulke</author><volume>121</volume><first_page>345</first_page><cYear>1992</cYear><article_title>Taxonomy and biology of the Philippine monitors (Varanus salvator).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gaulke M (1992a) Taxonomy and biology of the Philippine monitors (Varanus salvator). Phillippine Journal of Science 121: 345–381.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref17"><journal_title>Hamadryad</journal_title><author>Gaulke</author><volume>17</volume><first_page>21</first_page><cYear>1992</cYear><article_title>Distribution, population density, and exploitation of the water monitor in the Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gaulke M (1992b) Distribution, population density, and exploitation of the water monitor in the Philippines. Hamadryad 17: 21–27.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref18"><author>Gaulke</author><first_page>137</first_page><cYear>1998</cYear><volume_title>Conservation Trade and Sustainable Use of Lizards and Snakes in Indonesia Mertensiella suppliment to Salmandra 9</volume_title><article_title>Utilization and conservation of lizards and snakes in the Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gaulke M (1998) Utilization and conservation of lizards and snakes in the Philippines. Pp. 137–142 In: Erdelen W (Ed) Conservation, Trade and Sustainable Use of Lizards and Snakes in Indonesia. Mertensiella, suppliment to Salmandra 9.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref19"><journal_title>Herpetofauna</journal_title><author>Gaulke</author><volume>23</volume><first_page>23</first_page><cYear>2001</cYear><article_title>Die Herpetofauna von Sibaliw (Panay), einem der letzten Tieflandregenwaldgebiete der West-Visayas, Philippinen. Teil II: Schlangen.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gaulke M (2001) Die Herpetofauna von Sibaliw (Panay), einem der letzten Tieflandregenwaldgebiete der West-Visayas, Philippinen. Teil II: Schlangen. Herpetofauna 23: 23–34.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><author>Gray</author><cYear>1845</cYear><volume_title>Catalogue of the specimens of lizards in the collection of the British Museum</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Gray JE (1845) Catalogue of the specimens of lizards in the collection of the British Museum. Edward Newman, London. 125 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref21"><issn>03702774</issn><journal_title>Proc Zool Soc Lond</journal_title><author>Gray</author><volume>1864</volume><first_page>76</first_page><cYear>1864</cYear><article_title>Revision of the species of Trionychidae found in Asia and Africa, with the descriptions of some new species.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gray JE (1864) Revision of the species of Trionychidae found in Asia and Africa, with the descriptions of some new species. Proceedings of the Zoological Society of London 1864: 76–98.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref22"><issn>00069698</issn><journal_title>Breviora</journal_title><author>Gray</author><volume>275</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1967</cYear><article_title>A new scincid lizard from the northern Solomon Islands.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gray JE, Parker F (1967) A new scincid lizard from the northern Solomon Islands. Breviora 275: 1–20.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref23"><journal_title>Miscellaneous Publications of the University of Kansas Museum of Natural History</journal_title><author>Gyi</author><volume>29</volume><first_page>47</first_page><cYear>1970</cYear><article_title>A revision of the colubrid snakes of the subfamily Homolopsinae.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gyi K (1970) A revision of the colubrid snakes of the subfamily Homolopsinae. Miscellaneous Publications of the University of Kansas Museum of Natural History 29: 47–223.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref24"><author>Hall</author><first_page>35</first_page><cYear>2001</cYear><volume_title>Faunal and floral migrations and evolution in SE Asia–Australia</volume_title><article_title>Cenozoic reconstructions of SE Asia and the SW Pacific: Changing patterns of land and sea.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Hall R (2001) Cenozoic reconstructions of SE Asia and the SW Pacific: Changing patterns of land and sea. In: Metcalfe I, Smith J, Morwood M, Davidson I (Eds) Faunal and floral migrations and evolution in SE Asia–Australia. Swets and ZeitlInger Lisse, Netherlands, 35–56.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref24"><doi>10.1016/S1367-9120(01)00069-4</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref25"><author>Heyer</author><cYear>1994</cYear><volume_title>Measuring and Monitoring Biological Diversity Standard Methods for Amphibians</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Heyer WR, Donnelly MA, McDiarmid RW, Hayek L-AC, Foster MS (1994) Measuring and Monitoring Biological Diversity: Standard Methods for Amphibians. Smithsonian Institution Press, Washington D.C.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref25"><doi>10.1046/j.1365-2699.2000.00163.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref25"><doi>10.1111/j.1365-2699.2004.01120.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref26"><author>Hicks</author><cYear>2000</cYear><volume_title>The National Parks and Other Wild Places of the Philippines</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Hicks N (2000) The National Parks and Other Wild Places of the Philippines. New Holland Publishers, London, United Kingdom.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref27"><journal_title>Fieldiana</journal_title><author>Hoogstral</author><volume>33</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1951</cYear><article_title>Philippine Zoological Expedition 1946-1947: narrative and itinerary.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Hoogstral H (1951) Philippine Zoological Expedition 1946-1947: narrative and itinerary. Fieldiana 33: 1–86.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref28"><issn>03702774</issn><journal_title>Proc Zool Soc Lond</journal_title><author>Huxley</author><volume>1868</volume><first_page>296</first_page><cYear>1868</cYear><article_title>On the classification and distribution of the Alectoromorphae and Heteromorphae.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Huxley TH (1868) On the classification and distribution of the Alectoromorphae and Heteromorphae. Proceedings of the Zoological Society of London 1868: 296–319.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><issn>09442006</issn><journal_title>Zoology</journal_title><author>Inger</author><volume>33</volume><first_page>182</first_page><cYear>1954</cYear><article_title>Systematics aend zoogeography of Philippine Amphibia. Fieldiana</article_title><unstructured_citation>Inger RF (1954) Systematics aend zoogeography of Philippine Amphibia. Fieldiana: Zoology 33: 182–531.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><journal_title>Fieldiana</journal_title><author>Inger</author><volume>49</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1965</cYear><article_title>The systematics and evolution of the Oriental snake genus Calamaria.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Inger RF, Marx H (1965) The systematics and evolution of the Oriental snake genus Calamaria. Fieldiana 49: 1–304.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><doi>10.1046/j.1365-2699.2001.00580.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><author>Iskandar</author><cYear>2000</cYear><volume_title>Turtles and Crocodiles of Insular Southeast Asia and New Guinea</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Iskandar DT (2000) Turtles and Crocodiles of Insular Southeast Asia and New Guinea. Bandung Institute of Technology, Bandung, Indonesia.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><doi>10.1080/10635150500431254</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><doi>10.1111/j.1095-8312.2008.01073.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref32"><journal_title>Bulletin of the Raffles Museum</journal_title><author>Kloss</author><volume>2</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1929</cYear><article_title>The zoo-geographical boundaries between Asia and Australia and some Oriental sub-regions.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Kloss B (1929) The zoo-geographical boundaries between Asia and Australia and some Oriental sub-regions. Bulletin of the Raffles Museum 2: 1–10.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref32"><doi>10.5962/bhl.title.40284</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref32"><doi>10.2307/1312382</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref32"><doi>10.2108/zsj.28.12</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref32"><doi>10.1111/j.1463-6409.2012.00562.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref32"><doi>10.2108/zsj.27.222</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref32"><unstructured_citation>Diesmos AC (1998) The Amphibian Faunas of Mt. Banahao, Mt. San Cristobal, and Mt. Maquiling, Luzon Island, Philippines. MS thesis, University of the Philippines at Los Ba-os, College, Laguna, Philippines. 115 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref32"><unstructured_citation>Diesmos AC (2008) Ecology and diversity of herpetofaunal communities in fragmented lowland rainforests in the Philippines. Ph.D. dissertation, National University of Singapore, Singapore. 224 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref32"><unstructured_citation>Diesmos AC, Brown RM (2011) Diversity, Biogeography, and Conservation of Philippine Amphibians. Pp. 26–49 In: Biology and Conservation of Tropical Asian Amphibians. Proceedings of the Conference &quot;Biology of the Amphibians in the Sunda Region, South-east Asia.&quot; In: Das I, Haas A, Tuen AA (2011) Institute of Biodiversity and Environmental Conservation, Universiti Malaysia Sarawak, Kota Samarahan, Sarawak, Malaysia.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref32"><unstructured_citation>Gaulke M (2011) The Herpetofauna of Panay Island, Philippines. Chimaira Buchhandelsgesellschaft mbH; Frankfurt,Germany.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref32"><unstructured_citation>Griffin PB, Estioko–Griffin A (1985) The Agta of Northeastern Luzon: Recent Studies. San Carlos Publications, Cebu City, 189 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref32"><unstructured_citation>Hall R (1998) The plate tectonics of Cenozoic SE Asia and the distribution of land and sea. In: Hall R, Holloway JD (Eds) Biogeography and geological evolution of SE Asia. Backhuys Publications, Lieden, 99–131.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref32"><unstructured_citation>Inger RF (1999) Distributions of amphibians in southern Asia and adjacent islands. In: Duellman WE (Ed) Patterns of distribution of amphibians, a global perspective, 445–482. Johns Hopkins University Press, Baltimore.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref32"><unstructured_citation>IUCN (2010) Guidelines for using the IUCN redlist categories and criteria, version 8.1. http://intranet.iucn.org/webfiles/doc/SSC/RedList/RedListGuidelines.pdf [accessed on August 15 2011]</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref32"><unstructured_citation>IUCN (2011) IUCN Red List of Threatened Species. Version 2011.1. www.iucnredlist.org</unstructured_citation></citation>
</citation_list>
</doi_citations>
</body>
</doi_batch>
