<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doi_batch version="4.3.0" xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/doi_resources_schema/4.3.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/doi_resources_schema/4.3.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/deposit/doi_resources4.3.0.xsd">
<head>
<doi_batch_id>1d32f275-fa40-44ef-bbb4-94c93b830500</doi_batch_id>
<depositor>
<name>pens</name>
<email_address>bozhin.karaivanov@gmail.com</email_address>
</depositor>
</head>
<body>
<doi_citations>
<doi>part-1-266-3982</doi>
<citation_list>
	<citation key="ref1"><journal_title>Silliman Journal</journal_title><author>Alcala</author><volume>4</volume><first_page>90</first_page><cYear>1957</cYear><article_title>Philippine notes on the ecology of the giant marine toad.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Alcala AC (1957) Philippine notes on the ecology of the giant marine toad. Silliman Journal 4: 90–96.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref2"><journal_title>University of the Philippines Natural and Applied Sciences Bulletin</journal_title><author>Alcala</author><volume>20</volume><first_page>335</first_page><cYear>1967</cYear><article_title>Population biology of the flying lizard Draco volans on Negros Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Alcala AC (1967) Population biology of the flying lizard Draco volans on Negros Island, Philippines. University of the Philippines Natural and Applied Sciences Bulletin 20: 335–372.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref2"><doi>10.2307/1442238</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref3"><journal_title>Philippine Journal of Biology</journal_title><author>Alcala</author><volume>11</volume><first_page>203</first_page><cYear>1982</cYear><article_title>Reproductive biology of some species of Philautus (Rhacophoridae) and other Philippine anurans. Kalikasan</article_title><unstructured_citation>Alcala AC, Brown WC (1982) Reproductive biology of some species of Philautus (Rhacophoridae) and other Philippine anurans. Kalikasan, Philippine Journal of Biology 11: 203–226</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref4"><issn>0068547X</issn><journal_title>Proc Calif Acad Sci</journal_title><author>Alcala</author><volume>50</volume><first_page>381</first_page><cYear>1998</cYear><article_title>Two new species of the genus Platymantis (Amphibia: Ranidae) from Luzon Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Alcala AC, Brown WC, Diesmos AC (1998) Two new species of the genus Platymantis (Amphibia: Ranidae) from Luzon Island, Philippines. Proceeding of the California Academy of Science 50: 381–388.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref5"><author>Alcala</author><cYear>1998</cYear><volume_title>Philippine Amphibians an Illustrated Field Guide</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Alcala AC, Brown WC (1998) Philippine Amphibians: an Illustrated Field Guide. Bookmark Press, Makati City, Philippines.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref6"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Alcala</author><volume>128</volume><first_page>281</first_page><cYear>1999</cYear><article_title>Philippine frogs of the genus Platymantis (Amphibia: Ranidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Alcala AC, Brown WC (1999) Philippine frogs of the genus Platymantis (Amphibia: Ranidae). Philippine Journal of Science 128: 281–287.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref7"><journal_title>The Philippine Biota</journal_title><author>Alcala</author><volume>15</volume><first_page>57</first_page><cYear>1980</cYear><article_title>Growth and annual reproductive pattern of Rana c. cancrivora on Negros Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Alcala N, Alcala AC (1980) Growth and annual reproductive pattern of Rana c. cancrivora on Negros Island, Philippines. The Philippine Biota 15: 57–68.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref7"><doi>10.1111/j.1365-2699.2004.01114.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref7"><doi>10.1016/j.ympev.2007.10.024</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref8"><journal_title>Forktail</journal_title><author>Allen</author><volume>20</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2004</cYear><article_title>A new species of Gallirallus from Calayan Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Allen D, Oliveros C, Espa-ola CP, Broad G, Gonzalez JCT (2004) A new species of Gallirallus from Calayan Island, Philippines. Forktail 20: 1–7.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref9"><journal_title>Forktail</journal_title><author>Allen</author><volume>22</volume><first_page>57</first_page><cYear>2006</cYear><article_title>New bird records for the Babuyan Islands, Philippines, including two first records for the Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Allen D, Espa-ola CP, Broad G, Oliveros C, Gonzalez JCT (2006) New bird records for the Babuyan Islands, Philippines, including two first records for the Philippines. Forktail 22: 57–70.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref10"><cYear>2004</cYear><volume_title>Guidelines for use of live amphibians and reptiles in field and laboratory research Herpetological Animal Care and Use Committee (HACC)</volume_title><unstructured_citation>American Society of Ichthyologists and Herpetologists (ASIH) (2004) Guidelines for use of live amphibians and reptiles in field and laboratory research. Herpetological Animal Care and Use Committee (HACC), American Society of Ichthyologists and Herpetologists. Lawrence, KS.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref10"><doi>10.2307/1443381</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref10"><doi>10.1017/S0030605300016367</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref11"><issn>00716154</issn><journal_title>Bull Fla State Mus Biol Sci</journal_title><author>Auffenberg</author><volume>32</volume><first_page>151</first_page><cYear>1988</cYear><article_title>Resource partitioning in a community of Philippine skinks (Sauria: Scincidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Auffenberg W, Auffenberg T (1988) Resource partitioning in a community of Philippine skinks (Sauria: Scincidae). Bulletin of the Florida State Museum of Biological Sciences 32: 151–219.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref12"><issn>00716154</issn><journal_title>Bull Fla State Mus Biol Sci</journal_title><author>Auffenberg</author><volume>34</volume><first_page>201</first_page><cYear>1989</cYear><article_title>Reproductive patterns in sympatric Philippine skinks (Sauria: Scincidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Auffenberg W, Auffenberg T (1989) Reproductive patterns in sympatric Philippine skinks (Sauria: Scincidae). Bulletin of the Florida State Museum of Biological Sciences 34: 201–247.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref13"><author>Bain</author><first_page>74</first_page><cYear>2008</cYear><volume_title>Threatened Amphibians of the World Lynx Ediciones Barcelona Spain IUCN - The World Conservation Union Gland Switzerland and Conservation International</volume_title><article_title>Amphibians of the Indomalayan Realm.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bain R, Biju SD, Brown R, Das I, Diesmos A, Dutta S, Gower D, Inger R, Iskandar D, Kaneko Y, Lau MWN, Meegaskumbura M, Ohler A, Papenfuss T, Pethiyagoda R, Stuart B, Wilkinson M, Xie F (2008) Amphibians of the Indomalayan Realm. Pp. 74–79 In: Stuart SN, Hoffmann M, Chanson JS, Cox NA, Berridge R, Ramani P, Young BE (Eds) Threatened Amphibians of the World. Lynx Ediciones, Barcelona, Spain; IUCN - The World Conservation Union, Gland, Switzerland; and Conservation International, Arlington Virginia, USA.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref13"><doi>10.1080/00222939109460639</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref13"><doi>10.1515/9783110885958</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref14"><issn>00143820</issn><journal_title>Evolution</journal_title><author>Blackburn</author><article_title>An adaptive radiation of frogs in a Southeast Asian island archipelago.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Blackburn DC, Siler CD, Diesmos AC, McGuire JA, Cannatella DC, Brown RM (In review) An adaptive radiation of frogs in a Southeast Asian island archipelago. Evolution.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref15"><issn>03745481</issn><journal_title>Ann Mag Nat Hist</journal_title><author>Boulenger</author><volume>80</volume><first_page>6</first_page><cYear>1894</cYear><article_title>On the herpetological fauna of Palawan and Balabac.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Boulenger GA (1894) On the herpetological fauna of Palawan and Balabac. Annals and Magazine of Natural History 80: 6–90.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref16"><issn>02172445</issn><journal_title>Raffles Bull Zool</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>54</volume><first_page>225</first_page><cYear>2006</cYear><article_title>A case of suspected coral snake mimicry by lepidopteran larvae.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown RM (2006) A case of suspected coral snake mimicry by lepidopteran larvae. Raffles Bulletin of Zoology 54: 225–227.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref17"><author>Brown</author><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2007</cYear><volume_title>Systematics and Zoogeography of Philippine Amphibia</volume_title><article_title>Introduction to Robert F. Inger's Systematics and Zoogeography of Philippine Amphibia. Forward to the reprint of Inger's 1954 monograph.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown RM (2007) Introduction to Robert F. Inger's Systematics and Zoogeography of Philippine Amphibia. Forward to the reprint of Inger's 1954 monograph. In: Systematics and Zoogeography of Philippine Amphibia. Natural History Publications, Kota Kinabalu, Malaysia, 1–17.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref18"><journal_title>Technical Journal of Philippine Ecosystems and Natural Resources</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>10</volume><first_page>107</first_page><cYear>2000</cYear><article_title>The lizard genus Luperosaurus: taxonomy, history, and conservation prospects for some of the world's rarest lizards. Sylvatrop</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown RM, Diesmos AC (2000) The lizard genus Luperosaurus: taxonomy, history, and conservation prospects for some of the world's rarest lizards. Sylvatrop: Technical Journal of Philippine Ecosystems and Natural Resources 10: 107–124.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref19"><journal_title>Silliman Journal</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>42</volume><first_page>133</first_page><cYear>2002</cYear><article_title>Application of lineage-based species concepts to oceanic island frog populations: the effects of differing taxonomic philosophies on the estimation of Philippine biodiversity.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown RM, Diesmos AC (2002) Application of lineage-based species concepts to oceanic island frog populations: the effects of differing taxonomic philosophies on the estimation of Philippine biodiversity. Silliman Journal 42: 133–162.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><author>Brown</author><first_page>723</first_page><cYear>2009</cYear><volume_title>Encyclopedia of Islands</volume_title><article_title>Philippines, Biology.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown RM, Diesmos AC (2009) Philippines, Biology. In: Gillespie R, Clague D (Eds) Encyclopedia of Islands. University of California Press, Berkeley, pp. 723–732.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref21"><journal_title>Silliman Journal</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>42</volume><first_page>18</first_page><cYear>2001</cYear><article_title>[2002]) The state of Philippine herpetology and the challenges for the next decade.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown RM, Diesmos AC, Alcala AC (2001 [2002]) The state of Philippine herpetology and the challenges for the next decade. Silliman Journal 42:18–87.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref22"><author>Brown</author><first_page>82</first_page><cYear>2008</cYear><volume_title>Threatened Amphibians of the World Lynx Ediciones Barcelona Spain IUCN - The World Conservation Union Gland Switzerland and Conservation International</volume_title><article_title>Philippine amphibian biodiversity is increasing in leaps and bounds.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown RM, Diesmos AC, Alcala AC (2008) Philippine amphibian biodiversity is increasing in leaps and bounds. In: Stuart SN, Hoffmann M, Chanson JS, Cox NA, Berridge R, Ramani P, Young BE (Eds) Threatened Amphibians of the World. Lynx Ediciones, Barcelona, Spain; IUCN - The World Conservation Union, Gland, Switzerland; and Conservation International, Arlington Virginia, USA, 82–83.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref23"><issn>02172445</issn><journal_title>Raffles Bull Zool</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>55</volume><first_page>153</first_page><cYear>2007</cYear><article_title>A new species of Luperosaurus (Squamata: Gekkonidae) from the Sierra Madre mountain range of northern Luzon Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown RM, Diesmos AC, Duya M (2007) A new species of Luperosaurus (Squamata: Gekkonidae) from the Sierra Madre mountain range of northern Luzon Island, Philippines. Raffles Bulletin of Zoology 55: 153–160.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref23"><doi>10.1670/10-123.1</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref24"><journal_title>Herpetological Natural History</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>4</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1996</cYear><article_title>Amphibians and reptiles of the Zambales mountains of Luzon Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown RM, Ferner JW, Sison RV, Gonzales PC, Kennedy RS (1996) Amphibians and reptiles of the Zambales mountains of Luzon Island, Philippines. Herpetological Natural History 4: 1–17.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref24"><doi>10.1111/j.1095-8312.2002.tb01704.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref25"><issn>10513825</issn><journal_title>Asiat Herpetol Res</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>9</volume><first_page>9</first_page><cYear>2001</cYear><article_title>A new species of snake in the genus Hologerrhum (Reptilia; Squamata; Serpentes) from Panay Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown RM, Leviton AE, Ferner JW, Sison RV (2001) A new species of snake in the genus Hologerrhum (Reptilia; Squamata; Serpentes) from Panay Island, Philippines. Asiatic Herpetological Research 9: 9–22.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref26"><issn>10513825</issn><journal_title>Asiat Herpetol Res</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>8</volume><first_page>7</first_page><cYear>1999</cYear><article_title>Description of a new species of Pseudorabdion (Serpentes: Colubridae) from Panay Island, Philippines with a revised key to the genus.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown RM, Leviton AE, Sison RV (1999) Description of a new species of Pseudorabdion (Serpentes: Colubridae) from Panay Island, Philippines with a revised key to the genus. Asiatic Herpetological Research 8: 7–12.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref27"><journal_title>Scientific Publications of the Natural History Museum of the University of Kansas</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>42</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2010</cYear><article_title>Species boundaries in Philippine montane forest skinks (Genus Sphenomorphus): three new species from the mountains of Luzon and clarification of the status of the poorly known S. beyeri, S. knollmanae, and S. laterimaculatus.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown RM, Linkem CW, Balete D, Duya MV, Diesmos AC, Ferner JW (2010b) Species boundaries in Philippine montane forest skinks (Genus Sphenomorphus): three new species from the mountains of Luzon and clarification of the status of the poorly known S. beyeri, S. knollmanae, and S. laterimaculatus. Scientific Publications of the Natural History Museum of the University of Kansas 42: 1–27</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref27"><doi>10.1016/j.ympev.2010.06.015</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref27"><doi>10.2307/1447481</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref28"><journal_title>Hamadryad</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>25</volume><first_page>175</first_page><cYear>2000</cYear><article_title>Amphibians and reptiles of Luzon Island, II: preliminary report on the herpetofauna of Aurora Memorial National Park, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown RM, McGuire JA, Ferner JW, Icarangal N Jr., Kennedy RS (2000a) Amphibians and reptiles of Luzon Island, II: preliminary report on the herpetofauna of Aurora Memorial National Park, Philippines. Hamadryad 25: 175–195.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><issn>00180831</issn><journal_title>Herpetologica</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>56</volume><first_page>81</first_page><cYear>2000</cYear><article_title>Status of some Philippine frogs related to Rana everetti (Anura: Ranidae), description of a new species, and resurrection of Rana igorota Taylor 1922.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown RM, McGuire JA, Diesmos AC (2000b) Status of some Philippine frogs related to Rana everetti (Anura: Ranidae), description of a new species, and resurrection of Rana igorota Taylor 1922. Herpetologica 56: 81–104.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><doi>10.1655/07-078.1</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><doi>10.1670/08-207.1</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><journal_title>Check List</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>8</volume><first_page>469</first_page><cYear>2012</cYear><article_title>Amphibians and Reptiles, Northern Luzon Island (Philippines), VII: Herpetofauna of Ilocos Norte Province, Northern Cordillera Mountain Range.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown RM, Oliveros CH, Siler CD, Fernandez JB, Welton LJ, Buenavente PAC, Diesmos MLD, Diesmos AC (2012) Amphibians and Reptiles, Northern Luzon Island (Philippines), VII: Herpetofauna of Ilocos Norte Province, Northern Cordillera Mountain Range. Check List 8: 469–490.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><doi>10.1655/09-037.1</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><doi>10.1017/CBO9780511735882.016</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><doi>10.1643/0045-8511(2000)2000[0191:DOANSO]2.0.CO;2</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><doi>10.2307/1933494</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><issn>00372102</issn><journal_title>Senckenb Biol</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>45</volume><first_page>591</first_page><cYear>1963</cYear><article_title>Relationships of the herpetofauna of the non–dipterocarp communities to that of the dipterocarp forest of southern Negros Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown WC, Alcala AC (1963) Relationships of the herpetofauna of the non–dipterocarp communities to that of the dipterocarp forest of southern Negros Island, Philippines. Senckenbergiana Biologica 45: 591–611.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref32"><issn>0068547X</issn><journal_title>Proc Calif Acad Sci</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>38</volume><first_page>105</first_page><cYear>1970</cYear><article_title>The zoogeography of the Philippine Islands, a fringing archipelago.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown WC, Alcala AC (1970a) The zoogeography of the Philippine Islands, a fringing archipelago. Proceedings of the California Academy of Science 38: 105–130.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref32"><doi>10.2307/1442304</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><author>Brown</author><cYear>1978</cYear><volume_title>Philippine Lizards of the Family Gekkonidae</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Brown WC, Alcala AC (1978) Philippine Lizards of the Family Gekkonidae. Silliman University Press, Dumaguete City, Philippines.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref34"><author>Brown</author><cYear>1980</cYear><volume_title>Philippine Lizards of the Family Scincidae</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Brown WC, Alcala AC (1980) Philippine Lizards of the Family Scincidae. Silliman University Press, Dumaguete City, Philippines.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref35"><journal_title>Silliman Journal</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>33</volume><first_page>74</first_page><cYear>1986</cYear><article_title>Comparison of the herpetofaunal species richness on Negros and Cebu Islands, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown WC, Alcala AC (1986) Comparison of the herpetofaunal species richness on Negros and Cebu Islands, Philippines. Silliman Journal 33: 74–86.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref36"><author>Brown</author><first_page>416</first_page><cYear>1982</cYear><volume_title>Advances in Herpetology and Evolutionary Biology Museum of Comparative Biology</volume_title><article_title>Modes of reproduction of Philippine anurans.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown WC, Alcala AC (1982b) Modes of reproduction of Philippine anurans. Pp. 416–428. In: Rodin AGJ, Miyata K (Eds) Advances in Herpetology and Evolutionary Biology. Museum of Comparative Biology, Cambridge, MA, USA.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref37"><issn>0068547X</issn><journal_title>Proc Calif Acad Sci</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>48</volume><issue>2</issue><first_page>185</first_page><cYear>1994</cYear><article_title>Philippine frogs of the family Rhacophoridae.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown WC, Alcala AC (1994) Philippine frogs of the family Rhacophoridae. Proceedings of the California Academy of Sciences 48(2): 185–220.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref38"><issn>0006324X</issn><journal_title>Proc Biol Soc Wash</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>110</volume><first_page>18</first_page><cYear>1997</cYear><article_title>A new species of the genus Platymantis (Amphibia: Ranidae) from Luzon Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown WC, Alcala AC, Diesmos AC (1997a) A new species of the genus Platymantis (Amphibia: Ranidae) from Luzon Island, Philippines. Proceedings of the Biological Society of Washington 110: 18–23.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref39"><issn>0068547X</issn><journal_title>Proc Calif Acad Sci</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>51</volume><first_page>449</first_page><cYear>1999</cYear><article_title>Four new species of the genus Platymantis (Amphibia: Ranidae) from Luzon Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown WC, Alcala AC, Diesmos AC (1999b) Four new species of the genus Platymantis (Amphibia: Ranidae) from Luzon Island, Philippines. Proceedings of the California Academy of Sciences 51: 449–460.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref40"><issn>0068547X</issn><journal_title>Proc Calif Acad Sci</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>50</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1997</cYear><article_title>Species of the guentheri group of Platymantis with descriptions of four new species.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown WC, Alcala AC, Diesmos AC, Alcala E (1997b) Species of the guentheri group of Platymantis with descriptions of four new species. Proceedings of the California Academy of Science 50: 1–20.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref41"><issn>0006324X</issn><journal_title>Proc Biol Soc Wash</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>112</volume><first_page>510</first_page><cYear>1999</cYear><article_title>A new species of Platymantis (Amphibia: Ranidae) from the Sierra Madre Mountains of Luzon Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown WC, Alcala AC, Ong PS, Diesmos AC (1999a) A new species of Platymantis (Amphibia: Ranidae) from the Sierra Madre Mountains of Luzon Island, Philippines. Proceedings of the Biological Society of Washington 112: 510–514.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref42"><issn>0068547X</issn><journal_title>Proc Calif Acad Sci</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>49</volume><first_page>405</first_page><cYear>1997</cYear><article_title>Species of the hazelae group of Platymantis (Amphibia: Ranidae) from the Philippines, with descriptions of two new species.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown WC, Brown RM, Alcala AC (1997c) Species of the hazelae group of Platymantis (Amphibia: Ranidae) from the Philippines, with descriptions of two new species. Proceedings of the California Academy of Science 49: 405–421.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref43"><author>Catibog-Sinha</author><cYear>2006</cYear><volume_title>Philippine Biodiversity Principles and Practice</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Catibog-Sinha CS, Heaney LR (2006) Philippine Biodiversity: Principles and Practice. Quezon City, Haribon Foundation for the Conservation of Natural Resources, Inc.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref44"><author>Darlington</author><cYear>1957</cYear><volume_title>Zoogeography the geographical distribution of animals</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Darlington PJ (1957) Zoogeography: the geographical distribution of animals. Wiley, New York.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref45"><issn>07483007</issn><journal_title>Cladistics</journal_title><author>de Jong</author><volume>12</volume><first_page>323</first_page><cYear>1996</cYear><article_title>The continental Asian element in the fauna of the Philippines as exemplified by Coladenia Moore, 1881 (Lepidoptera: Hesperiidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>de Jong R (1996) The continental Asian element in the fauna of the Philippines as exemplified by Coladenia Moore, 1881 (Lepidoptera: Hesperiidae). Cladistics 12: 323–348.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref45"><unstructured_citation>Afuang LE (1994) Population ecology and distribution of Bufo marinus in the province of Isabella, Philippines. Masters thesis, University of the Philippines at Los Ba-os, Laguna.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref45"><unstructured_citation>Alcala AC (1986) Guide to Philippine Flora and Fauna. Vol X, Amphibians and Reptiles. Natural Resource Management Center, Ministry of Natural Resource Management Center, Ministry of Natural Resources and the University of the Philippines, Manila, Philippines. 195 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref45"><unstructured_citation>Auffenberg W (1988) Gray's Monitor Lizard. University of Florida Press, Gainsville. Florida. 419 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref45"><unstructured_citation>Brown WC, Alcala AC (1974) New frogs of the genus Platymantis (Ranidae) from the Philippines. Occasional Papers of the California Academy of Sciences 113: 1–12.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref45"><unstructured_citation>Carlquist S (1965) Island Life: A Natural History of the Islands of the World. Natural History Press, Dargen City.</unstructured_citation></citation>
</citation_list>
</doi_citations>
</body>
</doi_batch>
