<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doi_batch version="4.3.0" xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/doi_resources_schema/4.3.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/doi_resources_schema/4.3.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/deposit/doi_resources4.3.0.xsd">
<head>
<doi_batch_id>1d32f275-fa40-44ef-bbb4-94c93b830500</doi_batch_id>
<depositor>
<name>pens</name>
<email_address>bozhin.karaivanov@gmail.com</email_address>
</depositor>
</head>
<body>
<doi_citations>
<doi>10.3897/zookeys.266.3982</doi>
<citation_list>
	<citation key="ref1"><journal_title>Silliman Journal</journal_title><author>Alcala</author><volume>4</volume><first_page>90</first_page><cYear>1957</cYear><article_title>Philippine notes on the ecology of the giant marine toad.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Alcala AC (1957) Philippine notes on the ecology of the giant marine toad. Silliman Journal 4: 90–96.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref2"><journal_title>University of the Philippines Natural and Applied Sciences Bulletin</journal_title><author>Alcala</author><volume>20</volume><first_page>335</first_page><cYear>1967</cYear><article_title>Population biology of the flying lizard Draco volans on Negros Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Alcala AC (1967) Population biology of the flying lizard Draco volans on Negros Island, Philippines. University of the Philippines Natural and Applied Sciences Bulletin 20: 335–372.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref3"><doi>10.2307/1442238</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref4"><journal_title>Philippine Journal of Biology</journal_title><author>Alcala</author><volume>11</volume><first_page>203</first_page><cYear>1982</cYear><article_title>Reproductive biology of some species of Philautus (Rhacophoridae) and other Philippine anurans. Kalikasan</article_title><unstructured_citation>Alcala AC, Brown WC (1982) Reproductive biology of some species of Philautus (Rhacophoridae) and other Philippine anurans. Kalikasan, Philippine Journal of Biology 11: 203–226</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref5"><issn>0068547X</issn><journal_title>Proc Calif Acad Sci</journal_title><author>Alcala</author><volume>50</volume><first_page>381</first_page><cYear>1998</cYear><article_title>Two new species of the genus Platymantis (Amphibia: Ranidae) from Luzon Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Alcala AC, Brown WC, Diesmos AC (1998) Two new species of the genus Platymantis (Amphibia: Ranidae) from Luzon Island, Philippines. Proceeding of the California Academy of Science 50: 381–388.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref6"><author>Alcala</author><cYear>1998</cYear><volume_title>Philippine Amphibians an Illustrated Field Guide</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Alcala AC, Brown WC (1998) Philippine Amphibians: an Illustrated Field Guide. Bookmark Press, Makati City, Philippines.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref7"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Alcala</author><volume>128</volume><first_page>281</first_page><cYear>1999</cYear><article_title>Philippine frogs of the genus Platymantis (Amphibia: Ranidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Alcala AC, Brown WC (1999) Philippine frogs of the genus Platymantis (Amphibia: Ranidae). Philippine Journal of Science 128: 281–287.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref8"><journal_title>The Philippine Biota</journal_title><author>Alcala</author><volume>15</volume><first_page>57</first_page><cYear>1980</cYear><article_title>Growth and annual reproductive pattern of Rana c. cancrivora on Negros Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Alcala N, Alcala AC (1980) Growth and annual reproductive pattern of Rana c. cancrivora on Negros Island, Philippines. The Philippine Biota 15: 57–68.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref9"><doi>10.1111/j.1365-2699.2004.01114.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref10"><doi>10.1016/j.ympev.2007.10.024</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref11"><journal_title>Forktail</journal_title><author>Allen</author><volume>20</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2004</cYear><article_title>A new species of Gallirallus from Calayan Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Allen D, Oliveros C, Espa-ola CP, Broad G, Gonzalez JCT (2004) A new species of Gallirallus from Calayan Island, Philippines. Forktail 20: 1–7.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref12"><journal_title>Forktail</journal_title><author>Allen</author><volume>22</volume><first_page>57</first_page><cYear>2006</cYear><article_title>New bird records for the Babuyan Islands, Philippines, including two first records for the Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Allen D, Espa-ola CP, Broad G, Oliveros C, Gonzalez JCT (2006) New bird records for the Babuyan Islands, Philippines, including two first records for the Philippines. Forktail 22: 57–70.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref13"><cYear>2004</cYear><volume_title>Guidelines for use of live amphibians and reptiles in field and laboratory research Herpetological Animal Care and Use Committee (HACC)</volume_title><unstructured_citation>American Society of Ichthyologists and Herpetologists (ASIH) (2004) Guidelines for use of live amphibians and reptiles in field and laboratory research. Herpetological Animal Care and Use Committee (HACC), American Society of Ichthyologists and Herpetologists. Lawrence, KS.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref14"><doi>10.2307/1443381</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref15"><doi>10.1017/S0030605300016367</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref16"><issn>00716154</issn><journal_title>Bull Fla State Mus Biol Sci</journal_title><author>Auffenberg</author><volume>32</volume><first_page>151</first_page><cYear>1988</cYear><article_title>Resource partitioning in a community of Philippine skinks (Sauria: Scincidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Auffenberg W, Auffenberg T (1988) Resource partitioning in a community of Philippine skinks (Sauria: Scincidae). Bulletin of the Florida State Museum of Biological Sciences 32: 151–219.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref17"><issn>00716154</issn><journal_title>Bull Fla State Mus Biol Sci</journal_title><author>Auffenberg</author><volume>34</volume><first_page>201</first_page><cYear>1989</cYear><article_title>Reproductive patterns in sympatric Philippine skinks (Sauria: Scincidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Auffenberg W, Auffenberg T (1989) Reproductive patterns in sympatric Philippine skinks (Sauria: Scincidae). Bulletin of the Florida State Museum of Biological Sciences 34: 201–247.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref18"><author>Bain</author><first_page>74</first_page><cYear>2008</cYear><volume_title>Threatened Amphibians of the World Lynx Ediciones Barcelona Spain IUCN - The World Conservation Union Gland Switzerland and Conservation International</volume_title><article_title>Amphibians of the Indomalayan Realm.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Bain R, Biju SD, Brown R, Das I, Diesmos A, Dutta S, Gower D, Inger R, Iskandar D, Kaneko Y, Lau MWN, Meegaskumbura M, Ohler A, Papenfuss T, Pethiyagoda R, Stuart B, Wilkinson M, Xie F (2008) Amphibians of the Indomalayan Realm. Pp. 74–79 In: Stuart SN, Hoffmann M, Chanson JS, Cox NA, Berridge R, Ramani P, Young BE (Eds) Threatened Amphibians of the World. Lynx Ediciones, Barcelona, Spain; IUCN - The World Conservation Union, Gland, Switzerland; and Conservation International, Arlington Virginia, USA.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref19"><doi>10.1080/00222939109460639</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref20"><doi>10.1515/9783110885958</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref21"><issn>00143820</issn><journal_title>Evolution</journal_title><author>Blackburn</author><article_title>An adaptive radiation of frogs in a Southeast Asian island archipelago.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Blackburn DC, Siler CD, Diesmos AC, McGuire JA, Cannatella DC, Brown RM (In review) An adaptive radiation of frogs in a Southeast Asian island archipelago. Evolution.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref22"><issn>03745481</issn><journal_title>Ann Mag Nat Hist</journal_title><author>Boulenger</author><volume>80</volume><first_page>6</first_page><cYear>1894</cYear><article_title>On the herpetological fauna of Palawan and Balabac.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Boulenger GA (1894) On the herpetological fauna of Palawan and Balabac. Annals and Magazine of Natural History 80: 6–90.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref23"><issn>02172445</issn><journal_title>Raffles Bull Zool</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>54</volume><first_page>225</first_page><cYear>2006</cYear><article_title>A case of suspected coral snake mimicry by lepidopteran larvae.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown RM (2006) A case of suspected coral snake mimicry by lepidopteran larvae. Raffles Bulletin of Zoology 54: 225–227.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref24"><author>Brown</author><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2007</cYear><volume_title>Systematics and Zoogeography of Philippine Amphibia</volume_title><article_title>Introduction to Robert F. Inger's Systematics and Zoogeography of Philippine Amphibia. Forward to the reprint of Inger's 1954 monograph.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown RM (2007) Introduction to Robert F. Inger's Systematics and Zoogeography of Philippine Amphibia. Forward to the reprint of Inger's 1954 monograph. In: Systematics and Zoogeography of Philippine Amphibia. Natural History Publications, Kota Kinabalu, Malaysia, 1–17.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref25"><journal_title>Technical Journal of Philippine Ecosystems and Natural Resources</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>10</volume><first_page>107</first_page><cYear>2000</cYear><article_title>The lizard genus Luperosaurus: taxonomy, history, and conservation prospects for some of the world's rarest lizards. Sylvatrop</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown RM, Diesmos AC (2000) The lizard genus Luperosaurus: taxonomy, history, and conservation prospects for some of the world's rarest lizards. Sylvatrop: Technical Journal of Philippine Ecosystems and Natural Resources 10: 107–124.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref26"><journal_title>Silliman Journal</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>42</volume><first_page>133</first_page><cYear>2002</cYear><article_title>Application of lineage-based species concepts to oceanic island frog populations: the effects of differing taxonomic philosophies on the estimation of Philippine biodiversity.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown RM, Diesmos AC (2002) Application of lineage-based species concepts to oceanic island frog populations: the effects of differing taxonomic philosophies on the estimation of Philippine biodiversity. Silliman Journal 42: 133–162.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref27"><author>Brown</author><first_page>723</first_page><cYear>2009</cYear><volume_title>Encyclopedia of Islands</volume_title><article_title>Philippines, Biology.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown RM, Diesmos AC (2009) Philippines, Biology. In: Gillespie R, Clague D (Eds) Encyclopedia of Islands. University of California Press, Berkeley, pp. 723–732.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref28"><journal_title>Silliman Journal</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>42</volume><first_page>18</first_page><cYear>2001</cYear><article_title>[2002]) The state of Philippine herpetology and the challenges for the next decade.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown RM, Diesmos AC, Alcala AC (2001 [2002]) The state of Philippine herpetology and the challenges for the next decade. Silliman Journal 42:18–87.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref29"><author>Brown</author><first_page>82</first_page><cYear>2008</cYear><volume_title>Threatened Amphibians of the World Lynx Ediciones Barcelona Spain IUCN - The World Conservation Union Gland Switzerland and Conservation International</volume_title><article_title>Philippine amphibian biodiversity is increasing in leaps and bounds.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown RM, Diesmos AC, Alcala AC (2008) Philippine amphibian biodiversity is increasing in leaps and bounds. In: Stuart SN, Hoffmann M, Chanson JS, Cox NA, Berridge R, Ramani P, Young BE (Eds) Threatened Amphibians of the World. Lynx Ediciones, Barcelona, Spain; IUCN - The World Conservation Union, Gland, Switzerland; and Conservation International, Arlington Virginia, USA, 82–83.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref30"><issn>02172445</issn><journal_title>Raffles Bull Zool</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>55</volume><first_page>153</first_page><cYear>2007</cYear><article_title>A new species of Luperosaurus (Squamata: Gekkonidae) from the Sierra Madre mountain range of northern Luzon Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown RM, Diesmos AC, Duya M (2007) A new species of Luperosaurus (Squamata: Gekkonidae) from the Sierra Madre mountain range of northern Luzon Island, Philippines. Raffles Bulletin of Zoology 55: 153–160.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref31"><doi>10.1670/10-123.1</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref32"><journal_title>Herpetological Natural History</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>4</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1996</cYear><article_title>Amphibians and reptiles of the Zambales mountains of Luzon Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown RM, Ferner JW, Sison RV, Gonzales PC, Kennedy RS (1996) Amphibians and reptiles of the Zambales mountains of Luzon Island, Philippines. Herpetological Natural History 4: 1–17.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref33"><doi>10.1111/j.1095-8312.2002.tb01704.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref34"><issn>10513825</issn><journal_title>Asiat Herpetol Res</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>9</volume><first_page>9</first_page><cYear>2001</cYear><article_title>A new species of snake in the genus Hologerrhum (Reptilia; Squamata; Serpentes) from Panay Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown RM, Leviton AE, Ferner JW, Sison RV (2001) A new species of snake in the genus Hologerrhum (Reptilia; Squamata; Serpentes) from Panay Island, Philippines. Asiatic Herpetological Research 9: 9–22.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref35"><issn>10513825</issn><journal_title>Asiat Herpetol Res</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>8</volume><first_page>7</first_page><cYear>1999</cYear><article_title>Description of a new species of Pseudorabdion (Serpentes: Colubridae) from Panay Island, Philippines with a revised key to the genus.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown RM, Leviton AE, Sison RV (1999) Description of a new species of Pseudorabdion (Serpentes: Colubridae) from Panay Island, Philippines with a revised key to the genus. Asiatic Herpetological Research 8: 7–12.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref36"><journal_title>Scientific Publications of the Natural History Museum of the University of Kansas</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>42</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2010</cYear><article_title>Species boundaries in Philippine montane forest skinks (Genus Sphenomorphus): three new species from the mountains of Luzon and clarification of the status of the poorly known S. beyeri, S. knollmanae, and S. laterimaculatus.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown RM, Linkem CW, Balete D, Duya MV, Diesmos AC, Ferner JW (2010b) Species boundaries in Philippine montane forest skinks (Genus Sphenomorphus): three new species from the mountains of Luzon and clarification of the status of the poorly known S. beyeri, S. knollmanae, and S. laterimaculatus. Scientific Publications of the Natural History Museum of the University of Kansas 42: 1–27</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref37"><doi>10.1016/j.ympev.2010.06.015</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref38"><doi>10.2307/1447481</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref39"><journal_title>Hamadryad</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>25</volume><first_page>175</first_page><cYear>2000</cYear><article_title>Amphibians and reptiles of Luzon Island, II: preliminary report on the herpetofauna of Aurora Memorial National Park, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown RM, McGuire JA, Ferner JW, Icarangal N Jr., Kennedy RS (2000a) Amphibians and reptiles of Luzon Island, II: preliminary report on the herpetofauna of Aurora Memorial National Park, Philippines. Hamadryad 25: 175–195.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref40"><issn>00180831</issn><journal_title>Herpetologica</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>56</volume><first_page>81</first_page><cYear>2000</cYear><article_title>Status of some Philippine frogs related to Rana everetti (Anura: Ranidae), description of a new species, and resurrection of Rana igorota Taylor 1922.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown RM, McGuire JA, Diesmos AC (2000b) Status of some Philippine frogs related to Rana everetti (Anura: Ranidae), description of a new species, and resurrection of Rana igorota Taylor 1922. Herpetologica 56: 81–104.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref41"><doi>10.1655/07-078.1</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref42"><doi>10.1670/08-207.1</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref43"><journal_title>Check List</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>8</volume><first_page>469</first_page><cYear>2012</cYear><article_title>Amphibians and Reptiles, Northern Luzon Island (Philippines), VII: Herpetofauna of Ilocos Norte Province, Northern Cordillera Mountain Range.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown RM, Oliveros CH, Siler CD, Fernandez JB, Welton LJ, Buenavente PAC, Diesmos MLD, Diesmos AC (2012) Amphibians and Reptiles, Northern Luzon Island (Philippines), VII: Herpetofauna of Ilocos Norte Province, Northern Cordillera Mountain Range. Check List 8: 469–490.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref44"><doi>10.1655/09-037.1</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref45"><doi>10.1017/CBO9780511735882.016</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref46"><doi>10.1643/0045-8511(2000)2000[0191:DOANSO]2.0.CO;2</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref47"><doi>10.2307/1933494</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref48"><issn>00372102</issn><journal_title>Senckenb Biol</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>45</volume><first_page>591</first_page><cYear>1963</cYear><article_title>Relationships of the herpetofauna of the non–dipterocarp communities to that of the dipterocarp forest of southern Negros Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown WC, Alcala AC (1963) Relationships of the herpetofauna of the non–dipterocarp communities to that of the dipterocarp forest of southern Negros Island, Philippines. Senckenbergiana Biologica 45: 591–611.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref49"><issn>0068547X</issn><journal_title>Proc Calif Acad Sci</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>38</volume><first_page>105</first_page><cYear>1970</cYear><article_title>The zoogeography of the Philippine Islands, a fringing archipelago.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown WC, Alcala AC (1970a) The zoogeography of the Philippine Islands, a fringing archipelago. Proceedings of the California Academy of Science 38: 105–130.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref50"><doi>10.2307/1442304</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref51"><author>Brown</author><cYear>1978</cYear><volume_title>Philippine Lizards of the Family Gekkonidae</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Brown WC, Alcala AC (1978) Philippine Lizards of the Family Gekkonidae. Silliman University Press, Dumaguete City, Philippines.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref52"><author>Brown</author><cYear>1980</cYear><volume_title>Philippine Lizards of the Family Scincidae</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Brown WC, Alcala AC (1980) Philippine Lizards of the Family Scincidae. Silliman University Press, Dumaguete City, Philippines.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref53"><journal_title>Silliman Journal</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>33</volume><first_page>74</first_page><cYear>1986</cYear><article_title>Comparison of the herpetofaunal species richness on Negros and Cebu Islands, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown WC, Alcala AC (1986) Comparison of the herpetofaunal species richness on Negros and Cebu Islands, Philippines. Silliman Journal 33: 74–86.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref54"><author>Brown</author><first_page>416</first_page><cYear>1982</cYear><volume_title>Advances in Herpetology and Evolutionary Biology Museum of Comparative Biology</volume_title><article_title>Modes of reproduction of Philippine anurans.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown WC, Alcala AC (1982b) Modes of reproduction of Philippine anurans. Pp. 416–428. In: Rodin AGJ, Miyata K (Eds) Advances in Herpetology and Evolutionary Biology. Museum of Comparative Biology, Cambridge, MA, USA.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref55"><issn>0068547X</issn><journal_title>Proc Calif Acad Sci</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>48</volume><issue>2</issue><first_page>185</first_page><cYear>1994</cYear><article_title>Philippine frogs of the family Rhacophoridae.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown WC, Alcala AC (1994) Philippine frogs of the family Rhacophoridae. Proceedings of the California Academy of Sciences 48(2): 185–220.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref56"><issn>0006324X</issn><journal_title>Proc Biol Soc Wash</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>110</volume><first_page>18</first_page><cYear>1997</cYear><article_title>A new species of the genus Platymantis (Amphibia: Ranidae) from Luzon Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown WC, Alcala AC, Diesmos AC (1997a) A new species of the genus Platymantis (Amphibia: Ranidae) from Luzon Island, Philippines. Proceedings of the Biological Society of Washington 110: 18–23.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref57"><issn>0068547X</issn><journal_title>Proc Calif Acad Sci</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>51</volume><first_page>449</first_page><cYear>1999</cYear><article_title>Four new species of the genus Platymantis (Amphibia: Ranidae) from Luzon Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown WC, Alcala AC, Diesmos AC (1999b) Four new species of the genus Platymantis (Amphibia: Ranidae) from Luzon Island, Philippines. Proceedings of the California Academy of Sciences 51: 449–460.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref58"><issn>0068547X</issn><journal_title>Proc Calif Acad Sci</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>50</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1997</cYear><article_title>Species of the guentheri group of Platymantis with descriptions of four new species.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown WC, Alcala AC, Diesmos AC, Alcala E (1997b) Species of the guentheri group of Platymantis with descriptions of four new species. Proceedings of the California Academy of Science 50: 1–20.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref59"><issn>0006324X</issn><journal_title>Proc Biol Soc Wash</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>112</volume><first_page>510</first_page><cYear>1999</cYear><article_title>A new species of Platymantis (Amphibia: Ranidae) from the Sierra Madre Mountains of Luzon Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown WC, Alcala AC, Ong PS, Diesmos AC (1999a) A new species of Platymantis (Amphibia: Ranidae) from the Sierra Madre Mountains of Luzon Island, Philippines. Proceedings of the Biological Society of Washington 112: 510–514.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref60"><issn>0068547X</issn><journal_title>Proc Calif Acad Sci</journal_title><author>Brown</author><volume>49</volume><first_page>405</first_page><cYear>1997</cYear><article_title>Species of the hazelae group of Platymantis (Amphibia: Ranidae) from the Philippines, with descriptions of two new species.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Brown WC, Brown RM, Alcala AC (1997c) Species of the hazelae group of Platymantis (Amphibia: Ranidae) from the Philippines, with descriptions of two new species. Proceedings of the California Academy of Science 49: 405–421.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref61"><author>Catibog-Sinha</author><cYear>2006</cYear><volume_title>Philippine Biodiversity Principles and Practice</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Catibog-Sinha CS, Heaney LR (2006) Philippine Biodiversity: Principles and Practice. Quezon City, Haribon Foundation for the Conservation of Natural Resources, Inc.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref62"><author>Darlington</author><cYear>1957</cYear><volume_title>Zoogeography the geographical distribution of animals</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Darlington PJ (1957) Zoogeography: the geographical distribution of animals. Wiley, New York.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref63"><issn>07483007</issn><journal_title>Cladistics</journal_title><author>de Jong</author><volume>12</volume><first_page>323</first_page><cYear>1996</cYear><article_title>The continental Asian element in the fauna of the Philippines as exemplified by Coladenia Moore, 1881 (Lepidoptera: Hesperiidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>de Jong R (1996) The continental Asian element in the fauna of the Philippines as exemplified by Coladenia Moore, 1881 (Lepidoptera: Hesperiidae). Cladistics 12: 323–348.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref64"><unstructured_citation>Afuang LE (1994) Population ecology and distribution of Bufo marinus in the province of Isabella, Philippines. Masters thesis, University of the Philippines at Los Ba-os, Laguna.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref65"><unstructured_citation>Alcala AC (1986) Guide to Philippine Flora and Fauna. Vol X, Amphibians and Reptiles. Natural Resource Management Center, Ministry of Natural Resource Management Center, Ministry of Natural Resources and the University of the Philippines, Manila, Philippines. 195 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref66"><unstructured_citation>Auffenberg W (1988) Gray's Monitor Lizard. University of Florida Press, Gainsville. Florida. 419 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref67"><unstructured_citation>Brown WC, Alcala AC (1974) New frogs of the genus Platymantis (Ranidae) from the Philippines. Occasional Papers of the California Academy of Sciences 113: 1–12.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref68"><unstructured_citation>Carlquist S (1965) Island Life: A Natural History of the Islands of the World. Natural History Press, Dargen City.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref69"><doi>10.1130/0016-7606(1989)101&lt;0663:GATSOT&gt;2.3.CO;2</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref70"><doi>10.3724/SP.J.1245.2012.00001</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref71"><doi>10.2307/3544090</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref72"><author>Dickerson</author><cYear>1928</cYear><volume_title>Distribution of life in the Philippines</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Dickerson RE (1928) Distribution of life in the Philippines. Philippine Bureau of Science, Manila.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref73"><doi>10.1643/0045-8511(2002)002[1037:NSONMF]2.0.CO;2</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref74"><doi>10.2744/CCB-0672.1</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref75"><author>Diesmos</author><first_page>26</first_page><cYear>2002</cYear><volume_title>Philippine Biodiversity Conservation Priorities a Second Iteration of the National Biodiversity Strategy and Action Plan</volume_title><article_title>Philippine amphibians and reptiles.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Diesmos AC, Brown RM, Alcala AC, Sison RV, Afuang LE, Gee GVA (2002) Philippine amphibians and reptiles. Pp. 26–44 In: Ong PS, Afuang LE, Rosell-Ambal RG (Eds) Philippine Biodiversity Conservation Priorities: a Second Iteration of the National Biodiversity Strategy and Action Plan. Department of the Environment and Natural Resources–Protected Areas and Wildlife Bureau, Conservation International Philippines, Biodiversity Conservation Program–University of the Philippines Center for Integrative and Developmental Studies, and Foundation for the Philippine Environment, Quezon City, Philippines.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref76"><journal_title>Sylvatrop Technical Journal of Philippine Ecosystems and Natural Resources</journal_title><author>Diesmos</author><volume>13</volume><first_page>63</first_page><cYear>2005</cYear><article_title>Preliminary report on the amphibians and reptiles of Balbalasang-Balbalan National Park, Luzon Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Diesmos AC, Brown RM, Gee GVA (2005) Preliminary report on the amphibians and reptiles of Balbalasang-Balbalan National Park, Luzon Island, Philippines. Sylvatrop Technical Journal of Philippine Ecosystems and Natural Resources 13: 63–80.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref77"><journal_title>Journal of Environmental Science and Management Philippines</journal_title><author>Diesmos</author><volume>9</volume><first_page>41</first_page><cYear>2006</cYear><article_title>Status and distribution of alien invasive frogs in the Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Diesmos AC, Diesmos ML, Brown RM (2006) Status and distribution of alien invasive frogs in the Philippines. Journal of Environmental Science and Management, Philippines 9: 41–53.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref78"><author>Dickinson</author><cYear>1991</cYear><volume_title>The birds of the Philippines</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Dickinson EC, Kennedy RS, Parkes KC (1991) The birds of the Philippines. British Ornithologist's Union, Dorset.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref79"><author>Ernst</author><cYear>2000</cYear><volume_title>Turtles of the World</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Ernst CH, Altenburg RGM, Barbour RW (2000) Turtles of the World. Amsterdam: Expert Center for Taxo- nomic Identification, World Biodiversity Database, CD-ROM Series, University of Amsterdam.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref80"><doi>10.1016/j.ympev.2009.05.034</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref81"><issn>03050270</issn><journal_title>J Biogeogr</journal_title><author>Esselstyn</author><volume>37</volume><first_page>1504</first_page><cYear>2010</cYear><article_title>Colonization of the Philippines from Taiwan: a multi-locus test of the biogeographic and phylogenetic relationships of isolated populations of shrews.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Esselstyn JA, Oliveros CA (2010) Colonization of the Philippines from Taiwan: a multi-locus test of the biogeographic and phylogenetic relationships of isolated populations of shrews.  Journal of Biogeography 37: 1504–1514.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref82"><doi>10.1111/j.1558-5646.2009.00743.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref83"><issn>0006324X</issn><journal_title>Proc Biol Soc Wash</journal_title><author>Esselstyn</author><volume>117</volume><first_page>271</first_page><cYear>2004</cYear><article_title>The mammals of Palawan Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Esselstyn JA, Widmann P, Heaney LR (2004) The mammals of Palawan Island, Philippines. Proceedings of the Biological Society of Washington 117: 271–302.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref84"><issn>01150243</issn><journal_title>Philipp Q Cult Soc</journal_title><author>Estioko–Griffin</author><volume>3</volume><first_page>237</first_page><cYear>1975</cYear><article_title>The Ebuked Agta of northeast Luzon.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Estioko–Griffin AA, Griffin PB (1975) The Ebuked Agta of northeast Luzon. Philippine Quarterly of Culture and Society 3: 237–244.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref85"><issn>10635157</issn><journal_title>Syst Biol</journal_title><author>Evans</author><volume>52</volume><first_page>794</first_page><cYear>2003</cYear><article_title>Phylogenetics of fanged frogs: testing biogeographical hypotheses at the interface of the Asian and Australian faunal zones.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Evans BJ, Brown RM, McGuire JA, Supriatna J, Andayani N, Diesmos A, Iskandar D, Melnick DJ, Cannatella DC (2003) Phylogenetics of fanged frogs: testing biogeographical hypotheses at the interface of the Asian and Australian faunal zones. Systematic Biology 52: 794–819.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref86"><issn>03702774</issn><journal_title>Proc Zool Soc Lond</journal_title><author>Everett</author><volume>1889</volume><first_page>220</first_page><cYear>1889</cYear><article_title>Remarks on the zoogeographical relationships of the island of Palawan and some adjacent islands.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Everett AH (1889) Remarks on the zoogeographical relationships of the island of Palawan and some adjacent islands. Proceedings of the Zoological Society of London 1889: 220–228.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref87"><doi>10.2307/1565386</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref88"><issn>10513825</issn><journal_title>Asiat Herpetol Res</journal_title><author>Ferner</author><volume>9</volume><first_page>34</first_page><cYear>2001</cYear><article_title>The amphibians and reptiles of Panay Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Ferner JW, Brown RM, Sison RV, Kennedy RS (2001) The amphibians and reptiles of Panay Island, Philippines. Asiatic Herpetological Research 9: 34–70.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref89"><doi>10.1029/94TC00453</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref90"><journal_title>Vertebrate Zoology</journal_title><author>Fritz</author><volume>57</volume><first_page>149</first_page><cYear>2007</cYear><article_title>Checklist of the chelonians of the world.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Fritz U, Havas P (2007) Checklist of the chelonians of the world. Vertebrate Zoology 57: 149–368.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref91"><doi>10.1655/HERPETOLOGICA-D-10-00042.1</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref92"><issn>09346643</issn><journal_title>Mertensiella</journal_title><author>Gaulke</author><volume>15</volume><first_page>143</first_page><cYear>1991</cYear><article_title>On the diet of the water monitor, Varanus salvator, in the Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gaulke M (1991a) On the diet of the water monitor, Varanus salvator, in the Philippines. Mertensiella 15: 143–153.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref93"><issn>09346643</issn><journal_title>Mertensiella</journal_title><author>Gaulke</author><volume>15</volume><first_page>154</first_page><cYear>1991</cYear><article_title>Systematic relationships of the Philippine water monitors as compared with Varanus salvator salvator, with a discussion of possible dispersal routes.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gaulke M (1991b) Systematic relationships of the Philippine water monitors as compared with Varanus salvator salvator, with a discussion of possible dispersal routes. Mertensiella 15: 154–167.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref94"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Gaulke</author><volume>121</volume><first_page>345</first_page><cYear>1992</cYear><article_title>Taxonomy and biology of the Philippine monitors (Varanus salvator).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gaulke M (1992a) Taxonomy and biology of the Philippine monitors (Varanus salvator). Phillippine Journal of Science 121: 345–381.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref95"><journal_title>Hamadryad</journal_title><author>Gaulke</author><volume>17</volume><first_page>21</first_page><cYear>1992</cYear><article_title>Distribution, population density, and exploitation of the water monitor in the Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gaulke M (1992b) Distribution, population density, and exploitation of the water monitor in the Philippines. Hamadryad 17: 21–27.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref96"><author>Gaulke</author><first_page>137</first_page><cYear>1998</cYear><volume_title>Conservation Trade and Sustainable Use of Lizards and Snakes in Indonesia Mertensiella suppliment to Salmandra 9</volume_title><article_title>Utilization and conservation of lizards and snakes in the Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gaulke M (1998) Utilization and conservation of lizards and snakes in the Philippines. Pp. 137–142 In: Erdelen W (Ed) Conservation, Trade and Sustainable Use of Lizards and Snakes in Indonesia. Mertensiella, suppliment to Salmandra 9.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref97"><journal_title>Herpetofauna</journal_title><author>Gaulke</author><volume>23</volume><first_page>23</first_page><cYear>2001</cYear><article_title>Die Herpetofauna von Sibaliw (Panay), einem der letzten Tieflandregenwaldgebiete der West-Visayas, Philippinen. Teil II: Schlangen.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gaulke M (2001) Die Herpetofauna von Sibaliw (Panay), einem der letzten Tieflandregenwaldgebiete der West-Visayas, Philippinen. Teil II: Schlangen. Herpetofauna 23: 23–34.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref98"><author>Gray</author><cYear>1845</cYear><volume_title>Catalogue of the specimens of lizards in the collection of the British Museum</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Gray JE (1845) Catalogue of the specimens of lizards in the collection of the British Museum. Edward Newman, London. 125 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref99"><issn>03702774</issn><journal_title>Proc Zool Soc Lond</journal_title><author>Gray</author><volume>1864</volume><first_page>76</first_page><cYear>1864</cYear><article_title>Revision of the species of Trionychidae found in Asia and Africa, with the descriptions of some new species.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gray JE (1864) Revision of the species of Trionychidae found in Asia and Africa, with the descriptions of some new species. Proceedings of the Zoological Society of London 1864: 76–98.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref100"><issn>00069698</issn><journal_title>Breviora</journal_title><author>Gray</author><volume>275</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1967</cYear><article_title>A new scincid lizard from the northern Solomon Islands.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gray JE, Parker F (1967) A new scincid lizard from the northern Solomon Islands. Breviora 275: 1–20.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref101"><journal_title>Miscellaneous Publications of the University of Kansas Museum of Natural History</journal_title><author>Gyi</author><volume>29</volume><first_page>47</first_page><cYear>1970</cYear><article_title>A revision of the colubrid snakes of the subfamily Homolopsinae.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Gyi K (1970) A revision of the colubrid snakes of the subfamily Homolopsinae. Miscellaneous Publications of the University of Kansas Museum of Natural History 29: 47–223.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref102"><author>Hall</author><first_page>35</first_page><cYear>2001</cYear><volume_title>Faunal and floral migrations and evolution in SE Asia–Australia</volume_title><article_title>Cenozoic reconstructions of SE Asia and the SW Pacific: Changing patterns of land and sea.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Hall R (2001) Cenozoic reconstructions of SE Asia and the SW Pacific: Changing patterns of land and sea. In: Metcalfe I, Smith J, Morwood M, Davidson I (Eds) Faunal and floral migrations and evolution in SE Asia–Australia. Swets and ZeitlInger Lisse, Netherlands, 35–56.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref103"><doi>10.1016/S1367-9120(01)00069-4</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref104"><author>Heyer</author><cYear>1994</cYear><volume_title>Measuring and Monitoring Biological Diversity Standard Methods for Amphibians</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Heyer WR, Donnelly MA, McDiarmid RW, Hayek L-AC, Foster MS (1994) Measuring and Monitoring Biological Diversity: Standard Methods for Amphibians. Smithsonian Institution Press, Washington D.C.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref105"><doi>10.1046/j.1365-2699.2000.00163.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref106"><doi>10.1111/j.1365-2699.2004.01120.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref107"><author>Hicks</author><cYear>2000</cYear><volume_title>The National Parks and Other Wild Places of the Philippines</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Hicks N (2000) The National Parks and Other Wild Places of the Philippines. New Holland Publishers, London, United Kingdom.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref108"><journal_title>Fieldiana</journal_title><author>Hoogstral</author><volume>33</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1951</cYear><article_title>Philippine Zoological Expedition 1946-1947: narrative and itinerary.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Hoogstral H (1951) Philippine Zoological Expedition 1946-1947: narrative and itinerary. Fieldiana 33: 1–86.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref109"><issn>03702774</issn><journal_title>Proc Zool Soc Lond</journal_title><author>Huxley</author><volume>1868</volume><first_page>296</first_page><cYear>1868</cYear><article_title>On the classification and distribution of the Alectoromorphae and Heteromorphae.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Huxley TH (1868) On the classification and distribution of the Alectoromorphae and Heteromorphae. Proceedings of the Zoological Society of London 1868: 296–319.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref110"><issn>09442006</issn><journal_title>Zoology</journal_title><author>Inger</author><volume>33</volume><first_page>182</first_page><cYear>1954</cYear><article_title>Systematics aend zoogeography of Philippine Amphibia. Fieldiana</article_title><unstructured_citation>Inger RF (1954) Systematics aend zoogeography of Philippine Amphibia. Fieldiana: Zoology 33: 182–531.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref111"><journal_title>Fieldiana</journal_title><author>Inger</author><volume>49</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1965</cYear><article_title>The systematics and evolution of the Oriental snake genus Calamaria.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Inger RF, Marx H (1965) The systematics and evolution of the Oriental snake genus Calamaria. Fieldiana 49: 1–304.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref112"><doi>10.1046/j.1365-2699.2001.00580.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref113"><author>Iskandar</author><cYear>2000</cYear><volume_title>Turtles and Crocodiles of Insular Southeast Asia and New Guinea</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Iskandar DT (2000) Turtles and Crocodiles of Insular Southeast Asia and New Guinea. Bandung Institute of Technology, Bandung, Indonesia.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref114"><doi>10.1080/10635150500431254</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref115"><doi>10.1111/j.1095-8312.2008.01073.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref116"><journal_title>Bulletin of the Raffles Museum</journal_title><author>Kloss</author><volume>2</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>1929</cYear><article_title>The zoo-geographical boundaries between Asia and Australia and some Oriental sub-regions.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Kloss B (1929) The zoo-geographical boundaries between Asia and Australia and some Oriental sub-regions. Bulletin of the Raffles Museum 2: 1–10.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref117"><doi>10.5962/bhl.title.40284</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref118"><doi>10.2307/1312382</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref119"><doi>10.2108/zsj.28.12</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref120"><doi>10.1111/j.1463-6409.2012.00562.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref121"><doi>10.2108/zsj.27.222</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref122"><unstructured_citation>Diesmos AC (1998) The Amphibian Faunas of Mt. Banahao, Mt. San Cristobal, and Mt. Maquiling, Luzon Island, Philippines. MS thesis, University of the Philippines at Los Ba-os, College, Laguna, Philippines. 115 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref123"><unstructured_citation>Diesmos AC (2008) Ecology and diversity of herpetofaunal communities in fragmented lowland rainforests in the Philippines. Ph.D. dissertation, National University of Singapore, Singapore. 224 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref124"><unstructured_citation>Diesmos AC, Brown RM (2011) Diversity, Biogeography, and Conservation of Philippine Amphibians. Pp. 26–49 In: Biology and Conservation of Tropical Asian Amphibians. Proceedings of the Conference &quot;Biology of the Amphibians in the Sunda Region, South-east Asia.&quot; In: Das I, Haas A, Tuen AA (2011) Institute of Biodiversity and Environmental Conservation, Universiti Malaysia Sarawak, Kota Samarahan, Sarawak, Malaysia.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref125"><unstructured_citation>Gaulke M (2011) The Herpetofauna of Panay Island, Philippines. Chimaira Buchhandelsgesellschaft mbH; Frankfurt,Germany.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref126"><unstructured_citation>Griffin PB, Estioko–Griffin A (1985) The Agta of Northeastern Luzon: Recent Studies. San Carlos Publications, Cebu City, 189 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref127"><unstructured_citation>Hall R (1998) The plate tectonics of Cenozoic SE Asia and the distribution of land and sea. In: Hall R, Holloway JD (Eds) Biogeography and geological evolution of SE Asia. Backhuys Publications, Lieden, 99–131.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref128"><unstructured_citation>Inger RF (1999) Distributions of amphibians in southern Asia and adjacent islands. In: Duellman WE (Ed) Patterns of distribution of amphibians, a global perspective, 445–482. Johns Hopkins University Press, Baltimore.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref129"><unstructured_citation>IUCN (2010) Guidelines for using the IUCN redlist categories and criteria, version 8.1. http://intranet.iucn.org/webfiles/doc/SSC/RedList/RedListGuidelines.pdf [accessed on August 15 2011]</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref130"><unstructured_citation>IUCN (2011) IUCN Red List of Threatened Species. Version 2011.1. www.iucnredlist.org</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref131"><author>Lavieren</author><first_page>159</first_page><cYear>2009</cYear><volume_title>Crossing Boundaries</volume_title><article_title>Managing coastal Resources of the Northern Sierra Madre Natural Park.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Lavieren H, van Iongh HH, de Belen A, van Weerd M (2009) Managing coastal Resources of the Northern Sierra Madre Natural Park. In: Persoon G, Ploeg J, van der Masipiquena A, Weerd M van (Eds) Crossing Boundaries. Manila: Studio Graphics Corporation, 159–167.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref132"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Leviton</author><volume>91</volume><first_page>365</first_page><cYear>1962</cYear><article_title>Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, I. The snakes of the genus Oligodon.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Leviton AE (1962) Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, I. The snakes of the genus Oligodon. Philippine Journal of Science 91: 365–381.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref133"><issn>0068547X</issn><journal_title>Proc Calif Acad Sci</journal_title><author>Leviton</author><volume>4</volume><issue>31</issue><first_page>369</first_page><cYear>1963</cYear><article_title>Remarks on the zoogeography of Philippine terrestrial snakes.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Leviton AE (1963a) Remarks on the zoogeography of Philippine terrestrial snakes. Proceedings of the California Academy of Science 4(31): 369–416.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref134"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Leviton</author><volume>92</volume><first_page>523</first_page><cYear>1963</cYear><article_title>Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, III. The genera Maticora and Calliophis.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Leviton AE (1963b) Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, III. The genera Maticora and Calliophis. Philippine Journal of Science 92: 523–550.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref135"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Leviton</author><volume>93</volume><issue>2</issue><first_page>251</first_page><cYear>1964</cYear><article_title>Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, V. The snakes of the genus Trimeresurus.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Leviton AE (1964a) Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, V. The snakes of the genus Trimeresurus. Philippine Journal of Science 93(2): 251–276.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref136"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Leviton</author><volume>93</volume><first_page>531</first_page><cYear>1964</cYear><article_title>Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, VII. The snakes of the genera Naja and Ophiophagus.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Leviton AE (1964b) Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, VII. The snakes of the genera Naja and Ophiophagus. Philippine Journal of Science 93: 531–550.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref137"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Leviton</author><volume>93</volume><first_page>407</first_page><cYear>1964</cYear><article_title>Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, VI. The snakes of the genus Oxyrabdion.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Leviton AE (1964c) Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, VI. The snakes of the genus Oxyrabdion. Philippine Journal of Science 93: 407–422.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref138"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Leviton</author><volume>94</volume><issue>4</issue><first_page>519</first_page><cYear>1965</cYear><article_title>Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, IX. The snakes of the genus Cyclocorus.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Leviton AE (1965a) Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, IX. The snakes of the genus Cyclocorus. Philippine Journal of Science 94(4): 519–533.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref139"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Leviton</author><volume>94</volume><first_page>117</first_page><cYear>1965</cYear><article_title>Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, VIII. The snakes of the genus Lycodon H. Boie.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Leviton AE (1965b) Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, VIII. The snakes of the genus Lycodon H. Boie. Philippine Journal of Science 94: 117–140.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref140"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Leviton</author><volume>96</volume><issue>1</issue><first_page>73</first_page><cYear>1967</cYear><article_title>Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, X. The snakes of the genus Ahaetulla.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Leviton AE (1967) Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, X. The snakes of the genus Ahaetulla. Philippine Journal of Science 96(1): 73–90.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref141"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Leviton</author><volume>97</volume><first_page>371</first_page><cYear>1968</cYear><article_title>Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, VII. The Philippine snakes of the genus Dendrelaphis (Serpentes: Colubridae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Leviton AE (1968) Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, VII. The Philippine snakes of the genus Dendrelaphis (Serpentes: Colubridae). Philippine Journal of Science 97: 371–396.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref142"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Leviton</author><volume>97</volume><issue>3</issue><first_page>291</first_page><cYear>1970</cYear><article_title>Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, XI. The snakes of the genus Boiga.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Leviton AE (1970) Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, XI. The snakes of the genus Boiga. Philippine Journal of Science 97(3): 291–314.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref143"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Leviton</author><volume>106</volume><first_page>99</first_page><cYear>1979</cYear><article_title>Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, XIII. The snakes of the Genus Elaphe.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Leviton AE (1979) Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, XIII. The snakes of the Genus Elaphe. Philippine Journal of Science 106: 99–128.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref144"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Leviton</author><volume>112</volume><first_page>195</first_page><cYear>1983</cYear><article_title>Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, XIV. The Snakes of the Genus Xenopeltis, Zaocys, Psammodynastes, and Myersophis.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Leviton AE (1983) Contributions to a review of Philippine snakes, XIV. The Snakes of the Genus Xenopeltis, Zaocys, Psammodynastes, and Myersophis. Philippine Journal of Science 112: 195–223.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref145"><issn>0068547X</issn><journal_title>Proc Calif Acad Sci</journal_title><author>Leviton</author><volume>29</volume><first_page>475</first_page><cYear>1959</cYear><article_title>A review of the snakes of the genus Pseudorabdion with remarks on the status of the genera Agryophis and Typhlogeophis (Serpentes: Colubridae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Leviton AE, Brown WC (1959) A review of the snakes of the genus Pseudorabdion with remarks on the status of the genera Agryophis and Typhlogeophis (Serpentes: Colubridae). Proceedings of the California Academy of Science 29: 475–508.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref146"><author>Lim</author><cYear>1999</cYear><volume_title>Turtles of Borneo and Peninsular Malaysia Natural History Publications</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Lim BL, Das I (1999) Turtles of Borneo and Peninsular Malaysia. Natural History Publications (Borneo) Kota Kinabalu, Malaysia. 151 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref147"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Linkem</author><article_title>Systematic revision of the Parvoscincus decipiens (Boulenger 1894) complex of Philippine forest skinks (Squamata: Scincidae: Lygosominae) with descriptions of seven new species.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Linkem CW, Brown RM (in review) Systematic revision of the Parvoscincus decipiens (Boulenger 1894) complex of Philippine forest skinks (Squamata: Scincidae: Lygosominae) with descriptions of seven new species. Zootaxa.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref148"><doi>10.1111/jbi.12022</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref149"><doi>10.1111/j.1096-3642.2011.00747.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref150"><doi>10.1016/j.ympev.2010.03.043</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref151"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Linkem</author><volume>2396</volume><first_page>37</first_page><cYear>2010</cYear><article_title>A new species of Gekko (Squamata: Gekkonidae) from central Luzon Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Linkem CW, Siler CD, Diesmos AC, Brown RM (2010) A new species of Gekko (Squamata: Gekkonidae) from central Luzon Island, Philippines. Zootaxa 2396: 37–94.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref152"><doi>10.1016/0378-1127(93)90158-J</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref153"><author>Lomolino</author><cYear>2010</cYear><volume_title>Biogeography</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Lomolino MV, Riddle BR, Whittaker RJ, Brown JH (2010) Biogeography, Fourth edition. Sinauer Associates, Inc, Massachusetts.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref154"><issn>00973157</issn><journal_title>Proc Acad Nat Sci Philadelphia</journal_title><author>Malnate</author><volume>140</volume><first_page>59</first_page><cYear>1988</cYear><article_title>Australasian natricine snakes of the genus Tropidonophis.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Malnate EV, Underwood G (1988) Australasian natricine snakes of the genus Tropidonophis. Proceedings of the Academy of Natural Science of Philadelphia 140: 59–201.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref155"><author>Manthey</author><cYear>1997</cYear><volume_title>Amphibien und Reptilien Südostasiens</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Manthey U, Grossman W (1997) Amphibien und Reptilien Südostasiens. Natur und Tier, Verlag, Germany, 512 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref156"><doi>10.2307/1563076</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref157"><doi>10.2307/1467046</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref158"><journal_title>Asian Herpetological Research</journal_title><author>McLeod</author><volume>2011</volume><first_page>177</first_page><cYear>2011</cYear><article_title>Amphibians and Reptiles of Luzon Island, V: the herpetofauna of Angat Dam Watershed, Bulacan Province, Luzon Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>McLeod DS, Siler CD, Diesmos AC, Diesmos MLD, Garcia VS, Arkonceo AO, Balaquit KL, Uy CC, Villaseran MM, Yarra EC, Brown RM (2011) Amphibians and Reptiles of Luzon Island, V: the herpetofauna of Angat Dam Watershed, Bulacan Province, Luzon Island, Philippines. Asian Herpetological Research 2011: 177–198.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref159"><doi>10.1080/08941920.2012.676160</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref160"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Murphy</author><volume>3484</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2012</cYear><article_title>The dog-faced water snakes, a revision of the genus Cerberus Cuvier, (Squamata, Serpentes, Homalopsidae), with the description of a new species.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Murphy JC, Voris HK, Karns DR (2012) The dog-faced water snakes, a revision of the genus Cerberus Cuvier, (Squamata, Serpentes, Homalopsidae), with the description of a new species. Zootaxa 3484: 1–34.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref161"><doi>10.2307/2405975</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref162"><author>Myers</author><first_page>19</first_page><cYear>1962</cYear><volume_title>Proceedings of the Seventh Pacific Science Congress 4</volume_title><article_title>Ability of amphibians to cross sea barriers with especial reference to Pacific zoogeography.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Myers GS (1962) Ability of amphibians to cross sea barriers with especial reference to Pacific zoogeography. Proceedings of the Seventh Pacific Science Congress 4: 19–27.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref163"><doi>10.1007/s10531-009-9742-z</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref164"><journal_title>Scientific Publications of the Natural History Museum of the University of Kansas</journal_title><author>Oliveros</author><volume>43</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2011</cYear><article_title>The Herpetofauna of the Babuyan group of islands, northern Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Oliveros CH, Ota H, Crombie RI, Brown RM (2011) The Herpetofauna of the Babuyan group of islands, northern Philippines. Scientific Publications of the Natural History Museum of the University of Kansas 43: 1–20.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref165"><author>Ota</author><first_page>222</first_page><cYear>1989</cYear><volume_title>Current Herpetology in East Asia</volume_title><article_title>A review of the geckos (Lacertilia: Reptilia) of the Ryukyu Archipelago and Taiwan.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Ota H (1989) A review of the geckos (Lacertilia: Reptilia) of the Ryukyu Archipelago and Taiwan. In: Matsui M, Hikida T, Goris RC (Eds) Current Herpetology in East Asia. Herpetological Society of Japan, Kyoto, Japan, 222–261.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref166"><issn>0006324X</issn><journal_title>Proc Biol Soc Wash</journal_title><author>Ota</author><volume>102</volume><first_page>559</first_page><cYear>1989</cYear><article_title>A new lizard of the genus Lepidodactylus (Reptilia: Gekkonidae) from Batan island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Ota H, Crombie RI (1989) A new lizard of the genus Lepidodactylus (Reptilia: Gekkonidae) from Batan island, Philippines. Proceedings of the Biological Society of Washington 102: 559–567.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref167"><doi>10.2307/1564316</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref168"><issn>00221511</issn><journal_title>J Herpetol</journal_title><author>Ota</author><volume>13</volume><first_page>35</first_page><cYear>1989</cYear><article_title>A record of a triploid gecko, Hemidactylus stejnegeri, from the northern Philippines Japanese</article_title><unstructured_citation>Ota H, Hikida T (1989b) A record of a triploid gecko, Hemidactylus stejnegeri, from the northern Philippines Japanese Journal of Herpetology 13: 35–39.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref169"><doi>10.2307/1446682</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref170"><doi>10.1080/03946975.1993.10539214</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref171"><journal_title>Monatsbericht der Königlich-Preussischen Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin</journal_title><author>Peters</author><volume>1867</volume><first_page>13</first_page><cYear>1867</cYear><article_title>Herpetologische Notizen.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Peters WCH (1867) Herpetologische Notizen. Monatsbericht der Königlich-Preussischen Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin 1867: 13–37.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref172"><issn>0018084X</issn><journal_title>Herpetol Rev</journal_title><author>Phenix</author><volume>43</volume><first_page>614</first_page><cYear>2011</cYear><article_title>Hologerrhum philipinum—reproductive mode.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Phenix E, Phenix JW, Siler C, Brown RM, Diesmos AC (2011) Hologerrhum philipinum—reproductive mode. Herpetological Review 43: 614.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref173"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Roesler</author><volume>2989</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2011</cYear><article_title>Phylogeny, taxonomy, and zoogeography of the genu Gekko Laurenti, 1768 with the revalidation of G. reevesii Gray, 1831 (Sauria: Gekkonidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Roesler H, Bauer AM, Heinicke MP, Greenbaum E, Jackman T, Nguyen TQ, Ziegler T (2011) Phylogeny, taxonomy, and zoogeography of the genu Gekko Laurenti, 1768 with the revalidation of G. reevesii Gray, 1831 (Sauria: Gekkonidae). Zootaxa 2989: 1–50.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref174"><author>Ron</author><first_page>133</first_page><cYear>2008</cYear><volume_title>Threatened Amphibians of the World Lynx Ediciones Barcelona Spain IUCN - The World Conservation Union Gland Switzerland and Conservation International</volume_title><article_title>Filling the black hole: challenges in taxonomy to protect amphibians.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Ron S, Brown RM (2008) Filling the black hole: challenges in taxonomy to protect amphibians. Pp. 133 In: Stuart SN, Hoffmann M, Chanson JS, Cox NA, Berridge R, Ramani P, Young BE (Eds.) Threatened Amphibians of the World. Lynx Ediciones, Barcelona, Spain; IUCN - The World Conservation Union, Gland, Switzerland; and Conservation International, Arlington Virginia, USA.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref175"><journal_title>Silliman Journal</journal_title><author>Ross</author><volume>34</volume><first_page>29</first_page><cYear>1987</cYear><article_title>Distribution of Zoacys luzonensis (Serpentes: Colubridae) in the Visayan Islands, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Ross CA, Alcala AC, Sison RV (1987) Distribution of Zoacys luzonensis (Serpentes: Colubridae) in the Visayan Islands, Philippines. Silliman Journal 34: 29–31.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref176"><journal_title>National Museum Papers (Manila)</journal_title><author>Ross</author><volume>2</volume><first_page>50</first_page><cYear>1992</cYear><article_title>Amphibians and reptiles of Catanduanes Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Ross CA, Gonzales PC (1992) Amphibians and reptiles of Catanduanes Island, Philippines. National Museum Papers (Manila) 2: 50–76.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref177"><journal_title>Check List</journal_title><author>Siler</author><volume>6</volume><first_page>616</first_page><cYear>2010</cYear><article_title>Reptilia, Squamata, Scincidae, Brachymeles elerae (Taylor 1917): Rediscovery in Old Balbalan, Cordillera Mountain Range, Luzon Island, Philippines, and natural history.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Siler CD (2010) Reptilia, Squamata, Scincidae, Brachymeles elerae (Taylor 1917): Rediscovery in Old Balbalan, Cordillera Mountain Range, Luzon Island, Philippines, and natural history. Check List 6: 616–618.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref178"><doi>10.1655/HERPMONOGRAPHS-D-10-00003.1</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref179"><doi>10.1111/j.1558-5646.2011.01315.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref180"><doi>10.1670/10-103.1</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref181"><doi>10.1670/08-318.1</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref182"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>Siler</author><volume>2482</volume><first_page>49</first_page><cYear>2010</cYear><article_title>A new species of limestone-forest frog, genus Platymantis (Amphibia: Anura: Ceratobatrachidae) from central Luzon Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Siler CD, Diesmos AC, Linkem CW, Diesmos M, Brown RM (2010b) A new species of limestone-forest frog, genus Platymantis (Amphibia: Anura: Ceratobatrachidae) from central Luzon Island, Philippines. Zootaxa 2482: 49–63.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref183"><doi>10.1016/j.ympev.2010.12.019</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref184"><issn>0018084X</issn><journal_title>Herpetol Rev</journal_title><author>Siler</author><volume>42</volume><first_page>605</first_page><cYear>2011</cYear><article_title>Natural history notes on color variation of Lamprolepis smaragdina.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Siler CD, Linkem CW (2011) Natural history notes on color variation of Lamprolepis smaragdina. Herpetological Review 42: 605.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref185"><doi>10.1016/j.ympev.2010.01.027</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref186"><doi>10.1111/j.1365-2699.2011.02680.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref187"><doi>10.1111/zsc.12007</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref188"><doi>10.1655/08-076.1</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref189"><unstructured_citation>Leviton AE (1961) Description of a new subspecies of the Philippine snake Dendrelalaphis caudolineatus. Occasional Papers Natural History Museum of Stanford University 9: 1–6.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref190"><unstructured_citation>McDiarmid RW, Cambell JA, Touré TA (1999) Snake Species of the World: A Taxonomic and Geographic Reference. The Herpetologists' League, Washington DC. 511 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref191"><unstructured_citation>National Statistics Office (NSO) (2010) Final results 2010 census of population. Available at: http://www.census.gov.ph/data/census2010/index.html</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref192"><unstructured_citation>Nordic Agency for Development and Ecology (NORDECO) and Department of Environment and Natural Resources (DENR) (1998) Technical Report: Integrating Conservation and Development in Protected Area Management in the Norhern Sierra Madre Natural Park, The Philippines. NORDECO, Copenhagen and DENR, Manila. 205 pp.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref193"><unstructured_citation>Siler CD, Jones RM, Diesmos AC, Diesmos ML, Brown RM (2012) Phylogeny-based species delimitation in Philippine slender skinks (Reptilia: Squamata: Scincidae) III: taxonomic revision of Brachymeles gracilis and description of three new species. Herpetological Monographs.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref194"><issn>0018084X</issn><journal_title>Herpetol Rev</journal_title><author>Siler</author><volume>41</volume><first_page>427</first_page><cYear>2010</cYear><article_title>Geographic variation in a Philippine mimicry system: hypothesized wisespread coral snake (Hemibungarus calligaster) mimicry by Leptidopteran larvae (Bracca sp) on Luzon Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Siler CD, Welton LJ (2010) Geographic variation in a Philippine mimicry system: hypothesized wisespread coral snake (Hemibungarus calligaster) mimicry by Leptidopteran larvae (Bracca sp) on Luzon Island, Philippines. Herpetological Review 41: 427–430.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref195"><issn>0018084X</issn><journal_title>Herpetol Rev</journal_title><author>Siler</author><article_title>Population genetic structure and revised geographic range for the tridactyl skink (Brachymeles muntingkamay) from Luzon Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Siler CD, Welton LJ, Rock AA, Brown RM (in press) Population genetic structure and revised geographic range for the tridactyl skink (Brachymeles muntingkamay) from Luzon Island, Philippines. Herpetological Review.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref196"><journal_title>Check List</journal_title><author>Siler</author><volume>7</volume><first_page>182</first_page><cYear>2011</cYear><article_title>Amphibians and Reptiles, Luzon Island, Aurora Province and Aurora Memorial National Park, Northern Philippines: New island distribution records.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Siler CD, Welton LJ, Siler JM, Brown J, Bucol A, Diesmos AC, Brown RM (2011a) Amphibians and Reptiles, Luzon Island, Aurora Province and Aurora Memorial National Park, Northern Philippines: New island distribution records. Check List 7: 182–195.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref197"><journal_title>Society for the Study of Amphibians and Reptiles Herpetology Circular</journal_title><author>Simmons</author><volume>31</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2002</cYear><article_title>Herpetological collecting and collections management.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Simmons J (2002) Herpetological collecting and collections management. Society for the Study of Amphibians and Reptiles Herpetology Circular 31: 1–153.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref198"><doi>10.5479/si.00963801.1576.545</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref199"><issn>10513825</issn><journal_title>Asiat Herpetol Res</journal_title><author>Stuart</author><volume>10</volume><first_page>129</first_page><cYear>2004</cYear><article_title>Recent records of turtles and tortoises from Laos, Cambodia, and Vietnam.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Stuart BL, Platt SG (2004) Recent records of turtles and tortoises from Laos, Cambodia, and Vietnam. Asiatic Herpetological Research 10: 129–150.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref200"><doi>10.1371/journal.pone.0023179</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref201"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Taylor</author><volume>12</volume><first_page>353</first_page><cYear>1917</cYear><article_title>Snakes and lizards known from Negros, with descriptions of new species and subspecies.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Taylor EH (1917) Snakes and lizards known from Negros, with descriptions of new species and subspecies. Philippine Journal of Science 12: 353–381.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref202"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Taylor</author><volume>16</volume><issue>2</issue><first_page>213</first_page><cYear>1920</cYear><article_title>Philippine Amphibia.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Taylor EH (1920a) Philippine Amphibia. Philippine Journal of Science 16(2): 213–359.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref203"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Taylor</author><volume>16</volume><issue>1</issue><first_page>111</first_page><cYear>1920</cYear><article_title>Philippine turtles.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Taylor EH (1920b) Philippine turtles. Philippine Journal of Science 16(1): 111–144.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref204"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Taylor</author><volume>21</volume><issue>2</issue><first_page>161</first_page><cYear>1922</cYear><article_title>Additions to the herpetological fauna of the Philippine Islands, I.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Taylor EH (1922a) Additions to the herpetological fauna of the Philippine Islands, I. Philippine Journal of Science 21(2): 161–206.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref205"><author>Taylor</author><cYear>1922</cYear><volume_title>The snakes of the Philippine Islands</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Taylor EH (1922c) The snakes of the Philippine Islands. Manila: Department of Agriculture and Natural Resources, Bureau of Science. 312 p.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref206"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Taylor</author><volume>21</volume><issue>3</issue><first_page>257</first_page><cYear>1922</cYear><article_title>Additions to the herpetological fauna of the Philippine Islands, II.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Taylor EH (1922c) Additions to the herpetological fauna of the Philippine Islands, II. Philippine Journal of Science 21(3): 257–303.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref207"><journal_title>The Philippine Agriculturist</journal_title><author>Taylor</author><volume>5</volume><issue>1</issue><first_page>127</first_page><cYear>1922</cYear><article_title>Herpetological fauna of Mount Makiling.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Taylor EH (1922d) Herpetological fauna of Mount Makiling. The Philippine Agriculturist 5(1): 127–139.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref208"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Taylor</author><volume>22</volume><issue>4</issue><first_page>515</first_page><cYear>1923</cYear><article_title>Additions to the herpetological fauna of the Philippine Islands, III.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Taylor EH (1923) Additions to the herpetological fauna of the Philippine Islands, III. Philippine Journal of Science 22(4): 515–557.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref209"><issn>00317683</issn><journal_title>Philipp J Sci</journal_title><author>Taylor</author><volume>26</volume><issue>1</issue><first_page>97</first_page><cYear>1925</cYear><article_title>Additions to the herpetological fauna of the Philippine Islands, IV.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Taylor EH (1925) Additions to the herpetological fauna of the Philippine Islands, IV. Philippine Journal of Science 26(1): 97–111.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref210"><doi>10.2307/1441364</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref211"><author>Taylor</author><first_page>214</first_page><cYear>1928</cYear><volume_title>Distribution of life in the Philippines</volume_title><article_title>Amphibians, lizards, and snakes of the Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Taylor EH (1928) Amphibians, lizards, and snakes of the Philippines. In: Dickerson R, ed. Distribution of life in the Philippines. Manila: Philippine Bureau of Science, 214–241.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref212"><doi>10.2307/1441364</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref213"><issn>11046899</issn><journal_title>J For Econ</journal_title><author>Uitamo</author><volume>5</volume><first_page>99</first_page><cYear>1999</cYear><article_title>Modelling deforestation caused by the expansion of subsistence farming in the Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Uitamo E (1999) Modelling deforestation caused by the expansion of subsistence farming in the Philippines. Journal of Forest Economics 5: 99–122</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref214"><doi>10.1080/1943815X.2011.610804</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref215"><doi>10.1111/j.1755-263X.2011.00181.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref216"><issn>00317837</issn><journal_title>Philipp Stud</journal_title><author>van der Ploeg</author><volume>52</volume><first_page>346</first_page><cYear>2004</cYear><article_title>Devolution of natural resource management and Philippine crocodile conservation in San Mariano, Isabela.</article_title><unstructured_citation>van der Ploeg J, van Weerd M (2004) Devolution of natural resource management and Philippine crocodile conservation in San Mariano, Isabela. Philippine Studies 52: 346–383.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref217"><doi>10.4103/0972-4923.86991</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref218"><doi>10.3197/096734011X12997574043008</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref219"><issn>11755326</issn><journal_title>Zootaxa</journal_title><author>van Rooijen</author><volume>3272</volume><first_page>1</first_page><cYear>2012</cYear><article_title>A revision of the taxonomy of Dendrelaphis caudolineatus (Gray, 1834) (Serpentes: Colubridae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>van Rooijen J, Vogel G (2012) A revision of the taxonomy of Dendrelaphis caudolineatus (Gray, 1834) (Serpentes: Colubridae). Zootaxa 3272: 1–25.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref220"><author>van Weerd</author><first_page>71</first_page><cYear>2010</cYear><volume_title>Crocodiles Status Survey and Conservation Action Plan</volume_title><article_title>Philippine Crocodile Crocodylus mindorensis.</article_title><unstructured_citation>van Weerd M (2010) Philippine Crocodile Crocodylus mindorensis. In: Manolis SC, Stevenson C (Eds) Crocodiles. Status Survey and Conservation Action Plan. Third edition, Darwin: IUCN SSC Crocodile Specialist Group, 71–78.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref221"><journal_title>Sylvatrop</journal_title><author>van Weerd</author><volume>13</volume><first_page>31</first_page><cYear>2004</cYear><article_title>A new future for the Philippine crocodile.</article_title><unstructured_citation>van Weerd M, van der Ploeg J (2004a) A new future for the Philippine crocodile. Sylvatrop 13: 31–50.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref222"><doi>10.1007/s10531-010-9902-1</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref223"><doi>10.1016/j.apgeog.2005.11.005</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref224"><issn>10134425</issn><journal_title>Herpetozoa (Wien)</journal_title><author>Vogel</author><volume>21</volume><first_page>3</first_page><cYear>2008</cYear><article_title>Contributions to a review of the Dendrelaphis pictus (Gmelin, 1789) complex – 2. The eastern forms (Serpentes: Colubridae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Vogel G, van Rooijen J (2008) Contributions to a review of the Dendrelaphis pictus (Gmelin, 1789) complex – 2. The eastern forms (Serpentes: Colubridae). Herpetozoa 21: 3–29.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref225"><doi>10.1111/j.1096-3642.1860.tb00090.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref226"><author>Wallace</author><cYear>1876</cYear><volume_title>The geographical distribution of animals with a study of the relations of living and extinct faunas as elucidating the past changes of the Earth s surface</volume_title><unstructured_citation>Wallace AR (1876) The geographical distribution of animals, with a study of the relations of living and extinct faunas as elucidating the past changes of the Earth's surface. Harper &amp; Brothers, New York.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref227"><doi>10.1670/206-5.1</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref228"><issn>10718443</issn><journal_title>Chelonian Conserv Biol</journal_title><author>Webb</author><volume>1</volume><first_page>301</first_page><cYear>1995</cYear><article_title>Redescription and neotype designation of Pelochelys bibroni from southern New Guinea (Testudines: Trionychidae).</article_title><unstructured_citation>Webb RG (1995) Redescription and neotype designation of Pelochelys bibroni from southern New Guinea (Testudines: Trionychidae). Chelonian Conservation and Biology 1: 301–310.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref229"><journal_title>Hamadryad</journal_title><author>Webb</author><volume>27</volume><first_page>89</first_page><cYear>2002</cYear><article_title>Observations on the giant softshell turtle Pelochelys cantorii, with description of a new species.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Webb RG (2002) Observations on the giant softshell turtle Pelochelys cantorii, with description of a new species. Hamadryad 27: 89–97.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref230"><doi>10.1098/rsbl.2010.0119</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref231"><issn>0018084X</issn><journal_title>Herpetol Rev</journal_title><author>Welton</author><volume>43</volume><first_page>226</first_page><cYear>2012</cYear><article_title>Genetic identity, geographic range, and major distribution records for frugivorous monitor lizards of Luzon Island, Philippines.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Welton LJ, Siler CD, Diesmos AC, Diesmos MLD, Lagat R, Causaren R, Brown RM (2012) Genetic identity, geographic range, and major distribution records for frugivorous monitor lizards of Luzon Island, Philippines. Herpetological Review 43: 226–230.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref232"><doi>10.1016/j.biocon.2012.10.013</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref233"><issn>0006324X</issn><journal_title>Proc Biol Soc Wash</journal_title><author>Wynn</author><volume>106</volume><first_page>34</first_page><cYear>1993</cYear><article_title>Two new species of blind snake, genus Typhlops (Reptilia: Squamata: Typhlopidae) from the Philippine archipelago.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Wynn AH, Leviton AE (1993) Two new species of blind snake, genus Typhlops (Reptilia: Squamata: Typhlopidae) from the Philippine archipelago. Proceedings of the Biological Society of Washington 106: 34–45.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref234"><author>Yumul</author><first_page>732</first_page><cYear>2009</cYear><volume_title>Encyclopediea of Islands</volume_title><article_title>Philippines, Geology.</article_title><unstructured_citation>Yumul GP Jr, Dimalanta CB, Queano K, Marquez E (2009) Philippines, Geology. In: Gillespie R, Clague D (Eds) Encyclopediea of Islands. University of California Press, Berkeley, California, U.S.A., 732–738.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref235"><doi>10.1046/j.1440-1738.2003.00382.x</doi></citation>
	<citation key="ref236"><unstructured_citation>Taylor EH (1921) Amphibians and Turtles of the Philippine Islands. Manila: Department of Agriculture and Natural Resources, Bureau of Science, Publication 15, 193 p.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref237"><unstructured_citation>Taylor EH (1922b) The Lizards of the Philippine Islands. Manila: Philippine Bureau of Science, Monograph 17, 178 p.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref238"><unstructured_citation>van Beijnen J (2007) Effects of forest disturbance on amphibian species richness in northeast Luzon, the Philippines. MS thesis, Wageningen University, The Netherlands.</unstructured_citation></citation>
	<citation key="ref239"><unstructured_citation>van Weerd M, van der Ploeg J (2004b) Conservation of the Philippine crocodile Crocodylus mindorensis in NE Luzon, the Philippines. An update. In: Crocodiles. Proceedings of the 17th Working Meeting of the IUCN-SSC Crocodile Specialist Group. IUCN: Gland, 277–283.</unstructured_citation></citation>
</citation_list>
</doi_citations>
</body>
</doi_batch>
